So TLOU2 opens with Joel, discussing the ending events of the first game.
The cameras focused on the threat board of the guitar,
which has a very distinctive symbol on it, which will be important later.
I want you to take a mental picture of this scene
because it's going to come back all the way at the end of the game.
During this conversation between Joel and Tommy,
Joel explains his decision to save Ellie over humanity.
Now even this point was one of controversy when the game first launched.
You see, at the end of the first game,
there was a serious question as to whether or not the Fireflies would be able to develop a vaccine at all.
It was one of the reasons that a lot of people thought that Joel's actions were highly justified.
Not just in that he was saving Ellie, his "daughter character",
but rather that he didn't want to sacrifice Ellie's life
for the sake of a cause which likely wouldn't find success any ways.
After all, the fireflies in the first game are pretty damn in competent.
They hire somebody from outside their ranks to transport,
who is likely the most important human being who has ever lived in the form of Ellie
all the way across the country in order to hopefully develop a vaccine.
But when you get there and you explore the hospital at the end of the first game,
you find out that a lot of the doctors involved in this procedure are unsure as to whether or not it's even possible.
After all, literally, every single person in this hospital
is completely inexperienced in developing a vaccine for a fungus such as this.
But the fireflies argument is that at least there's a chance.
If Ellie runs off, and they don't even attempt to extract any of the antibodies
or whatever the hell his inside of her brain that allows her to survive after having a bite.
Then they will never know whether or not a vaccine is possible.
But if they crack her skull open and try and develop some sort of vaccine at the very least,
then there's a chance.
However, in the opening for this sequel,
We see that Joel is pretty confident
that they were trying to develop a vaccine and that they likely would have been able to,
but that it would have killed her.
But it's Tommy's expression that I think sets the tone
for how the player is supposed to feel about joel's decision.
He's stunned, but at the same time he can't really blame Joel for the choice that he made.
After all, later on, in this very intro sequence,
Tommy turns to Joel and tells him that he would have done the same thing.
Regardless, the choice to open the game in this way is very, very important.
The writers over at Naughty Dog wanted to remind the player of what Joel had done
and establish that as the fulcrum from which every narrative mechanism will hinge.
After this conversation, Tommy still unsure of how to react,
simply tells Joel to hop on his horse and head back into town.
It buys Tommy some time in order to form an opinion,
and it also gives the player a chance to settle back into this world.
It's really common for sequels to rush into things,
Giving the player a chance to see something new and fresh and different
that they only could have dreamed of in the first game.
However, and thankfully Naughty Dog doesn't do this.
They take their time during this intro to set things up,
and I think it works very, very well.
You ride through a beautiful landscape and come up on Jackson,
and it's at this time that we get our first look at a fully realized Jackson,
the city that we saw peak of at the end of the first game, but that we could only imagine.
And I've got to hand it to Naughty Dog.
This opening sequence has one of the most well realized cities I've ever seen in any video game ever.
It truly is fantastic.
Every NPC, every animation, every building, every step in the snow is detailed and realistic.
As far as immersion is concerned,
I think this is one of the most fantastically effective games that's ever been created.
After you reach the inside of the city,
Tommy and Joel hop off of their horses and Tommy offers to stow Joel's horse for him,
while also saying that he'll take the truth to his grave.
This implies a couple of things.
For one, it might seem as though he's referring directly to Ellie
that if Ellie were to find out this truth, it would cause a lot of problems.
After all, as far as Ellie is concerned,
Joel simply took Ellie after a bunch of tests were run,
and it was clear that she was not going to be able to provide any sort of help towards a vaccine at all.
At the end of the first game,
it's pretty clear that Ellie sees through this lie, that Joel is telling,
or at the very least, she expects that there's more to this story.
For the sake of their relationship, she simply goes along with it.
However, I think there's another implication to this as well,
and that is that if other people in the camp were to find out what Joel had done,
I am not so sure that they would approve of it either.
Again, we can talk all day about how incompetent the fireflies were in the first game.
And I think there's a real argument to be had there.
I mean, if I had to entrust them with the fate of humanity,
I would hop on the next asteroid off the planet.
What I mean, though, is that Naughty Dog is trying to tell his story,
and they're framing the plot points the way that they want you the player to see them.
For the sake of this story,
it's important to understand that the fireflies were the ones that were trying to save humanity
and were apparently on the cusp of developing a vaccine to save countless millions of lives.
And once again, for the sake of this story, that's been told in TLOU2,
Joel is the one that undid that.
Again, at the very least, if Ellie had gone under the knife, there would have been a chance for a vaccine.
By killing the doctors that were about to operate on Ellie and potentially develop a vaccine,
he effectively saved his "daughter figure",
but he damned all of humanity for the rest of time.
In other words, he strained at a gnat but swallowed a camel.
He traded what seemed to be a smaller evil for a much much larger evil,
and he did this because his judgment was clouded by his own personal wants and wishes.
This isn't to say that Joel would or does regret any of this in this particular sequence.
But it is to say that the players should start seriously considering
whether or not Joel's actions were justified, or perhaps even whether or not they were right.
But don't worry, Naughty Dog is going to help you think about this
by constantly bringing it up using flashbacks. as Elie grew up in Jackson.
and I promise you before you know it,
you might even be convinced that Joel is in fact a villain.
This isn't to say that Joel is unlikable character that you should hate him or wish that he were dead,
but rather Joel is the one that damned humanity.
If you tell any other story and there's a character which damns humanity for the sake of one single person,
we would say he's a bad guy.
Or perhaps we wouldn't even say bad guy,
we would simply say that he was a confused or perhaps mistaken individual,
whose motivations were complex.
But the point is, it's not as simple as hero and villain.
There is a lot of gray in between.
Now this intro sequence is just shortly after Joel's arrival, while Ellie is still young.
She's living out of grandmothers suite in the back of the house that is presumably owned by Joel.
It's super cute that she has her own space,
but it even now shows and tells a lot about their relationship.
Now granted, Joel is a middle aged man that found this little girl,
and he took her halfway across the country,
rescued her from a bunch of cannibals,
and now has her in a town that his brother runs with his wife.
it could be presumed that her staying in his house could be considered an appropriate.
But I don't think that's the point here.
Joel is Ellie's "father figure", and I don't think that's a controversial thing to say.
The fact that Ellie wants space, physical space separated from him means a lot.
Regardless, we see Ellie and she's drawing something
that will come back time and time again throughout the rest of the game.
She's actually pretty artsy and gifted, artistically,
you'll see this in the note book that you'll be using throughout the course of the main game.
She often draws pictures of what she sees or sketches out different things
in order to remind her to return to that area
or simply to keep a journal of the events and happenings of the main story.
She's listening to music when Joel comes in.
It's a really cute and awkward moment, but it's pretty damn sweet.
It doesn't take a body language expert to see that there's a lot of tension here.
Jole's unsure of how to stand, where to move, how to talk, how to relate to her,
and Ellie picks up on this as well.
The tension is really palpable.
They both know what happened in Utah hasn't been resolved,
but neither knows how to broach the topic,
so they simply delay it and push it off.
But the point of this sequence is where Joel to express how much he needs Ellie in his life.
Let's all just take a moment to relax and appreciate how beautiful the scenery is,
and how Ellie responds in classic Ellie fashion.
如果有一天我失去了你
我肯定会失去自我
我在这里找到的一切
都不是只靠我自己
尝试吧，或许你能做到
成就现在的我
我丢失的一切
早已不再需要
因为我相信
我深信因我可预见
我们未来的日子
有你与我作伴
还不错吧
嗯……
不难听
我就当作是夸奖了
And I'm sure I don't need to tell you this.
but this song is going to come up time and time again throughout the course of the main story.
So make sure that you remember it.
Though I'm sure I don't need to tell you that because you'll likely remember this for the rest of your life.
considering how unbelievably touching it was.
Also a funny little thing that Neil Druckman tweeted out.
Apparently he had been asked many many times on Twitter and in person
why Pearl Jam's "Future Days" was used in the game.
People ask this because the song didn't actually drop until October of 2013 officially.
And that is actually a month after outbreak day in this universe,
so it shouldn't have actually existed.
Neil Druckman responded by saying,
感谢您的提问！其实……这首歌在专辑发布的几个月
之前就在YouTube上有一场live了。
And you can actually go look it up on Youtube,
and sure enough, Pearl jam performed this live,
and that video was posted on July, 26th of 2013.
That's the actual date of the video.
It's a perfect example of Naughty Dog's excessive attention to detail.
I don't think anybody would have cared, particularly if this song released three years after outbreak day,
but the fact that they took it upon themselves to find a song that fit the theme and the tone of the game
and that fits so perfectly within Joel and Ellie's relationship,
and then to also make sure that it fit in with the timeline they were dealing with it.
It's unbelievable.
But once again its one of the examples of Naughty Dog's perfectionism.
They don't need to care about these little things, but they do.
And that's what sets them apart, whether you love them or hate them.
After this touching flashback, we cut to Ellie, waking up late.
Jesse, a character we'll get to see a little bit throughout the course of the game
is at her front door, giving her crap for sleeping in.
Over the next ten or so minutes as you walk through the town,
you have a recap of everything that went down and then some in the trailer from E3 2018.
Now I found this particularly interesting,
because that sequence where Dina and Ellie share their first kiss,
I thought was a pretty important sequence to see.
But Naughty Dog doesn't show it to the player, at least not right now.
Instead, they rely on the dialog to explain what happened,
but I can't help to notice that this is the first instance
where trailers are important to a contextual grasp of the game itself.
because, after all, in this case,
the scene that's being discussed isn't actually shown to the player
until the last 15 or so minutes of the game.
Time and time again, stuff that was shown in the trailers is either changed drastically or is moved around
such that you need to have seen the trailer in order to truly understand what's going on.
Now I understand that it's a small thing to point out or be frustrated by,
because after all chances are every single person who bought the game had seen that trailer.
However, I still think it's strange to show a scene in a trailer,
but then not show it in the game when that item is being discussed.
It's one of countless times in this game,
when Naughty Dog will take a sequence, cut it up into fifteen different parts
and then spread it randomly, seemingly throughout the course of the story.
Sometimes I think it helps with pacing
by giving the player a break from a very stressful environment or activity,
but often it feels as though it's jarring and out of nowhere.
But don't worry, we're going to get to some very egregious examples of this later on in the story.
All that's really important to understand is that Ellie and Dina shared a first kiss,
a character that we meet briefly, said something offensive and bigoted,
and everybody wants you to know that it's bigoted.
You get some sandwiches and then you go off to start on patrol.
It's also important to understand that Jesse just broke up with Dina
around a week to a week and a half before this is taking place.
Or may be Dina broke up with him, or maybe it was mutual.
I don't know, it … it's so high school …  these first few conversations. It's kind of painful.
Jessie heads off to the stable to prepare the horses and the rest of the attendees.
While Dina and Ellie shared a snowball fight against a bunch of kids.
Now I kind of found this snowball fight to be a little weird
because it seemed as though it's meant to serve as some sort of combat introduction.
But I think I was just reading too much into it because I don't think it does a very good job of that.
Now I did go back through the game a second time,
as I stated previously on "New Game +" and on the hardest difficulty.
After becoming completely familiarized with the controls after playing the entire game,
this whole snowball fight was much more intriguing and interesting and frankly fun
than it was the first time I played.
The three tiered stance that Ellie's able to have between standing, crouch and prone
is something that takes a minute to get used to.
I know it sounds weird because that's true of pretty much any third person or first person shooter
that they're going to have those three stances.
But in TLOU2, there are multiple levels of movement associated with each.
And that's more of my point.
The sequence does a very poor job of introducing the player to those three stances.
But you are able to use each of those three stances in this sequence.
It just seems a little jarring,
but I will admit I appreciate the effort that they put into this
because it's still way better than the alternative,
which would be to have the standard stereotypical sequence
where the protagonist goes and has shown how to use a gun,
and it's like issue bottles or some crabs …  I hate that.
Probably the most egregious example would be the opening of Fallout 3 when you're given a BB gun,
and then you go downstairs, shoot some targets and then some giant radroaches.
I just think that that's so overplayed.
If you're going to introduce shooting mechanics and combat,
you should at the very least have a little bit of a creative spin to it,
so I appreciate that throwing compacted snow at children was presented here.
After hucking some powder you meet up with Dina,
there's some awkward exchanges where Ellie isn't sure how to talk to …
I mean again, it … it's very high school.
The two walks out the stables and you head out on patrol.
Then the first surprise of the game hits,
and to be honest, it's a surprise, even if you had the game spoiled for you.
You see the camera slowly pans over a bunch of sleeping young adults.
It centers on one girl who most of us will immediately recognize from the Paris Games trailer from 2017,
she gets up talks to a young man who asks to show her something,
and then we are given control of her.
Like I said earlier, I had the game spoiled for me.
But all of those spoilers said that you were going to get to play half of the game as Abby
and start halfway through.
I did not expect to be playing as her within the first 30 to 45 minutes.
I bet you, at this point, some people had put the game down.
After all, there was a very vocal minority that said
that they were going to flip out if you didn't play the whole game as Ellie and or Joel.
But a key thing to understand here is that the player must give it time and effort
to stand on its own and justify itself
in the same way that you can't judge a book by its cover or a film by its trailer.
You'll never get an informed opinion of the game if you don't give it a chance.
This isn't to say that you have to play every single game in order to have an opinion of every single game,
but rather that if you're going to have an extremely negative or critical opinion of a game,
you have to be able to justify that critical opinion.
And in my opinion, I don't think it's fair to say that playing as any character
other than the one on the Box-Art is bad bad and means that the game is terrible and not worth your time.
After you take control of Abby and you start exploring through the woods,
walking through some pretty deep snow,
seeing some interesting landscapes,
these two characters share in some dialogue about other people in the group,
likely the same people that you just saw the camera pan over.
Now we don't know any of these people at this point and Naughty Dog will do this a lot.
They are unapologetic in their unexplained dialogue.
The characters will have conversations that makes sense to them,
but might not, or perhaps don't make any sense at all to the player.
Now I love this,
though I do admit that it can be confusing to those who like to enjoy their content more passively.
But this is a narrative game,
it seems like it comes with the territory of this type of game to have dialogue
that's much more realistic and grounded
compared to dialogue that just hit you over the head with exposition.
I also think it's important to note that these conversations make a second run of the game AWESOME.
Seriously, every single thing they are discussing here,
it makes perfect sense and is relatable and understandable.
Once you've gone through the whole game and met all of these characters
and grown to know them and care about them throughout the course of the story,
and as somebody that usually placed their games that I critique at least two times,
I really appreciated this because it made it.
So my second run through was more informed and more interesting than my first run through.
Really, I think you should play the game a second time through just to give it a shot.
I think you'll be surprised at how many little things were added that you didn't hear before.
But for the sake of a first run through,
it's important to note that Abbey and Owen are the names of these two characters,
they seem to have a previous relationship.
In other words, they dated at some sort of romantic involvement at some point.
And also that some girl named Mel, who Owen is apparently involved with at this point, is pregnant.
There may be, I'm all alone in this,
but the second I heard she was pregnant, I got a pit in my stomach.
This is what I meant when I tweeted out early in my first run through of the game
that I felt as though the opening was dreadful.
I meant it in the purest sense of the word that the game fills you with dread.
You have a sinking feeling in your stomach that something terrible is about to happen.
and I don't know if it's just that the game was spoiled and so everybody saw this coming,
or that it's some sort of masterful way that they designed all of these conversations and scenes
that makes you feel as though there's an impending danger and doom.
I don't know which it is.
I would love to hear your opinion of it down in the comments section below or tweeted at me @LukeStephensTV.
But nonetheless I can't help but feel as though everything terrible that could happen is about to happen.
And so when I heard that this girl, Mel, was pregnant,
I just knew something horrible was going to happen to her
and likely that one of the characters we were being introduced to on Ellie's side of the fence
would likely become pregnant to contrast the two relationships
and to set up narrative beats where you could have one character faced with an option,
have the other character faced with the other option
and see how each reacts in their individual moments.
But I understand that they likely doesn't make any sense at all if you haven't played through the game yourself,
so I'm simply going to move on and loop back to it later.
I promise it'll make sense.
Abby and Owen reach their destination, and they overlook Jackson.
It's a massive city.
And judging Abby's reaction, it seems as though she didn't expect it to be this massive at all.
It's not clear what they're looking for, but it's a man for sure.
any one with two brain cells to rub together will instantly know that they're talking about and looking for Joel
though we don't know why at this particular moment.
Now Owen doesn't think that they should continue on this quest to reach whoever they're looking for
because they obviously aren't going to be able to infiltrate Jackson no matter how hard they try.
They're a small group and they aren't going to be able to do it.
So he thinks that they should just turn back.
Especially since malaise now pregnant, they need to return to take care of her.
Again remember this plot point,
Owen, the dude, wants to turn back to make sure that he can take care of the woman that he impregnated.
It seems like a weird, random thing to say.
But this is something that's going to be repeated later in the story,
and Ellie is going to be making the same decision that Abby makes in this moment, a stupid one.
Naughty Dog will do this a lot throughout the course of the main story
where they will have Abby do something and then change it with a fresh coat of paint
and have Ellie do the same exact thing.
But you can't help feel as though Ellie is more justified in her actions,
while Abbey is just a bad villainess character.
This game is all about perspectives
and this flip flopping that they do constantly is an important piece of that narrative mechanism.
Now I'll be obviously doesn't want to turn back.
They've travelled, presumably for days, weeks and even months to get to where they are now
and simply to turn around upon seeing the city of Jackson.
It doesn't seem like it's a good option.
Owen says that they should return back to the mansion they're staying at.
But Abby doesn't like their recommendation,
and she starts to become enraged, and she pushes on herself towards Jackson,
trying to find a patrol that was traveling that Owen spotted
in order to get them to tell her where their target is,
so that she can finish the job herself before returning back to wherever they came from.
Controlling Abby, you push forward into an impending storm.
You fight some zombies and you eventually find some tracks from one of the patrols.
These patrols are the same ones that characters such as Ellie, Dina, Jesse, Joel and Tommy are all on,
and this is the first of a plethora of coincidences in the early hours of the game that set up its narrative,
the coincidence that Abby happened to be driven into a rage
at the same time that Joel and everyone else happens to be out on patrol.
It's going to happen a lot.
Joel is an old man as his Tommy,
at the very least older than all the youngsters that they have out on the patrols with them.
The fact that Joel is still going on patrols is, in my opinion, a bit of a stretch.
It would be stupid for him to go on patrols, especially because he has a leadership position within the city.
His super fancy house, I think, serves as proof positive of that,
Not to mention that Tommy, his brother, who was also going out on patrols with him,
has a leadership position within the city.
In many ways, Tommy runs the city along with his wife.
So to me, it just seems like a bit of a stretch that Tommy and Joel would be going out on patrols at all.
But I understand that perhaps Joel or Tommy just want to get out and get their hands dirty.
They don't want to feel old, they don't want to feel as though they can't contribute,
so they want to go out and do things themselves.
I understand that perhaps that's justifiable.
But I can't help feel as though Joel and Tommy being out on patrols
the same patrol routes that Ellie Dina and Jesse are taking,
was purely designed, and established that way to make sure
that Abby would be able to encounter Joel and Tommy while she randomly ran through the forest.
And this is the reason that I don't like narrative coincidences.
Often it's just to give a way
that the writers are trying to force characters into normally unjustifiable situations.
But it's not always a bad thing.
In fact, in some cases, I think these coincidences can lead to some really interesting sequences.
I mean, look at that scene from Breaking Bad.
Where Jane's father runs into vault at a bar.
They share a short conversation about fatherhood, about kids,
and they don't realize that they're talking about two characters, in this case, Jesse and Jane,
who are inextricably tied and who are about to go on a roller coaster together.
For those of you who have seen the show and know what happens right after this meeting,
you are going to probably think roller coaster is a bit of an understatement.
But didn't I didn't want to spoil it? So …
The point is, go watch Breaking Bad, it's awesome.
The other point is that narrative coincidences can be fine.
After all, coincidences do happen in real life all the time.
The problem comes when they are used to make characters do things they wouldn't otherwise be doing
in order to fulfill some sort of plot point.
It's the same reason I hate psychics or prophecies in stories because I think that they're just lazy.
The writers know that they want a character to go and do something,
so they write some sort of prophecy to explain how it's going to happen,
and then they make sure that they have characters that fit around that prophecy.
And if it's a little messy,
or if it doesn't seem to be totally justified narratively or in terms of the characters, motivations,
they simply explain it by way of while he or she was fulfilling the prophecy.
It had to happen.
It must have happened because the prophecy stated.
It's just lazy,
And while I feel as though many of the instances of coincidences in TLOU2,
are not justifiable and are a grievous offences,
I think that other instances are more justifiable and could be explained.
But eventually there becomes so many that stack up on top of each other.
It just seems as though Naughty Dog need Joel to run into Abby,
and this was the fastest, cleanest way that they could figure out how to do that.
In a previous episode of NitGrit, a show that I do here on Youtube,
I discussed narrative coincidences in TLOU2,
and I couldn't help but notice that they were all front loaded in the opening hour or two of TLOU2.
I threw out a potential intro that they could have swapped where, for instance,
Abby, Owen and perhaps a few other members of her crew
infiltrated Jackson working with the people being welcomed in
and eventually earning the trust of Joel and Tommy, and Ellie
until eventually they turned on everybody, killed Joel and escape in the middle of the night,
while the game then carries out just like it would have otherwise,
it could have been really interesting because Abby and Ellie could have even formed a friendship,
or at least some sort of sympathetic position towards each other,
which would have made the betrayal all the worse.
I mean, as of right now, Tommy and Joel are very welcoming to this group.
They even invite them back to Jackson to restock on supplies before leaving
right before you know the thing happens.
So we know that Tommy and Joel are welcoming.
They would have brought this group in, at least for a little bit.
Perhaps if they came in,
they pretended to be wandering survivors simply in need of assistance in a new fresh start.
Perhaps then they go when they work at Jackson for a few weeks,
Or maybe even just a couple of days before turning and killing Joel and escaping.
At the very least, then you don't have to rely on a bunch of coincidences.
But I do understand that it might have been bad for pacing
and especially considering the leaks that happened towards the game's release.
It seems as though is probably for the best.
because once the game was spoiled,
we all knew that Abby was going to kill Joel
so that would have completely negated the opening sequence where Abby and Ellie are starting to bond,
or perhaps at least tolerating each other.
I've heard from various people on Twitter and through Email
that Naughty Dog was actually considering this as an opening,
which is funny because I just let it roll off my dome,
I wasn't actually thinking that hard.
But apparently this was a seriously considered intro sequence
instead of what we got in the end product of TLOU2,
But they decided to go in this current direction because the other version ran into a lot of pacing issues.
In other words, you likely would have needed to spend the first five or six hours of the game in Jackson
doing menial chores while getting to know Abby and her crew before being betrayed,
it would have completely changed the structure of the rest of the game,
so Naughty Dog just decided to expedite the process,
have Abby get to Joel within the first two hours of the game and get the revenge plot moving.
I think that's fair.
I just think it's a little sloppy, considering how many coincidences they rely on to make it happen.
After Abby finds the tracks in the snow, leading to one of the patrols,
we swap back to Ellie, whose on patrol with Dina.
You ride your horses through a beautifully realized landscape, walking on ice in a river.
It's absolutely beautiful.
I mean again, how Naughty Dog achieves these graphical features, I don't know.
It really makes it look like every other development studio isn't even trying.
There's a lot of character building in this sequence as you go on your patrol.
There's some light flirting, clearly, Dina likes Ellie and Ellie likes Dina.
And the tension starts to rise here.
Again there's a lot of dread, things are going too well,
and the world of TLOU, as we know, is very cutthroat, sometimes literally.
The fact that everybody's happy that they are so carefree that they're even flirting with each other.
It's unsettling, because we know that something bad has to happen soon.
But you continue exploring, you go to an outpost to explore some abandoned houses.
And at one point,
Ellie even says that she's going to be inviting Joel over for a movie later that night.
This will be VERY important at the end of the game,
so make sure you remember this.
Ellie on this day was planning on having Joel over for a movie that night.
It seems like a small point,
especially considering that Ellie and Joel have this deep connection with each other.
She lives right behind him, even still in the grandmothers sweet,
and it makes sense that perhaps they would try to fill an empty time,
watching movies and spending time together.
But again, at the end of the game, we're going to find out a lot more.
And this very statement by Ellie something that happens as an optional moment
while you're exploring an abandoned house.
This is going to be very important.
Ellie and Dina, come up on a supermarket that's infested.
You cleared out, gives you the chance to explore some stealth options and combat,
and it's a good thing that this is a really well done portion of the game.
Because this stealth and the crafting that goes along with it
is going to be the bread and butter of the game,
especially if you're playing on higher difficulties,
you're going to need to get acclimated to these mechanics as soon as possible.
You are also given a quick introduction to clickers as well,
and these guys work almost identically to how they did in the first game.
I don't really feel the need to explain a lot as to how these sequences work,
because if you've played the first game, you're going to know how this goes.
It's going to be a hot minute before we're thrown anything that's markedly different.
I will say that in the first game,
it always bugging me that clickers are obviously able to navigate their environments
by use of clicking sounds that use echolocation to map out their environment.
However, they never were able to hear characters talking to each other
or you reloading your weapon or moving your backpack on and off.
That is mostly true again in this game, except only on the lower levels.
In my testing, I actually found that on new game Plus on survivor difficulty,
the clickers can actually hear this as well.
If you open your backpack to swap weapons, they'll notice and they'll come running.
This was a game changer in terms of immersion.
Seriously, I've never played a game where I was so attentive to everything that I was doing,
that I was scared to even open up the inventory,
because I knew that it was going to create a small amount of sound that could attract clickers,
which could mean that I die and have to reload.
Granted to some people, I'm sure that sounds absolutely terrible,
which is why there are difficulty settings to begin with.
But if you want to be totally immersed in this game,
I recommend you play it on the hardest possible difficulty.
It really does change everything.
Another thing to note in this supermarket sequences that
Ellie is wearing a mask when she encounters spores now.
If you played the first game,
this is going to be kind of weird because obviously Ellie is immune to the virus,
or so we thought, why does she need to wear a mask?
In the trailers we saw before the game's launch,
a lot of people thought that this would mean that Ellie was no longer immune,
or perhaps she was not as immune as she once was,
so perhaps if she inhaled spores, that would make her very very sick,
but she would eventually pull through it.
However, the explanation is far simpler.
Joel and Ellie obviously know that Ellie is immune, but nobody else can know that.
If people were to find out that Ellie's immune,
the same crap with the fireflies would happen all over again.
Now this seems to be much more Joel's wish than it is Ellie's,
after all, Ellie was totally prepared and fine with giving her life to save humanity in the form of a vaccine,
And this would of course make sense because Joel wanted to make sure
nobody else would come to Ellie to try and capitalize on her gift,
because if they did, it would mean that he would lose her.
But the fact that Ellie is still using the mask, even though she doesn't need to,
I think, serves as proof positive that she still cares about what he thinks,
and she's yet to fully separate and become her own person.
But this isn't something that's explained or really justified at this point in the game,
but we will see an actual conversation between Ellie and Joel later on that explains all of this.
If I throw a bunch of zombies and clickers and eventually find your way up to the top of the supermarket,
where you jumped down out to the front,
Ellie and Dina's entire goal throughout exploring this supermarket was to clear it of infected,
and they've done just that.
Honestly, it's not a bad way of forcing the player to kill zombies
in order to get experience with the combat system and become more comfortable with it.
A lot of people are going to simply try to stealth around them in most instances,
especially later in the game, when resources become very scarce.
but if the characters mission is to wipe out all infected in an area to protect Jackson, the city,
you all of a sudden don't have to worry about players doing that
because they're going to be justified narratively in killing absolutely everything.
After all, they can't leave the area unless they've completely wiped all of the infected within that area.
Once you get out of the supermarket, the blizzard starts to come in full force.
So Ellie and Dina race through the snow, and end up at a library that Dina knew about.
It's the previous abode of somebody named Eugene,
who, by my calculations, using the log book in the first outpost,
likely died of a stroke laid in the previous year just a few months before this game starts.
Well, we know about him is that he was a firefly who served with Tommy,
and he was also an electronics geek who was a total hippy.
In other words, he loved weed.
After being introduced to the workbench,
Which has to be the most awesome and kick ass weapon customization system I have ever seen in a game
you went down to the basement where you find Eugene's true passion.
Now, when I first saw all of this,
I had to ask the question: Was he actually like selling this stuff? Was he trading it?
I don't know, maybe there's a notes that I missed,
that explained what he was doing with all of this pot.
I don't know, let me know if there is something there probably is, and I just didn't find it.
But it seems as though it's a huge potential opportunity for Jackson in terms of trade,
if they had a whole of this marijuana to offer took transients coming in and out,
I mean it would be pretty funny if Jackson,
this thriving city in the apocalypse if their entire economy was based off of selling weed.
I think it would be hilarious and kind of cool
that in this world, this one thing this plant has brought everybody together.
I mean, yeah, I live in Colorado.
Maybe that's why I'm partial to that argument.
I mean I don't smoke and I don't … I don't smoke.
But, still, like you live in Colorado, everyone talks about pot, and this is what you do.
What was I talking about? Oh, yeah!
Dana and Ellie smoke a blunt.
They shared some high school musical style discussion about their kiss from the night before.
And then they share another one and then a few other ones,
and eventually their overcome, and they begin making out as we cut to Abby, once again.
she's running from all sorts of hordes.
She's making a lot of noise, and they are definitely hearing it.
This increases the tension a lot after the calm of the previous scene.
And this type of pacing is going to happen often.
Honestly, I love it.
It's a very common Naughty Dog tactic.
They work you up, and then they contrast it with something that's very calm that lowers your heart rate
only to whack you over the head again and then luring you back into a sense of calm.
The best example would be in the opening of the original game.
Everything's calm and relaxed,
And then the world starts to fall apart and everything's terrible and then your daughter dies,
and then you cut forward to Joel sleeping on a mattress twenty years later
and having a very calm, comparatively conversation with Tess
and prepare your butts because this is going to happen on a regular basis throughout all of the sequel.
And thankfully, the predictability of this doesn't actually negatively affect the efficacy of this mechanism.
It still works pretty well.
Now as you run as Abby through all of these hordes, you eventually reach a chain link fence.
You squeeze through it and a bunch of zombies grab onto you,
start ripping your hat off and doing all sorts of gross stuff, and then one breaks through,
and this happens.
Now they haven't been introduced yet.
but as of right now, Abby's just glad to be alive.
As far as she knows,
Joel is just some random guy, as is Tommy,
and they just happened to be in the right place at the right time to save her.
Again, a coincidence.
This one's a little harder to justify and explained.
Because they have no reason to be out at this dead end area of a building they have likely been in before.
All of you escaped together to a ski lodge at the top of the mountain.
You up on some horses,
and after a brief introduction wherein Abby learns who she's with,
she recommends that they weighed out the storm in a mansion that she and her friends have been staying in.
Joel and Tommy agree to go without any significant hesitance
beyond the initial belief that they could survive in the lodge.
Once again, it's another coincidence.
Joel and Tommy, aren't this naive,
or at the very least they shouldn't be, even when pushed in these extreme conditions.
我的意思是我明白外面暴风雪肆虐
What I mean is, I understand that there's a blizzard raging,
我也明白这会让他们做出相比天气晴好的时候不会做出的选择
and I understand that would push them into choices that they wouldn't otherwise make,
should the weather be fine and dandy.
But Joel and Tommy aren't stupid, and they know not to trust strangers,
even a stranger that looks as innocent as hulked out heroin.
and they definitely should know that they shouldn't trust a group of strangers
that are living out of a mansion that's on their patrol route.
She says they've been staying there for a few days
that they have weapons, food and all sorts of things that could help Joel and Tommy.
While it's nice that she's offering to help them in this way,
it should also raise a lot of red flags that she's willing to help them first of all,
and also that this giant group of people is present so close to Jackson without their knowledge.
But nonetheless Joel and Tommy agree to go.
Once you arrive at the cabin, Joel, Tommy, and Abby dismount and settle into the house.
Abby is clearly distressed, while Tommy and Joel are none the wiser.
Again, the dread is building. Something is very wrong.
Everyone moves into the nearby basement room, And Tommy and Joel introduce themselves.
Again, this might be construed as out of character
that they would use their real names to a bunch of strangers.
But in my opinion, it's not actually stretch
because Tommy and Joel have no reason to believe that their first names could give them away,
or that one of them is being hunted for that matter.
Yes, they've all done a lot of really messed up stuff,
but knowing somebody's first name and hunting them down across the country,
that seems like a bit of a stretch.
But here we are.
Point is I don't think that it's unrealistic that Joel and Tommy use their real names
when introducing themselves to a group that seemingly is helping them out.
And I have to say it's pretty impressive at how slow and steady
the dread is building throughout this entire introductory sequence, the prologue of the game.
And then at this very moment,
when Joel says his name and everybody's faces turn from very friendly to cold and evil.
It's a moment that I'm not sure I'll ever forget
the second Joel says his name, the room shifts.
You could hear a pin drop.
Instead of being friendly, they all looked at him as though their hyenas looking at their next meal.
And it's important to note that this kindness that we feel before Joel introduces himself
is very important and it will come up again later, I promise you.
Now Joel picks up on this shift, and this plays out.
We cut back to Ellie, closing in on the cabin.
Now right before Joel and Tommy pushed up to the cabin with Abby,
We saw Jesse come across Abby and Dina in the basement of Eugene's library in a compromised position.
He tells them that Joel and Tommy are missing and nobody has seen them since the storm came in.
Ellie becomes panicked and races off to help find them.
It's important to note also that Ellie stressed
that they should all split up to try and cover as much ground as possible.
Some people have said that this itself is a coincidence
or a bit of a stretch that they wouldn't actually do this,
but again, think about it.
From her perspective, I don't think it's a stretch.
Because as far as Ellie is concerned,
it's very possible that Joel and Tommy simply had to bunker down somewhere because of the blizzard
and were caught there by surprise.
It's not to say that she expected Joel to be hunted by some random chick from Seattle.
But regardless everybody breaks off looking for Joel and Tommy.
After Abby starts her attack on Joel, we cut to Ellie, closing in on the cabin,
they give a bit of a fake out here by dropping some ammo right as you enter the cabin,
which makes the player think that you're about to fight.
I actually really like it.
When games do this, do this little fake out.
So you're prepped for a fight,
and then it's taken away from you, but I know that's just me.
Of course this is in the case because the second that we enter the basement, this happens.
There are some heated discussion between the members of Abby's party as to what to do with Ellie.
It's all very muffled, and you can't understand any of it,
though we will get to see this from another perspective later.
Eventually they just knocked her out.
and Ellie wakes up after some time to Dina and Jesse rescuing them.
At this point is not clear if Tommy survived, but it's clear that Joel did not.
You know what? This is as good a time as any to address the elephant in the room dead on the floor,
I had the game spoiled for me,
so I knew that Joel was going to die at some point.
And to be honest,
many of us had a feeling as though Joel was going to die at some point in the game years ago
because they only made sense.
One of the stereotypes of a sequel is that they're going to kill off one of the major characters
from the first iteration of whatever is in question,
whether it's a movie and novel, a podcast or a video game,
time and time again, we've seen this trope played out.
And it's become a trope because this actually works pretty well.
You grow the character and the audience falls in love with them over the course of the first story.
Then, with this foundation laid you pull the rug out from everybody
and smack them over the head with a two by four of emotion.
Or maybe in this case, a golf club of emotion.
Maybe that's too soon, I don't care, moving on.
Even with this presumption, having been established by many people before this game was launched,
Naughty Dog seems to have actively tried to dissuade fans from this presupposition
by way of their pre launch trailers.
Now this actually got a lot of people pretty upset when they played through the entirety of TLOU2.
There are multiple events that were shown in the trailers
that aren't actually indicative of what the game has to offer.
The clearest example would be this one,
where Ellie is fighting through a bunch of WLF,
and then has a hand put over her mouth,
and when she turns round, she sees that it's Joel,
telling her that he's not going to let her do this by herself.
Now I'm not going to respond in the same way that a lot of people on Twitter responded
where they demanded their money back to the false advertising.
I don't think that's fair,
especially because you paid sixty dollars and have gotten a lot of game play out of it before.
You know, I don't even need to explain my reasoning, I just think that's stupid.
What I will say, however, was that this was very confusing,
at least for me, the first time I play through the game.
Having watched all of the trailers multiple times,
I knew that Joel made an appearance later on in the game because Ellie responds to him.
But that never happens in the actual game.
So I kept asking myself whether or not there was going to be some sort of dream sequence
where she plays back through the same level again.
But this time Joel is at the end of the line instead, and then that scene plays out.
Of course, I don't have to tell you that never happens.
This was simply a way to divert the attention from the fans
away from what was actually going to happen.
And Naughty Dog does have a history of doing this type of thing,
which is part of the reason I can't fault them completely,
because usually it's for a good reason.
The most obvious example would be with the original TLOU,
when they said that you would only be playing his Joel throughout the entirety of the game.
Of course, this isn't true.
And it made it so when you actually get your hands on Ellie,
that sounded weird when I said it out loud,
it made it, so when you started playing as alley,
the entire sequence was much more surreal because you didn't expect at all to have this opportunity.
Another example would be with this very game,
TLOU2 when they said that you would only be playing as Elie throughout the entirety of the campaign,
something which was obviously not true.
The problem with these sort of white lies to better the game play experience for the player
is that they only work if people don't know any better.
And with the original game, as far as I am aware,
most people believed that you would only play as Joel throughout the entirety of the game,
and it made it so when they got their hands on the controller playing as Ellie.
It was much more interesting because they didn't expect it at all.
But with TLOU2 and all of the leaks that followed, people saw this coming from a mile away,
and it lost a lot of its punch.
I've actually spent a lot of time thinking what this game would be like
if I had no expectations and nothing spoiled for me.
I think the experience would have been much different,
and I'm not sure how that would have changed my perspective.
Nonetheless, if you happen to be one of the few lucky people
who got to play the entire game without having anything spoiled for you,
I want to hear your thoughts down in the comment section below or in a tweet.
Sent it to me, I'm really interested in hearing what your perspective is on all of this.
But as for Joel's death itself, I have no problem with it.
Joel's actions throughout the course of the first game were quite reckless
and he screwed over a lot of people and killed a lot of people while he was at it.
I've said before, and I'll say it again: I don't think Joel is a hero.
If anything, he's an anti hero, if you look at his actions in a vacuum.
你完全可以说人生与道德在实际生活中会复杂得多
You can always say that life and morality is much more complicated than looking at it purely in a vacuum,
但我仍然认为乔尔不能算是我们大家应该敬仰 应该向他学习的道德标杆
but I think it still stands to say that Joel is not a pillar of morality,
to which we should all look and pray for guidance.
I think rather, he's a damaged, broken, sad and a moral character
who is looking to do what he needs to do, to survive and protect those he cares about.
That's something that I think is in a way admirable in and of itself.
But I don't think that that makes you a hero quote-unquote in the same way
that you could compare a character such as Aloy
who is actively trying to do the moral thing in any instance that she comes across.
Furthermore, from a game play perspective, we got our game with Joel.
We know him, we have experienced him and his perspectives.
I think it was time for something new,
and if we had played through the entire game as Joel or half and half between Joel and Ellie,
I think it would have lost a lot of its punch.
Now Joel's death didn't come as a surprise to me. or probably any one,
especially once you walk through that door in the cabin.
That being said, it's still pretty horrible having to watch him get his head crammed in with a golf club.
It's pretty haunting, but that's by design.
Naughty Dog needed the player to be just as haunted by this event as Ellie is
because then they feel emotionally equivalent,
especially in their hatred towards Abby,
which is one of the major elements that they need to establish early on.
You, the player, need to hate this girl with every fiber of your being.
Just like Ellie hates her with every fibre of her being.
so that later, when they try to flip perspectives and flip the table on you,
they can do that effectively.
If you're apathetic towards Abby
and then you go through the entirety of the game trying to pursue revenge,
you're not going to be motivated at all.
It's going to be pretty uninteresting because the entire premise of the game and the story is a moot point.
But if you hate Abby, just as much as Elie hates her and wants to see her die,
you'll be motivated to get through the first half of the game.
And then Naughty Dog has you set up for the final act.
Now, after this, we enter the end of the prologue.
Yes, we are an hour into this video, and we are just getting out of the prologue.
Ellie and Tommy discuss their next steps.
Tommy talk to Maria, and she's not going to let him go or do anything,
and he's not allowed to have any sort of spare men.
He has to keep them all in Jackson.
She thinks that they should just move on,
except that what happened was terrible and go on with their lives.
As usual, Maria seems to be the one voice of reason.
Tommy and Ellie, however, are understandably upset.
Tommy lost his brother in a terrible way,
and Ellie also lost her "father figure" in a terrible way.
They still aren't certain why this happened,
or what Joel did that made them seek his death out so fervently.
Tommy happened to see some patches on their coats that read "WLF".
And because of his previous history with the Fireflies,
he knows that that would be the Washington Liberation Front,
which is a group that's in Washington.
Huh … Go figure.
And that's what allows Ellie to know where she needs to go next.
It's a long stretch that they would have returned to Seattle
and that they would still be there and that they would be findable.
But when you're motivated this strongly, you're willing to go and try anything.
In the same way that Abby was so desperate to go and get revenge against Joel.
Ellie now is motivated to go to her turf and get revenge against her.
Now Tommy wants to go to Seattle by himself, and Hunt Abby down and get revenge.
Maria, of course, is not going to let him do that.
But Tommy's main objective is to prevent Ellie from going,
he promised Joel that he would take care of Ellie, no matter what.
And in this case, he knows that if Ellie goes to Seattle,
her chances of survival aren't very high.
So he'd rather go take on those chances himself
and spare Ellie while trying to get revenge for the sake of the both of them,
Ellie demands that they either go together,
or that Tommy allow Ellie to go with Dina
and some other people with some troops from the camp to get revenge herself.
Tommy, of course, rejects this idea and asks for and more time just a day or so
so that he can try and work something out.
In this case, he's just buying time.
He's made up his mind as to what he's going to do.
We then see Ellie in Joel's grave site.
It's a really touching moment,
and it reaffirms that Joel is actually gone.
I don't know about you guys.
But I had this sort of surreal feeling when I played through this game the first time.
I kept saying to myself: Joel can't actually be dead.
For one because we saw that trailer, where Joel was featured later on in the game in Seattle.
And for two because Joel is Joel,
you can't just kill off Joel that suddenly, there has to be more to it.
But there isn't.
He's dead. This is his grave and it's sad.
Ellie then visits Joles house with Dina,
picks up his watch from the first game, it's still broken.
And also takes his revolver, which you'll be using throughout the rest of the game.
It's actually pretty cool that this is where she gets it.
We do this though, only after exploring his house a little bit,
and there's a lot of incredible detail here,
and it really encapsulates Joel's character.
He's very music heavy and organized his neat and tidy,
and his house is also painfully empty.
There's a lot of big, empty rooms.
And maybe I'm just reading too much into it,
but I couldn't help but feel as though there was a lot of space
where Ellie could have stayed if she had wanted to.
Like I said earlier, there was no reason other than the emotional turmoil between the two
for Ellie to go and live in the grandmother, sweet out back.
But truly everything from the paintings on the walls which we'll come back to later, I promise to,
Joel's bed still being a little rough and that there is a space magazine and books by his bed,
that he was reading because he's interested in space
like it's … it's so cute, and it's so touching,
and it's so painfully sad to know that he's never going to walk through that house ever again.
After you grab these items,
you walked downstairs and realized that Maria is there sitting with Dina.
She informs you that Tommy left on his own already
and is asking that Ellie be locked up to prevent her from following him.
Maria is understandably frustrated, angry, Pissed,
whatever words you want to associate with it.
But more than anything, she's worried.
and she knows that if she sends Ellie and Dina off to try and help Tommy
at least still stand a better chance.
So Maria allows Ellie Indiana to leave Jackson with their horses and some extra supplies
so long as they promised to bring back Tommy, when they return, in one piece.
This sets up the dual purpose of your journey and theirs.
You're going there to kill Abby, but also to save Tommy,
although Tommy probably doesn't need much saving.
And you'll realize that once we get to Seattle,
There's going to be a third purpose in their journey and motivation to everything that they're doing,
that's added on top of it.
I find it really interesting that they set up these multiple goals
because it seems as though it just complicates things which I actually like.
Having a single quest, we are just going to try and kill one person, is a little bland.
It's a little uninteresting.
So to see that we have multiple things we're trying to do all at once is a little refreshing.
至此 我们来到了游戏的核心内容——西雅图 第一天
After this we jumped to the start of the core game itself, Seattle day 1.
序章结束了 该开始游玩游戏的最核心部分了
And after this, we're done with the prologue and ready to move into the core of the game.
但在这之前 我想先和大家聊聊此时我的感受
But before we do that, I want to discuss our feelings at this point.
我一周目玩到这里 我感觉我是充满继续游玩的动力的
At this moment in my first run, I felt motivated.
同时内心又觉得充满担忧
Yet still pretty dreadful, in again, the pure sense of the word dread overwhelmed me.
因为这类复仇对任何人来说都不会有好下场
These revenge quests never end well for anybody,
我不禁去想艾莉最后搞砸了 弄得自己死无葬身之地怎么办
and I couldn't help but feel as though Ellie was going to totally screw herself over
and end up dead in a ditch somewhere if she tried to do this.
但我觉得这也正是关键所在
But again, I think that's kind of the point.
玩家需要去融入艾莉 切身体会她的彷徨与疑虑
The player should be just as hesitant and doubtful as Ellie is in this pursuit.
诚然 艾莉嘴上说着要去怎样怎样砍死埃比还不带眨眼的
Sure, Ellie talks a big game and explains how she's going to go and kill Abby without any remorse,
要让埃比为自己的行为付出代价云云
and she's going to get revenge for this terrible act.
但艾莉自己还是时不时表现出些许的保留态度
But she still shows some slight reservations every once in a while.
她深知自己的行为在逻辑上是不合理的
She knows that this doesn't make a lot of logical sense
就像埃比最初肯定也知道自己一头扎进暴雪中的杰克逊小镇
in the same way that Abby knew that her plan to just go in storm Jackson
也没什么逻辑可言
didn't make a lot of logical sense,
但她们都去做了 因为她们认为这似乎是正确的
but they are going to try and do it because they felt as though it was the right thing to do,
这也是她们坚持下去的原因
and that's what kept them going.
这是一场情感与动机的拉锯战
It's a tug of war of emotions and motivations.
这样的冲突才会造就有趣的故事
And that conflict is what makes an interesting story.
你可以说你对TLOU2这部分故事有自己的见解
Say what you will about TLOU2 at this point in the story.
但游戏本身还是有趣的
But it's interesting and engaging,
可能剧情不是那种令人开心的爽剧
none the less, might not be fun might not be enjoyable,
但对我来讲游戏还是很有意思的
but it's interesting at least to me.
可能会有人不喜欢 那我也欢迎大家在下面留言
Maybe you hated it, and if you did, I would love to hear your thoughts down below,
不过说真的 可能不喜欢的人早就关掉视频了
but to be perfectly honest, you're probably not still here in this video.
如果这游戏没有任何一点让你觉得有趣的地方
If you don't find the story of this game, at least somewhat interesting,
还看了一个多小时序章的测评内容 你要还没关视频那大哥你真是纯爷们
I mean, after all, we just got through the prologue and we are well over an hour into this video.
So it's with that newfound motivation to find Abby that we enter the core of the game.
And it's good that we have this emotional drive behind us
because we're about to enter a very slow sequence of the game.
Seriously there's moments in here where I became actively bored because it was all puzzle solving in platform.
It's just kind of blaaaah
but don't worry, we're going to get into it.
And with that we move to Seattle Day 1.
Our first day in Seattle starts with the gate,
basically riding through the forest, talking with Dina.
And you have to try and get into the body of the city.
Of course, there's a lot of military installations that were put up
towards the end of quarantine that have since fallen to pieces.
But nonetheless you have to get through them.
There's a few supplies here and there that you can gather.
But for the most part, this is a puzzle solving sequence.
We climbed some buildings go up some ladders enter some codes that we find on some papers
and we push into Seattle.
This was probably my least favorite part of the game.
We're emotionally motivated.
We want to go, kick some ass and take some names
and then give those names to other people whose asses we've kicked,
but instead we're forced to just slowly solved some basic puzzles.
Write down some codes, walked to another place,
pull open our note book to look back at what the codes were and then enter those in manually.
It's not that interesting,
and it is in direct conflict with what the player wants to be doing at this point.
I understand may be Naughty Dog wanted to slow the pace down
after how emotionally distraught you might be after the prologue.
But still, I can't help but feel as though there would have been a better way to do this
may be some more combat sequences, may be introducing you to a new type of infected.
I'm not sure, anything I think would have been better than this.
We get to downtown and by my estimation, this is the largest single area of the game.
It's very open, and there's about eleven main locations,
at least that I found to explore in this little area.
This includes a bank, a synagogue, a court house all very well realized.
The bank is cool because it's frozen in time, right after a group of people tried to rob,
I loved seeing all of the money strewn throughout the bank
and watching Allie and Dina ponder what they would do with that money
if it actually was worth anything in their world.
And I gotta say Naughty Dog is really good at this sort of indirect world building,
it makes you question your actual priorities in your current life.
If you're motivated purely by money and you have fat stack
sitting next to you as you watch this video,
you can't help but feel a little bit strange
when you walk into this post apocalyptic world and the money is absolutely useless.
It's those types of little things that get the wheels turning in your mind
to start putting yourself in the shoes of the characters in that world.
That makes Naughty Dog so good at motivating players to continue engaging with the story.
My favorite part of this chapter, however,
is an optional item interaction in the music store of this section.
and basically if you interact with the guitar here, Ellie will start playing and singing Take On Me to Dina.
It's really beautiful and is another calm moment in this already relaxing section.
And I really enjoyed it, and I recommend that you also enjoy it because it's not going to last.
But while the story elements of this section of the game are pretty impressive,
我觉得你要探索的广阔区域并不像我认为顽皮狗希望的那样令人印象深刻
I don't feel as though the expansive areas that you're meant to explore are quite as impressive
as I think Naughty Dog was hoping they would be.
This whole area is very reminiscent of the opening of The Lost Legacy,
Naughty Dog's, other most recent Uncharted game.
In The Lost Legacy, You have a huge open expanse to explore.
But by explore,
they pretty much mean that you move from one location to the other, fights some bad guys,
solve a quick little puzzle and then move to the next area.
It's not actually exploring in the same way that you would probably show it in,
for instance, The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild, where you're actively exploring the map.
Maybe my expectations were just out of check
because Naughty Dog did talk these sections up a lot,
saying that these were the largest levels they had ever designed in any of their games ever,
which is true in their pretty impressive on that front.
But in the age of Red Dead Redemption 2 riding a horse through a field really isn't an incredible achievement.
Now, of course, it's not a competition between Naughty Dog and Rockstar.
They're both the prettiest girl in the ball, and you can't have either of them,
but I can't help but notice as though the foliage and the horses in Red Dead Redemption 2
looked a lot better two years ago, in an open world game, when compared to those in TLOU2.
Maybe I'm just really picky or may be my preferences are a skew.
Let me know in the comments section below.
But I really do feel as though there's a strong difference between these two and it's in Red Dead's favor.
Nonetheless, you continue exploring the map and eventually pushed through the gate that was locked,
keeping you in this area,
everything's quiet and you simply ride your horse through the checkpoint,
at least until this happens.
We open back up with Ellie, tied to a desk in a small elementary school called Eastbrook.
This is not really important, what's important is that l is being held hostage,
and Dina seems to have escaped.
Ellie is about to be executed when Dina comes in and saves the day … Well, at least … almost.
You watches this guy tries to strangle Dina, feeling absolutely helpless.
It's actually pretty well done.
I found my heart rate increasing quite drastically during this.
Eventually, use your foot to grab a shard of glass,
use it to cut your bindings.
And Ellie goes up and kills Dina's attacker,
at which point she grabs a letter and picture from his pocket.
Which will be important in just a little bit.
You are through a few combat sequences here that pair you against human enemies.
It's a nice change of pace from the infected that you've been dealing with exclusively up to this point,
and it forces you to change your approach.
For instance, you have to really be careful managing your flashlights.
Going up against most infected, you don't have to worry about your flashlight being on or off
because they can't see it or don't respond to it.
With humans, of course they do.
They're much more visual and much less auditory,
though tactically flank you and maneuver around you if they need to,
though they can be lured with sound into traps very easily.
But on survivor difficulty, I will say it can be frustrating if you run out of ammo,
as your only option in dealing with them and ranged attacks is to throw bottles and rush
or just sit and pray that they come around.
I understand that it's a post apocalyptic world, and not everything is going to be convenient within it.
But nonetheless, it's pretty frustrating.
After fighting your way to safety,
Ellie looks at the document and the picture that she swiped off of Dina's attacker.
It's a new picture that Leah gave to her boyfriend, Jordan, who is actually the guy that you just killed.
但抱歉了各位 照片上有块血污挡住了关键信息
And sorry boys, but there's a blood smear that covers all of the good stuff,
所以暂停视频肯定没用啦
so no use in pausing the video.
Now, Leah happens to be one of the people that joined Abby on their "kill-cation",
another coincidence that leads Ellie to the Channel 13 Station to find Leah,
who might be able to help them find the Abby in turn.
Ellie and Dina also hear about this guy Isaac in conversations that can be overheard from the WLF members.
Now not much is known about this guy or revealed about him for that matter, for quite a while.
But what we do know is that he seemingly runs the WLF, and he has a firm grip on power.
Everyone does what he says and are scared of him.
Naughty Dog games of the past would use this as a set up for the later boss fight with Isaac.
既然提到他了 那他在游戏后面肯定是个关键角色了对吧？
If he's mentioned, he'll be a key part of the story later, right?
恭喜你答错了
Well, actually wrong.
这样的事情还会在未来另一个角色身上发生 可能是为续作之类的内容做准备
This will happen again with another character later, maybe it's a set up for a sequel or something.
但就伊萨克和另一位即将登场女性角色来说 这样的事情的确没有发生
But … as for Isaac himself and the other lady that's going to be shown off, it actually doesn't come around.
总之接下来艾莉和蒂娜继续前往城市中心 寻找13频道电视台
All of that said Ellie and Dina head into the heart of the city to find the Channel 13 Station
追捕利娅 想办法从她那里获得更多埃比的消息
to hunt down Leah to try and in turn, get more information on Abby.
你继续推进 顺手杀了一堆WLF士兵和感染者
You push through a ton of WLF soldiers and lots of infected as well.
你发现地上有绊雷 不禁想起一代里的比尔
You find some trip wire traps set up that reminded me of Bill from the first game.
但在这里它们除了减慢游戏探索速度之外似乎没有任何作用
But here they don't seem to serve any purpose other than to slow down game play and exploration then.
就我个人而言我很快发现这些绊雷的乐趣所在——它们就是单纯的烦
Personally I just soon find these trip wire bombs fun. They're just annoying.
偶尔用一些新的不同的东西来为单调的游戏调味的想法是好的
It's good to shake up the monotony of game play every once in a while that something new and different,
比如这些绊雷
such as these trip wire minds.
而在这里 这些绊雷并没有在游戏剩余部分中出现
But in this case, these things don't really come up again for the rest of the game.
它们只是一种不会让你形成游戏中新的习惯行为的烦人道具
They're just a one of frustration that doesn't actually drive you into any sort of new habitual behavior.
换句话说 在大多数游戏中 制作者向你介绍一个新的游戏元素
In other words in most games, when they introduce you to a new gameplay element,
其原因是这个元素会在游戏中剩余部分用到
it's because it's going to be used throughout the rest of the game,
所以你需要学会掌握它
which is why you need to be taught how to deal with it.
但在这里 这个元素用的很少 而且很多可以避开
But in this case they're used very sparingly and in most cases they are entirely avoidable.
当然了 这可能是我自己的小癖好罢了
But granted. This is probably just a pet peeve on my end.
接下来你会遇到游戏中最棒的收集品
So you come up on the station after finding the best collectable in the game.
马赛克马赛克马赛克马赛克马赛克马赛克马赛克马赛克
And you begin exploring it,
you find the remnants of a Scar ceremony of some sort.
There's a bunch of bodies that are strung up everywhere and that have been disemboweled.
Now it's not clear exactly when this happened, but it seems relatively recent.
Now if you're anything like me, you would have immediately realized that
Leah is probably not going to be in any sort of condition to help you find Abby,
especially after all of this Scar stuff.
If she's even still in the station, she is probably dead.
And sure enough you finally at the top of the station in an office
shot dead with a bunch of arrows sticking out of her.
But the coincidence is common clutch and save the day
because Ellie decides to open up leah's duffel bag underneath her cot,
which just happens to have pictures of all of the team members that went to Jackson and killed Joel.
Apparently, they basically have logged the whole thing,
which is why I called a "kill-cation" earlier.
这可能是，我觉得不止可能，它就是
This is probably, and to be perfectly honest, I think it is
靠巧合推动游戏剧情发展的最糟糕的例子
the most egregious example of coincidence is driving this story.
They needed Ellie to be reminded and have some sort of firm idea
of what these people looked like and what their names were,
so that she could ask other people who they were and where they were,
they couldn't come up with any reasonable way of her coming up with this information herself,
so instead they had to have her stumble onto it by finding a bag that happened to be left behind,
that happened to have all of these pictures placed in it by some lady that was on a work assignment.
And that's the thing she wasn't even really supposed to be at this TV station for very long,
so I don't understand why she would have brought all of these pictures very precious to …
I … I just, I don't understand.
But I'll stop beating the dead horse there.
Right as you find the photos WLF members show up and assuming that you're a Scar
pushed through the entire building to find Ellie and Dina.
you fight them and escaped through the basement
which leads to the underground tunnel system for the subway.
This encounter seems really intimidating at first,
but rest assured, it's actually pretty easy to spam, as you can see in this instance.
If you know what I use a good Molotov cocktail, you can work wonders.
当你进入地铁
Once you're in the subway system,
你会遇到新的名为跛行者的感染者 会走到你面前释放一种酸雾
you find some new zombies known as Shamblers, which eject a sort of acidic cloud when at the road.
在普通难度下 我其实感觉它们令人失望的简单
At Normal difficulty, I will actually say that these things are disappointingly easy to kill,
简直完全不符合我的预期
like they do not meet the expectation at all.
它们抱住你的时候完全没有叫声听起来那么吓人
Their bite is nowhere near as bad as their bark,
但到了二周目生还者难度 这玩意虐你简直跟玩一样
but on Survivor who came plus, these things can eat my entire ass,
and maybe it was just me that had an easy time with these Shamblers,
or perhaps just expected way more for them.
Because there are some signs that Naughty Dog expected players to have more trouble with these guys.
I mean, look at how Dina locks this door.
I thought this was kind of weird in my first run through
because there was nothing left to keep from getting through.
All of the zombies were dead.
I killed them all, and there was nothing left in that room to prevent from escaping.
But in my new game plus run,
I snuck through this section, leaving many or even most of those infected alive.
In that case, locking this door made a lot more sense.
But on my first run, on a normal difficulty with all of the zombies dead,
it really seemed strange that Dina wanted to lock this door down.
I mean, I guess it can't hurt, but still it just seemed odd.
This is a simple, but I think it's an effective example of
how Naughty Dog likely expected more players to stealth their way through these sections.
Now Ellie and Dina continue to push through these tunnels.
And it's actually a pretty cool sequence going through these things again when remembering the first game.
Because of course, in the first game, Ellie couldn't even swim.
And Joel had to use all sorts of floating platforms to get her from one area to the next.
In this case, Ellie is much more capable.
And if anything, it's Dina, who requires a little more babying.
But after exploring a few of these tunnels and climbing through some train cars, one of them collapses.
Ellie takes a tumble as they're jumped by a bunch of infected and Ellie's mask actually cracks,
leaving her exposed to the spores.
Dina understandably starts to freak out, thinking that Ellie is going to die.
Ellie says she's fine as they raced to the street level
and insists that Dina does not take off her mask to share between the two of them.
You fight your way all the way up to the street level,
locked the door behind you and look across the street and see an old theatre.
You decide to take refuge there,
and thankfully it's fairly well guarded, defensible, and the doors do lock from the inside.
Ellie and Dina break in, take refuge and start to rest.
Dina is understandably upset because she thinks that Ellie is going to die.
After all, she just saw her inhale spores.
And for any other human being that she knows that would be an instant death sentence.
But instead, Ellie seems fine. There's no problem.
And it's at this point that Ellie again explains how she's actually immune.
She previously explained this to Dina
back when they were in Eugene's basement weed emporium.
然而当时蒂娜看起来并没有相信
However, it seemed back then that Dina did not believe her thought
她以为艾莉只是在骗她 开了个很黑色幽默的玩笑
that she was pulling your leg and just thought it was a cruel joke.
但现在蒂娜明白过来这可能是真的
But now Dina understands that this might actually be true,
虽然我感觉蒂娜好像没太把这当回事
although I will say that Dina never really seems to go any further with this.
她的爱人的天赋可是免疫一种能感染地球上所有人类的真菌
Her love interest is immune from the fungus that is infecting all of life on the planet.
可她好像丝毫不感兴趣
And she doesn't seem that interesting in it.
真的 我不确定她在整个游戏后来是否还提起过此事
Really, I'm not sure if she brings it up ever again throughout the entire game,
哪怕是减掉的场景片段里
even in the later cut scenes and sequences.
这点就有点奇怪
It's just a little strange,
我明白这个故事流程里涉及到很多内容
I understand there's a lot to get through during the course of this story.
也有可能某个片段她们更深入地交流了这方面的事情
And perhaps there were scenes that had been written where they discuss it further,
但最终被减掉了……我也不确定
but it was eventually cut … I'm not sure.
总之我感觉蒂娜没再跟艾莉提起她的免疫这件事是很奇怪的
But all I know is that it seems strange that Dina doesn't engage with Ellie further on this matter.
While also in the theater, Dina explains that she thinks that she's pregnant.
You see, she dated Jesse, broke up with him a week before Ellie and Dina's kiss.
And that would mean that the baby is Jesse's.
This, of course complicates the relationship between all of them.
Now, personally, this came as no surprise at all to me.
After all of the signaling that they did for the last three or so hours of game play
and if you were reading Ellie's journal at all,
you'll know this well ahead of Ellie.
蒂娜吐了几次 说是自己感觉不太好 太累了
Dina was puking a lot, saying that she wasn't feeling well, saying that she was tired,
把这些归于一路的厮杀血腥 但实际上只是孕吐
blaming a lot of things on the gore around her, but in reality it was morning sickness.
Furthermore, having heard Abby and Owen discuss Mel, Owen's other love interest, and her pregnancy,
it seemed like a slam dunk
that Naughty Dog was going to have somebody in Ellie's friend Circle become pregnant
so that they could draw a further parallel later.
Sure enough, that's exactly what they did.
Regardless, Ellie breaks away, allowing Dina to sleep.
You get some electricity running after the awkward conversation
and stumble upon a radio in a technician's closet.
It's broken, Ellie becomes frustrated and wax at in frustration,
which is how she actually finds the keys that led her into the deeper areas of the theater.
I don't know why the keys were under the radio.
It's almighty convenient that she hit the radio in frustration in the first place
because if she didn't, she wouldn't have found the keys.
But whatever, you get the point, I have been complaining about coincidences in this whole videos.
So you get the point. I'll just, I'll move on.
You find a guitar in the back of the theater and play the same song
that we saw Joel played for Ellie in the flashback wherein he was teaching Ellie how to play.
She plays the first few bars, and then we cut to a flashback.
Probably my favourite flashback of the entire game.
It's Joel and Ellie.
It seems to be Ellie's birthday,
and Joel is taking her to find her birthday gift.
There's not much to say about this sequence other than that it's very touching and sweet.
Joel found this museum that had a giant dinosaur statue in it
because he knew that Ellie dreamed of seeing dinosaurs.
She also wants to go to space, one of her dreams is to go to space.
And he takes her to the astronaut exhibit,
wherein she can put on a helmet and then climb into the actual capsule.
Joel hops in too, gives her a headset and allows her to zone out
while imagining herself going into space and taking off.
This sequence is actually just like the arcade one in Left Behind
the DLC from the first game wherein Ellie and Riley were imagining playing this video game.
Of course they couldn't play it, it was long since broken.
But Riley had Ellie close her eyes and imagine everything while she described it.
You'd better believe it's no coincidence that these two events are so similar.
It's a super simple scene.
But it just serves to further establish that Joel and Ellie had a deep relationship and care for each other.
Also that their relationship is pretty complicated.
Because at the very end of this scene you come across a writing on the wall.
And needless to say, it's something that Joel and Ellie don't want to discuss.
So they just leave.
And after that we jumped to Seattle Day 2.
Starting out our second day in Seattle,
Ellie wakes up in the theater and finds Dina in the radio room vomiting.
A not so subtle reminder of the revelation that we saw before the flashback.
She's been listening to the radio, deciphering the WLF's communications
to figure out where members of Joel's assassination party might be.
Dina and Ellie overhear a WLF broadcast together that there's a lone gunman in Zone 14.
They guess that this is a neighborhood called Hillcrest and Ellie heads out to investigate.
They think that this could be Tommy because, well, who else could it be?
Sorry for the bell, I have a kitten on my lap and she's making noise.
But yeah, Shakur have, Of course it's not Tommy,
Playing as Ellie, you push through a few different areas,
fighting all sorts of wolfs and looting lots of buildings.
Not much happens for around thirty minutes of exploring
until all of the WLF seems to descend at the same spot,
a smoke signal that Ellie also follows.
The level design here is really fantastic.
This use of a visual objective in the distance that you can follow as you go through the level.
It's really well done, and it's something Naughty Dog has been doing for a long time
and that they really have perfected.
Now these level really crescendos in difficulty,
especially in harder difficulty settings where difficulty spikes are far more severe.
Now the thing about this is that you'll get caught with no ammo in this level
If you're not careful and use it all too early.
So you have to be very careful to preserve it.
But the problem is on your first run through you're not going to know
that you're going to run out of ammo so quickly.
You couldn't have known.
So in turn you are always careful and never want to use any of your ammo whatsoever.
But when that's the case, you are always careful,
which also means that you never are because your behavior isn't changing in any way.
You are just refusing to use ammo,
so you're effectively playing through the game as a melee game.
It's this game play hesitance that I have noticed in a lot of horror video games,
especially where ammo is very limited.
It's strange to me because I don't think it actually reflects a better game play experience
because it just ends up with the player refusing to use multiple mechanics
because they are scared that if they do use them,
they're going to run out of ammo and be unable to use them later on.
But I understand that getting rid of this system could also be like throwing the baby out with the bathwater.
Though regardless, Ellie pushes to the smokestack,
killing and evading all sorts of WLF members while she goes.
You eventually unlock the bow and arrow here,
which is actually probably my favorite weapon of the whole game.
It's silent, you can recollect a lot of the ammo depending on where you hit the enemy
and on what difficulty you're playing.
And all around I just like it, I find it really satisfying.
She reaches the location of the smoke stack, and then this happens.
This is really weird to me … because …
as far as I knew, this was going to be Joel when Ellie turned around,
and I was really confused when I saw that we were getting to that point where the trailer happened.
And I knew that Joel was dead.
How could he possibly show up and save the day?
But sure enough, it ends up being Jesse.
It's just strange to me that they chose to do this fake out,
where we thought that it was going to be Joel here,
because that's what the trailer showed,
and then it ends up being just … It's just it's weird … It's weird to me.
I don't know what else to say.
If you have more information on this, let me know in the comments section below,
I just …  it's weird. I don't know what to make of it.
Nonetheless, Ellie and Jessie managed to escape by way of a stolen car
that they drive into a river in a pretty impressive sequence that also leaked pre launch.
It's a superfluid sequence, and no, I'm not just saying that because they end up in a river,
I think it's very well polished and it looks incredible to boot.
But then again, I mean, this is a Naughty Dog game wouldn't expect anything else.
You bring Jesse back to Dina and there's a ton of tension here.
Ellie, of course, leaves because she feels very awkward.
After all Ellie's girlfriend's baby daddy just showed up.
I don't blame her for wanting to leave.
As Ellie walks away, we jump into another flashback, and this one's actually pretty simple.
Ellie and Joel are exploring a hotel while on their way to a music store
after Ellie receives a lesson on sniping from Tommy.
And this may seem really random,
especially because sniping will not be a major mechanic for Ellie throughout the entire game.
But there actually is a reason for them showing the player this sniping tutorial.
I'll get to that more in a little bit, though.
After you finish your sniping tutorial with Tommy, ride back down the hill and find Joel sitting there
and you prepare to go out with him to find some guitar strings at a music store.
Now, A fun little detail is that this actually was originally an entirely different plot.
Originally after Ellie finished her sniping tutorial with Tommy,
she and Joel were going to go and say Hi to Joels girlfriend who lived just a little ways down the road.
They were going to ride up, find Joel's girlfriend having been freshly bitten
and they were going to be forced to make a difficult choice.
While they all negotiated back and forth what they should do about it,
they send Ellie outside to grab some fresh water from the stream.
Once Ellie walks outside, she hears a gunshot,
and then Joel walks out, and they know that something happened.
They know that … she's gone.
And either Joel put her out of her misery at her request,
or she put herself out of her own misery because she knew that she didn't want Joel have to do it for her,
because they knew how this was going to end.
Regardless, it would have been a very touching moment
and interesting thing to see Joel and Ellie experience together.
Joel experiencing another loss and using Ellie to help him get through it.
But apparently, according to the press release and comments by Neil Druckmann and all of his writing staff,
this scene was cut in favor of this new scene
where they go and explore a hotel cutting through to a music store.
Because they felt as though it was too much of a diversion from the priorities of the story.
In other words, this is a game about Ellie, it's not a game about Joel.
And if they had this scene focused on Joel, it would start to feel much more like a Joel AND Ellie Game.
But a Joel and Ellie game, where your only playing as Ellie, but make of that what you will.
You cut through the resort, clearing out a ton of infected
and it actually feels a lot like the first game, it's pretty nice.
As they pushed through the resort, Joel insists that Ellie wear her mask,
even though she's immune to the spores.
she asks why she'd would need to do this,
after all, it's just them exploring the hotel.
And he says, because if somebody saw her, they would have a lot of questions understandably.
So it's better to be safe than sorry, she should just wear it.
and this explains why she was wearing it
and all of the other sequences like we talked about at the beginning.
She wore the mask at Joel's insistence because she didn't want to risk anybody finding out
because it would cause too much trouble,
or it just wasn't worth the headache of explaining everything that went down with the fireflies,
even if Joel was going to stick to his original story of what happened.
But after pushing through a ton of infected fighting, a mini boss fight with Joel again,
very reminiscent of the first game touching and tugging on all of my heart strings,
they end up finding a couple that left Jackson a few months before
which spurs a conversation about what happened at the hospital.
Unfortunately, Joel continues to lie.
We then cut to Ellie, patching up a cut in the theater.
Dina helps her and they try to resolve some of the awkward tension
that they just experienced after Jesse's arrival.
Dina reveals that she's figured out using the radio that Nora, one of the Joel's squad
is stationed at the hospital and may know where Abby is.
Ellie takes off immediately and heads for that hospital,
and this is actually pretty quiet chapter of the game.
Because Ellie is, of course by herself.
There's no one to bounce anything off of, she's just alone.
而制作组也利用这个机会给玩家设了好多措手不及的局
And they are actually able to throw a couple curve balls at the player as a result of this,
我非常非常喜欢这点
which I actually really really enjoyed.
最好的例子就是艾莉在工作台这里
The best example would probably be when Ellie walks up to a workbench,
游戏中工作台是用来升级武器的
which is where you do all of your maintenance on all of your weapons,
用你满世界搜刮来的零件资源给你的武器升级
adding upgrades changing things out using the scrap that you find in the world,
而就在这时惊喜来了
at which point she's jumped.
我第一次玩的时候感觉这段太牛逼了
I thought this was super cool when I saw it,
我当时就……我靠！在菜单里也能被偷袭吗！
I was like ah … shoot! I'm not even safe in the menus now!
我……我理解可能有些人会被吓到 甚至有些生气
I … I … I understand this probably pissed some people off when freaked them out.
因为一般来讲在游戏的菜单界面肯定是绝对安全的
Because if anything, in video games' menus are sacred, you should be safe in a menu.
但这个例子打破了这个惯例 我觉得太棒了
But in this case you're not, and I just thought it was awesome.
Now let's also take this chance to discuss crafting a little bit.
The crafting system is pretty much identical to the first game,
except there's a few new items like pipe bombs.
Most character upgrades will only get about halfway through their upgrade tree
if you want to call it that throughout most runs.
New game plus lets you Max Level Ellie and Abby
by the time you're done playing each of their respective halves of the game,
which does make you feel like a superhero.
Now on higher difficulties, these crafting items are stupid scarce, really.
They're pretty hard to find than they don't tend to generate or populate in the world itself
unless you are really struggling later in the game.
But these dynamic policemen systems that Naughty Dog uses in these TLOU games works pretty well
and they don't have a lot of complaints about them, except for healing items.
These quick snacks and things that refill your health are far too plentiful on high difficulties,
at least in my mind, it makes the game too easy,
even though the combat is remarkably hard on, for instance, Survivor.
Part of the reason this is a problem in my mind is because molotovs are crafted using the same materials.
So effectively, the player is always faced with a choice
between crafting a healthcare and a Molotov cocktail.
Seems like a stupid delineation to draw, but I think it's important.
You see, health kits just represent a major mistake on the part of the player.
If you make a major mistake, you're probably going to die on a higher difficulty,
so it's not worth continuing.
You're usually just going to reload and save and continue on
with all the ammo you had before you made that big mistake.
This means that in my new game plus run on Survivor,
I almost never crafted any healing kits at all because Molotovs were far more useful.
And if I ever got to the point where my health was really, really low,
I would have just restarted from the previous save
and not made that same mistake that landed me in that tough spot.
The other piece to all of this looting and crafting crap is that
looting materials does make it feel as though you are exploring the levels.
And it motivates the player to explore the levels in most instances.
But the developers used a balanced, dynamic generation system that makes it.
So if you were preparing to go up against a boss fight, for instance,
more ammo will generate as you get closer to that boss
to bring you up to the recommended level that they set for that boss fighting counter.
Now of course, nothing is forcing you to pick up these items,
but the game will generate them more frequently and present them to you more obviously
if it calculates that you are in need of them.
On higher difficulties, it calculates you as needing less of them.
But nonetheless, it calculates you as needing these items,
which means that you don't actually have to explore the levels to find the items
you just have to get to the end of the level,
at which point there's a software gate before you move on to the next section.
And before that software gate is going to be a generation of items in certain stashes
that are going to refill your supplies before you move on.
But to be honest, I don't think that this is a major issue.
If anything, it's just a perk for speed runners.
And to be honest, it probably does more good than it does harm,
因为如果有玩家错过了某个有大量补给的区域
because it makes it so if players overlooked a certain area that had a lot of gear in it,
这个机制也不会让他们在之后的关卡中束手无策
they're not going to be totally screwed over in the next level.
But after this little jumps scare, we keep pushing through.
Ellie fights some Seraphites, or Scars,
solve some more puzzles, fight some more zombies,
including some stealth focused zombies that could have been an interesting if they weren't so damn stupid.
But the peak of this chapter is when we get our first extensive exposure to the Seraphites.
You see, they fight differently. They're much more stealthy and careful.
They communicate also through whistling.
Now depending on your sound system. Tweaking the audio settings could really work wonders.
Seriously, you can figure out where enemies are without needing to use the listen mode at all.
If you have a good pair of headphones or a surround sound theater, it's pretty damn cool.
And from what I can tell there's going to be even more of this type of thing
on next gen consoles with all of the Playstation 5 3D audio stuff they're doing.
It's really awesome, I can't wait.
Now a fun little detail just to prove the point of Naughty Dogs attention to detail
here as we push up on a bunch of Seraphites.
If we blow up all of the cult members before they're able to disembowel this man,
they actually have a backup.
Bear in mind, this is only possible if you happen to have explosive arrows unlocked
and crafted at this point in the game, which is a long stretch,
if you're playing through on the first run, so it's more of a new game plus problem.
If you do have it unlocked and you blow up all of the cult members
surrounding this man that's being hung and about to be disemboweled and killed,
he'll actually just hang and it's a much slower and more aggravated death,
unless you put him out of his misery.
I actually tested this,
where I tried to shoot the rope and cut him down to allow him to escape,
but I wasn't able to get it to work.
Maybe there is a way to do it, and I just have bad aim on the shore.
But nonetheless, it's still pretty cool that they have two states available.
For one, if they are able to finish their little ceremony,
kill him by hanging and disemboweling at the same time;
and then the other case being that you kill them before they are able to disembowel him,
at which point they just kick the bucket out and he hangs slowly.
Now you fight and sneak through multiple levels of these guys finishing on a mini boss fight
with a big Seraphite Brute, the same one that was seen in the Dina Ellie kiss trailer.
Now it's a little less polished in this final version, at least in my opinion,
it's less fluid, but it's still awesome.
What I mean by that is that there seems to be a lot less scripted elements and animations.
But to be honest, you'd probably expect that from a trailer.
Now there are grunts in the back room during this fight,
which actually makes this a really difficult to encounter a new game plus
considering that I had used all of my ammo by the time that I got here,
meaning that I had to take him on pretty much entirely with melee.
Now one of the frustrations with TLOU is that it requires a lot of trial and error.
A lot of the time the only way to figure out exactly how to get through a particular encounter
is by dying repeatedly and trying again.
The worst examples would be, for instance,
this scene where I had to run around into the back room,
try killing those guys first and then moving outside melee, trying to fight the big brute in the back room,
trying to fight the big brute in the front room, and then moving to the back room.
It required a lot of trial and error to figure out the best way to do it.
Another example would be when Ellie was trying to get the boat
in this flooded mall sequence a little bit later.
It's visually fascinating as a scene,
but on survivor it took around thirty minutes of experimenting to find the path
that just narrowly dodged everybody's perception.
And even then I'm not convinced that I should have escaped
because I got in the boat, started it and was spotted and then shot started coming in,
at which point a lot of bullets definitely hit Ellie,
and she probably should have died, but I was still allowed to escape.
From what I can tell Naughty Dog tweaked their aim while you're inside this boat
to make it feel as though you are whizzing past incoming fire.
But here I actually forgot that the boat controls in this game
are defaulted to the stupidest lay out possible.
So I sat there for a second holding down are too like a chump
before I realized that it was all steered using the left stick,
and by the time I figured it out,
I definitely should have died, but nonetheless I was allowed to live.
So the player and Ellie pushed to the hospital after the fight with the mini boss.
We stealth our way into the hospital.
We kill this check that is holding the Vita who we will also see again later in Abby's sections.
But don't worry, she's only in there for a couple of seconds.
And then we find out that WLF are clearing the hospital, which makes sense,
they want to make sure that there's no infected here,
but they're also taking all of their supplies back to their headquarters
for some reason that isn't explained.
Though we will figure it out later on when we play as Abby.
But as for right now, all we know is that Isaac, the leader,
ordered that all of the supplies be returned to the centralized location.
Now we go through a bunch of sequences
where we can either stealth or fight our way through a bunch of WLF.
It's not particularly important, it's just more of the same.
But eventually we push up to the top floor and find Nora.
She's talking with some other WLF about Abby.
Apparently she's missing and these WLF think
that Nora knows something about where she is headed and how she escaped.
It's a little confusing for Ellie because as far as Ellie knew,
埃比是WLF的负责人之一
Abby was one of the head honchos with the WLF.
Why is she being sought out by some of the members?
Why was she imprisoned?
Why is Nora going to be in trouble if it turns out she knows where Abby is?
It's very confusing, but it will make sense later.
As for the player right now,
it just seems as though Abby is in some sort of direct conflict with the group.
Now, for a brief moment,
I thought that perhaps we were going to pair up with WLF members to hunt Abby down.
After all, an enemy of our enemy is our friend.
But don't worry, they're not going to do this.
You chase Nora through the hospital
after a brief interaction where she pushes back at Ellie asking:
You chase her to a dead end with a break in the hallway that leads to the spore filled basement
as armed guards chase you.
Ellie takes Nora hostage and holds her as a body shield,
realizing that there's no way out,
and that Nora's knowledge of her immunity is of no importance
since she's going to die from the spores in just a few moments,
Ellie takes Nora into the basement,
kills some zombies and finds Nora cowering in a dead end hallway.
And then this sequence plays out wherein we see Ellie get her hands dirty.
Ellie returns to the theater covered in Nora's blood.
She's clearly distressed at what she's just done to figure out where Abby is.
But she did it.
And she knows that she's at the aquarium, for some reason.
Dina helps Ellie Clean up,
and it's here that we see the first visual example of
what this revenge pursuit is doing to Ellie, physically.
We can infer Ellie's mental distress through the dialog and behavior,
but it's still largely up to interpretation.
But these physical injuries are visual and apparent.
It's a brief and quiet scene.
在这段感人的片段过后 艾莉和蒂娜睡觉了
And after this touching moment, Ellie and Dina fall asleep,
故事进入西雅图第三天
which takes us to Seattle Day 3.
首先是一段两年前的回忆
We begin with a flashback to two years earlier
艾莉回到了一代作品中结尾部分的医院
when Ellie returned to the hospital from the end of the first game.
在探索了医院 发现了一些文书和最关键的录音记录后
After exploring the hospital, discovering some paper work and eventually recording,
她发现了曾经这里的真相
she finds out what truly happened here.
乔尔害怕永远失去艾莉 也终于不得不告诉她真相
And Joel is forced to tell the truth finally, so as to not lose her forever.
这标志着乔尔和艾莉关系的一个重要转折点
This marks a significant pivot in Joel and Ellie's relationship.
艾莉很早就知道乔尔并没有那样诚实
Ellie is known for a long time that Joel was being less than truthful.
她心里有数
She had her suspicions.
然而即使她对乔尔有所怀疑
However, even with those suspicions,
也仍然是往的好方面去想的 以免破坏两人的关系
she still gave Joel the benefit of the doubt so as to not wreck their relationship.
但现在 真相大白于天下 艾莉感受到了背叛
However, now, with the truth fully released out into the open air, Ellie feels betrayed.
她所担忧的一切都是真的
Everything she feared is true.
也许成功制作疫苗的几率并不高
Perhaps the odds of successfully making a vaccine were not particularly high,
特别是考虑到火萤组织在整个第一部作品中是多么的废物
especially considering how incompetent the Fireflies were throughout the entire first game.
但重要的是艾莉得知真相后
However, it's important to note that with this revelation,
她便明白这个概率并不完全是零
it's made clear to Ellie that the odds were not zero.
没错 概率不高 但不是完全没有
Sure, they might not have been great, but they weren't zero.
这给艾莉带来了巨大的负担 她觉得自己对人类有责任
That places a huge burden on Ellie shoulders, where she feels a duty to humanity,
要献出自己的生命来挽救其他人 这样就有可能重建人类文明
to give her life so that others can live and so that humanity could potentially build itself back up.
这是一个有趣的问题 特别是当你把自己放在她的位置上时
It's an interesting question, especially when you put yourself into her shoes.
如果你是艾莉你会怎样做？
What if you were in Ellie's position in this world?
如果你的性命关系到这一切的解药？
What if your life held the answer to the cure for all of this?
如果你能牺牲你自己 那这一切的苦难就有可能得到化解
All of the misery could be fixed if you were to sacrifice your life.
我用的是“可能”因为没人保证这真的会成功
Now there is an emphasis on COULD because there's no guarantee that it would actually work.
就算疫苗真的被研发出来了
And even if a vaccine were successfully developed,
谁又能在整个地球上分发这种疫苗？
who's to say that anyone would be able to distribute that vaccine throughout the planet?
毕竟TLOU2的背景是全世界的秩序已经彻底崩塌了
After all, one of the big focuses in TLOU2 is the fact that the world has gone to absolute hell.
人们会毫无理由地互相背叛
People betray each other left and right for seemingly no reason at all.
信任在这个世界里早已不复存在
Trust is something that basically doesn't exist in this world any more.
而且毫无疑问 如果有人屁颠屁颠跑到你的据点前
And without a doubt, if somebody were to waltz up to the front of your complex,
说自己有疫苗 有治愈虫草菌的办法
claiming that they had the vaccine, the cure to the Cordyceps fungus,
那你首先会持高度怀疑的态度 根本不会让他进入你的据点
chances are you would be highly skeptical and wouldn't allow them into the base at all.
关键是 我理解艾莉对乔尔擅自为她做决定而伤感
The point is, I understand that Ellie is frustrated that choice was removed from her,
而这个决定也是为了她好
and that decision was made for her.
然而即使是这样也不能改变这样一个现实：
However, even with that being the case, it doesn't change the reality
这个决定不是治愈与不治愈那么简单
that this decision is not as simple as cure versus no cure,
也不是艾莉能不能拯救人类那么简单
or Ellie saving humanity versus not saving humanity.
事情没那么简单 这个世界也不是非黑即白的
Nothing is that simple. Nothing is black and white in this world.
也许总体分析TLOU2故事情节的时候
Perhaps for purposes of general analysis within the story of TLOU2
你可以指着乔尔的行为说他为了拯救一个他非常关心的人而毁了全人类
you could point at Joel's actions and say that he damned humanity
for the sake of saving one individual that he cared greatly about.
然而我认为凡事都有两面性 因为你完全可以说
However, I think there's two sides to the coin and you could say that
即使疫苗研发出来了 也不太可能分发出去
even if they were able to develop some sort of vaccine, it wouldn't have actually gone anywhere,
或者只能用在一个很小的社区环境内
or at the very least it would have been contained within a very small community.
那么如果确实如此的话
But at the same time you could also say that if that were the case
如果疫苗只在火萤组织或者WLF内部使用
and if the vaccine were only used within the Fireflies or the WLF
因为这些组织最后都分散到全国各地
as they eventually became after being splintered across the country,
那你的确可以说艾莉的牺牲是值得的
then you could say that Ellie sacrifice would have been worth it
因为她能拯救几十条 甚至成百上千条生命
because she could have saved dozens or perhaps hundreds or even thousands of lives.
当然不如几万几亿数量级那么多 但也是个很伟大的数字了
Sure, it's less than millions or billions, but none the less that's a significant number.
更广泛的观点是 艾莉觉得这个选择好像是为她而做的
The broader point is that Ellie feels as though this choice was made for her,
因为的确如此
because it was,
而且艾莉因为乔尔欺骗了她多年而感受到了来自乔尔的背叛
and she feels as though Joel betrayed her,
especially considering that he's been lying to her about it for years.
But after this flashback, we cut back to Ellie waking up in the theater,
and she goes looking for Jesse and Dina.
After a brief conversation about Dina's pregnancy,
Ellie and Jesse decided to push out towards the aquarium together.
They think that Abby is likely hiding out there.
They don't know why she would be there,
and they don't know why she would be running from or have reason to be afraid of the WLF.
After all, they seemed to be the group that she originated from.
So at the very least it should get the player intrigued as to what actually happened.
When I first played the game,
I thought, perhaps it was that they were acting out against her
after she took this group AWOL to go and find Joel.
However, that doesn't actually make much sense,
considering that all of the other people that went with her on that trip
seemed to be operating in their regular profession just fine.
So at the end of the day,
all we're left with is a suspicious absence on Abby's part from the group
and lots of gossip that's overheard between the characters.
But regardless Ellie and Jesse push up towards the aquarium.
And the section in my opinion, is actually pretty unremarkable.
There's not a lot of interesting fight sequences here,
and more broadly,
it's just served as a chance for Ellie and Jesse
to get all of the drama about Dina's pregnancy out on the table.
Over the course of the sequence, they determined that she has to return to Jackson.
There's no other way.
If she is to receive any semblance of healthcare in the lead up to the delivery of the child,
she's going to need to return to where they came from.
This, in turn means that this is likely their last chance to find Abby,
because once they find Tommy,
they're all going to pack up and head back to Jackson together.
Chances are Jesse and Dina, and especially Tommy, are not going to allow Ellie to remain.
Now Jesse knows that it's his baby.
Yeah, he's heard that Dina hasn't told him that she's pregnant yet.
She's keeping it a secret, which seems kind of stupid, but I guess that's just me.
Regardless, the motivations have shifted.
Jesse is not as concerned about finding Abby and getting revenge.
Rather, he's looking for Tommy so that they can all return to Jackson together
whereas Ellie claims the same.
However, she is much more concerned with finding Abby as we'll see in just a moment.
This whole climaxes when Jesse and Ellie here over a radio that there's a sniper on the pier,
that's taking out a bunch of WLF members in causing trouble more generally.
Jesse and Ellie determined that this has to be Tommy.
And it's actually a fair point because the WLF wouldn't be sniping themselves.
And the Scars don't actually use sniper rifles in this way, so it's likely not them.
So it's either Tommy or another rogue individual
who happens to just be sniping WLF members for fun.
And of course it ends up being Tommy at the end of the day,
but it's here that we see Ellie make a decision that's much harder to justify.
She insists that Tommy is going to be OK by himself and that he doesn't need her help.
While this is perhaps true, it's more the thought that counts.
Of course, Tommy has made it this long.
And the fact that he sniping WLF members
shows that he's at least somewhat confident in his abilities to deal with them.
However, Ellie isn't saying this because she wants to protect Jesse or herself, or Dina's well being.
Rather, she's seeing it purely because she wants to get to Abbey quickly, kill her,
and then be able to leave with Tommy, Jesse and Dina back to Jackson,
having accomplished everything she set out to do.
I don't know about you guys,
but when I first played the game,
this was the moment that I immediately lost all sympathy for Ellie.
At this point, she's making, what seems to me, the wrong decision.
She's potentially damning all of those that she seems to love, for her own selfish pursuit,
which is thematically related to what Joel did in the first game,
where he seemingly screwed over humanity to serve his own private interests.
And once again, this is something that they do time and time again
throughout the course of the game.
There's parallels all over the course mirror sequences that are meant to echo what happened previously.
It's all over the place.
Needless to say, Jesse is just as disappointed in Ellie for this decision
as the player is likely disappointed in her.
So he breaks off and goes to find Tommy
and help him get back to the theater so that they can all leave together.
However, Ellie splits off alone.
And she fights for a boat that she saw driving through a canal
that she hopes to take to the aquarium that's across the harbour.
Now this sequence is super tough and especially in higher difficulties.
It requires an almost exclusively stealth approach.
Now, thankfully, the designers seem to have anticipated this fact,
which is why most of the levels have secret passageways
that you can find to get around most of the enemies
so that you either don't have to kill any of them to get through to the next checkpoint,
or you only have to kill a select few.
In my opinion, these are the best designed levels in the entirety of the game.
It's where the stealth mechanics really shine, and TLOU2 is at its best.
So you continue pushing to the aquarium
and you fight your way through several waves of Seraphites,
take on a Bloater or two, and you solve some environmental puzzles.
Nothing too difficult, but none the less they're there.
You eventually get your boat to the mouth of the harbour
and you start heading towards the shore over by the aquarium.
It's at this point that Ellie's overtaken with a rogue wave and almost drowned,
but ends up just barely escaping to the shore of the aquarium outcrop.
And I will just say this whole sequence is done so smoothly and beautifully well.
I can't complemented enough.
I'm not a game developer myself,
but I have delved into a lot of the intricacies involved with designing levels and managing memory systems
to see what they're able to do throughout the course of this game,
and especially this sequence is absolutely ridiculous,
and I have to applaud all of the developers over a Naughty Dog for their hard work.
But with that out of the way,
Ellie pushes into the aquarium and finds a few strange things.
There are several doors locked,
there's lights on and there's bloody instruments strewn across an operation table.
With the context we have in the game so far,
we assume that there must have been some strange torture session going on here and nothing more.
However, as we'll see later, this wasn't as terrible as it seems.
Ellie climbs into an air duct, and then the following sequence plays out.
This dog may seem like it's just another dog.
After all, it was shown off in the trailers, as just some mud that you put down.
But don't worry, we're going to see a lot. more of her later.
Ellie recovers, but here's some muffled voices through a double door,
She pushes through, and the following happens.
Needless to say, this is a deeply upsetting sequence.
It's one that I personally saw coming a mile away.
You see one thing I do know about the writer's over a Naughty Dog,
especially Neil Druckmann and Halley Gross,
is that they love their similes.
They loved the reflections between characters.
It gives you a chance to see how these two different people respond to similar situations.
And so whenever you start to see things that are similar or things that characters have in common,
you have to assume that the developers and writers
are going to force those two characters into a similar situation where those similarities can come out.
In this case, Ellie's girlfriend, Dina, is pregnant.
And one of the first things that we hear about Owen and Abby's group in general
is that Mel is pregnant.
At this point in the game we don't know who Mel is
when we're standing on this snowy hillside overlooking Jackson.
But I personally knew that there was a very good chance
that Ellie would end up killing her pregnant friend Mel
simply because Dina was likely going to end a pregnant as well.
And sure enough, when Dina is revealed to be pregnant,
this point was solidified for me.
Now besides the predictability of this plot point, I have to ask one other question,
which is whether or not Ellie would have actually killed Owen and Mel if they had tattled on Abbey.
And given what we know about Ellie in this game,
I think the odds are pretty good that she probably would have.
It's horrible to say, but Ellie was here for revenge.
She knows that these people were there, even though technically she owes her life to Owen.
Owen is the one that stepped in when Ellie was on the floor, staring at Joel's corpse.
While everyone else wanted to kill her to clean up after themselves,
which objectively probably would have been the smarter thing to do,
especially considering how TLOU2 plays out.
But nonetheless, she technically owes her life to Owen.
Even so, I think she would have killed him.
The other question that you have to ask is where is Abby and what happened.
Where did she go?
How long is it going to be before she finds out what Ellie is done?
Why did she leave in the first place?
Now it's implied that she's fleeing from Ellie.
However, this doesn't really make a lot of sense,
especially when you consider that she's already fleeing something else.
It seems as though she's involved in something that's taking her away from her duties within the WLF,
which is why Isaac seems to be upset with her.
But nonetheless, I think Naughty Dog is trying to keep the story moving along
so that you don't think about it long enough to realize that there's got to be more to it.
And honestly, I'm okay with that.
Especially because Ellie herself isn't particularly interested
in the reasons why Abbey is going to the places she's going
or why Abby seems to be at odds with the rest of her group.
All she's interested in is revenge.
And the last thing about this sequence is that I can't help but feel as though it's a little strange
that Tommy, Jesse and Ellie just leave after this.
他们看见了地上的尸体 却选择了转身离去
They see the dead bodies on the floor, and don't do anything more.
竟然还押韵了 我不是故意的
That rhymed, I didn't mean it to rhyme.
I'm sorry, but I'm … you know what we're leaving it in.
No, I'm not demanding an elaborate sequence
where we clear the entire aquarium of any sort of bogey
to make sure that Abby is not some were hiding within the aquarium.
But at the very least,
it seems odd that they wouldn't have done a more elaborate check throughout the rest of the building.
They just find Ellie, and clearly she's pretty shaken up about what she has just done.
But they just leave.
Perhaps at this point, they have just accepted that they're not going to find Abby.
That's not destined to be.
And that they've done enough damage that they've made their point.
Regardless, the scenes after this are actually quite calm and it's fairly refreshing.
We see Ellie in bed with Dina, and they're just resting.
After a while Ellie goes, and talks with Jesse and Tommy,
trying to determine the best route back to Jackson.
They've officially determined that they can't stay and find Abby,
but rather need to get Dina somewhere safe for the sake of her unborn child.
All is normal, until this …
This is a stunningly sudden and sharp narrative beat.
I knew something was coming, but I didn't know that it would happen this suddenly.
Jesse's death happens almost instantaneously as the cut scene begins,
there's no warning, there was no forethought, it simply happens and Jesse's dead.
There's also a problem with what the fuc … what it …  What is that?
What it … That's gross. Stop it, OK, OK, a slight detour.
I know this is a serious scene and it's sad and everything.
But it was almost completely ruined because the first time that I play through the game,
Ellie has a bandage on her arm.
It's not actually supposed to be there.
It's from the previous sequence when she patched herself up.
However, it did something strange where it's warped the actual mesh of her arm.
So it looks that she has some sort of weird noodle bone disease.
It … it's bizarre and I wouldn't complain about it,
except that when I went back through the game on new game plus
it didn't happen and her arm looked normal.
So I can tell that this was a glitch.
It's just a really, really weird one that I don't really know what to make of.
But nonetheless it … it happened,
and I am going to have nightmares about this weird T-Rex arm that she has.
But nonetheless it happened, hopefully this didn't happen to you,
but for me it almost spoiled the entire scene because I found myself giggling at her messed up arm.
But … you know, I'll leave it there.
到了这里 游戏的前半部分就算结束了
Now this marks the end of the first half of the game.
别急 我之后会讨论玩到游戏中期的想法
And don't worry, we're going to discuss midpoint thoughts
以及我游玩过程中的心路历程 情绪等等一切的想法
and where I was at in my play through, what my emotions were, what I thought of everything.
但首先我想先过一遍接下来的场景
But first, I want to go through the next scene.
在埃比枪杀杰西 貌似杀死了汤米 同时拿枪指着艾莉的镜头之后
You see right after Abby kills Jesse, seemingly kills Tommy, and is holding Ellie at gunpoint,
我们直接跳转到了一个年轻 还没有那么多肌肉的埃比
we jump to a clip of a young, non-yoked Abby.
她在找她爸爸 而她爸爸在找某只动物
She's looking for her dad, who is in turn looking for some animal,
后来发现是一只产仔过后的斑马
that turns out to be a zebra that's just given birth.
这段很温暖 给我们过去十小时游戏经历的悲痛带来了些许慰藉
It's cute, and it's a nice break from the dread that the last ten hours have brought.
说真的 我之前都没意识到TLOU2的前半部分玩着有多么艰难
Seriously I didn't realize how much of a trudge the first half of TLOU2 felt like
直到我玩到这个场景 感觉就像是从第一代结尾直接跳到这里一样
until we got to the sequence and it felt like something straight out of the first game.
至少对我而言 我感觉艾莉在这作是一个非常难相处的人
Ellie, God bless her, is a really difficult person to relate to in this sequel, at least for me.
在第一部作品中 她身上有一些能引起所有人共鸣的人性特点
In the first game, there was something really human about her,
something that was reflective of all of us.
玩家能与乔尔和艾莉以某种难以名状而遥不可及的方式产生情感共鸣
We can all connect with her and we can all connect with Joel in some weird, distant way.
然而这在第二部作品中表现却寥寥无几
However, in the second game, there's not much of that to be seen or had.
这让我实在喜欢不起来续作中的艾莉
But nonetheless I can't help but feel as though Ellie is painfully unlikable in the sequel,
所以游戏前半部分操控艾莉的时候总有种奇怪的感觉
which is why it's all the more bizarre to go through the first half of the game with Ellie,
你不会太喜欢她 也无法饶恕她做出的事情
where you don't particularly like her, or condone any thing that she's doing.
然后剧情到了你操控的埃比杀死了你慢慢开始尊敬 喜爱甚至爱上了的角色
And then you reach this point after this character you're playing as Abby
has killed characters that you really began to respect and enjoy and even love.
但你发现自己开始慢慢了解埃比 对她性格的喜欢甚至远超艾莉
But now you find yourself relating to her and liking her personality way more than Ellie's.
这种体验很非同寻常 我认为其中有一半是制作者刻意为之的
It's really bizarre and I think it was half intentional and half not.
也就是说我认为这段埃比好相处与惹人喜欢的品质是刻意安排的
What I mean is that I think Abby's relatability and likability, was completely intentional,
而前半部分艾莉让人喜欢不起来的感受则不完全是刻意安排的
that I don't think that Ellie's lack of likability was completely intended.
当然 在这个时间点我觉得绝大多数玩家是非常憎恨埃比的
Now of course, at this point in the game, players for the most part are going to hate Abby.
我不怪大家
I wouldn't blame them.
毕竟她杀死了游戏史上最让玩家喜爱的角色乔尔
She killed Joel, one of the most beloved characters in gaming history.
我也理解游戏强迫你操控埃比所带来的厌恶感
And I understand that frustration that now we are forced to play as her.
然而 游戏制作者希望你能给埃比一个机会
However, they want you to give Abby a chance,
也正因如此 他们把时间调回了四年前
which is why they rewind the clock to four years before the events of this game.
我之前提到过
Now, as I mentioned earlier,
我曾做过一次调查 统计大家对这个游戏的看法
I conducted a massive poll of all of you guys to see what you thought of the game,
无论这个游戏是否达到了你的期待 都可以畅所欲言
and whether or not you felt as though it lived up to your expectations.
如果没有达到 那怎样改会更好
And if it didn't, what it could have done better.
调查中有几十个问题
There were several dozens of questions involved in the survey,
我不会在这一一列举这些问题 不过我已经整理好了一个Excel表格
so I'm not going to go through all of them, but I will include a Excel spreadsheet
大家可以随意筛选各种问题的答案
that you can actually use to sift through all of the answers yourself if you would like to.
这当中其实有很多有趣的信息
There's actually a lot of really interesting information in here,
我花了大约一周筛选了大量的回复
and I've spent the better part of a week sifting through a lot of the responses,
因为其中有很多宝贵的留言
because there's a lot of really good stuff here.
但其中令我震惊的一点是
But one of the things that I was stunned to realize
很多人在游戏玩到这就弃坑了
is that a lot of people actually gave up on the game at this point.
他们完成了游戏前半部分 大部分时间都很享受艾莉的章节
They got through the first half of the game enjoyed Ellie's sections for the most part,
但当他们看到自己要被迫操控埃比的时候
but once they saw that they are going to be forced to play as Abby,
他们就觉得受到了背叛 放弃游戏了
they felt betrayed and stopped playing completely.
我本来想直接放一些玩家们表达的这种挫折感的评论
Now I was going to show some direct quotations from some of the gamers that expressed this frustration.
但奈何其中一些人的言语实在难登大雅之堂
However, many of them had too much profanity for me to comfortably include in this video
要是放出来的话我这频道收益化就拜拜了
with any hopes of getting monetized at the end of the day.
所以我打算简单转述一下他们的意思
So I am simply going to paraphrase.
如果你想看实际评论内容的话
But if you want to read the actual word for word responses again,
视频下方会有整个调查结果的链接
I'll have the entire survey and all of the responses linked below.
总的来说 在这个时间点放弃游戏的玩家认为
In general, the people that quit the game at this point felt as though
他们被迫要与一个毫无兴趣的人产生情感上的交集
they were being forced to relate to somebody that had no interest in relating to.
但仔细想想这又有点奇怪
It's kind of a bizarre idea when you think about it,
会有人因为不得不去控制某些角色体会她的心路历程而感到不安
that somebody would be so upset that they would have to relate to somebody
以至于会直接关掉游戏彻底弃坑
that they would turn off the game entirely and walk away.
但还真就有
But here we are.
真要说的话 我觉得这反而是对顽皮狗角色塑造能力的一种赞美
If anything, it could be construed as a compliment to the character building
正因为之前乔尔这个角色太有亲和力了
and the relatability and care that people felt towards Joel initially,
导致玩家对他和以他为代表的这个想象中的角色会表现得非常忠诚
that they are so loyal to him and this imaginary character that he represents
使得玩家不愿意给杀死他的角色一丁点时间
that they won't even give the time of day effectively to the character that brought on his demise.
我也能完全想到顽皮狗内部做这个决定时会多么两极分化
And I completely understand how polarizing this decision was on Naughty Dog's part.
决定让埃比和艾莉都成为主角
It would have been a very early decision
并让她们各自占一半的流程本应是开发流程中一个非常早的决定
in the development process to have Abby and Ellie costars of this game,
to the point where they're both playable for roughly half of the game each.
值得庆幸的是至少在我看来 在大多数情况下 游戏做的还相当不错
And thankfully it seems to have for the most part, been done fairly well, at least in my opinion.
我理解有些人一开始就不同意这样的安排
I understand that some people who disagree with the thematic decision at the outset.
但这不是问题所在 问题在于当前的安排是否执行顺利
But that's not really the question. the question is whether or not it was well executed.
Now, once we've gotten through Abby sections,
I'll be able to talk a lot more about whether or not I feel as though
they struck a good balance in trying to present both characters equally.
I think the biggest problem with TLOU2 has to do was its pace.
It gets really easy to doze off and lose focus, especially in the last third of the game.
After all, TLOU2 asks a lot of the player.
It's not that easy actually to stay intrigued and involved in everything that's going on,
especially because it's so emotionally taxing.
But don't worry, we're going to get into all of that a little bit later.
As you go through this sequence,
you eventually find the zebra that's been trapped in some barbed wire,
and Abby helps her father with Owen's assistance cut her loose.
She runs off in cuddles with her newborn in a field
directly across from the hospital that we saw at the end of the first game, St. Mary's.
Their group is informed that Marlin's girl just arrived
and that it seems as though she actually is immune as they were initially told.
This is, of course, Ellie.
Just as she was found at the end of the first game.
We then cut to Marlin from the first game, arguing with Abby's dad
about whether or not to perform the operation that could lead to a vaccine.
It's actually the conversation that we always wanted to hear.
You see Abby's dad wants to do it.
He feels as though the sacrifice of Ellie is going to be worth it
because it could potentially save thousands or even millions of lives.
The problem is that they can't afford to ask Ellie or Joel.
They have to do it and ask for forgiveness.
If they were to ask Ellie, she would likely say yes.
But if they were to ask Joel, he would likely say no.
And as we found out, he would also likely go berserk.
It's at the end of this discussion that Abby comes in the room, bringing her father some dinner.
And she offers a fairly interesting anecdote.
Immediately after this, we cut to black and we transitioned the Abby running into the operating room.
Finding her dad, dead.
This is why Abby wanted to kill Joel.
This made all the clear by the immediate cut to Joel's death to reaffirm the point.
It may seem a little ham fisted, but I actually really like this,
because now we can hear this sequence without the murmur and drowning out
that we had the first time that we saw it.
Now we can hear the entire conversation, the debate that goes back and forth.
This is the midpoint of the game, really.
As far as we can tell, we're done playing as Ellie.
The next sequence pops up with Seattle Day 1,
implying that we're going to be going back through the entirety of what we just did with Ellie,
but from Abby's perspective.
It's an interesting flip, and the change of perspective is,
after all, the operative narrative element of this entire game's design.
But I can't help but feel as though many players are going to already be exhausted
from the journey that they just endeavored on.
This is why at this point in the game, pace is more important than ever.
You have to keep the player engaged,
especially because many of us probably felt as though
we had just played through an entire game by itself.
And now you're asking us to play through another game with another character,
but in this case, the villain, as far as we're concerned,
and you want us to give her the same time of day and attention that we give Ellie,
a character that we have a deep relationship built up with
after having played a game with her back in 2013.
It really is a lot to ask,
and I don't really blame a lot of players that decided to walk away at this point.
Sure, they may never get the actual story resolved with what happened
when that Abby pulled the gun on Ellie in the theater,
or perhaps they simply fast forwarded and watched a run through of the game after that point.
And lastly, most players are going to have a very skeptical outlook at this second half.
We're all looking for reasons to dislike Abbey.
After all, she's done something that we would deem most likely unforgivable.
However, I would like to think that most of us would have an open enough mind to play through this
and see whether or not they could be convinced of whether or not she was justified.
In that survey I conducted, it seemed as though the overwhelming majority of people
that decided to walk away from the game didn't play it after this particular point,
and those people tended to rate the game very negatively, averaging around a 4 to 5.
However, of the people that played the game all the way through,
the majority of them rated the game in the range of an 8 to 9.
Seems to be the conclusion is fairly clear.
Those that gave the game the chance to prove itself to them
ended up enjoying it once they experienced the whole thing.
Whereas those that decided to cut and run
had the experience that you would expect from somebody who cuts and runs.
It really is that simple.
You have to give a game like this the chance to do its job.
What they're trying to do is convince you that a character you hate
is actually a human being that has feelings and emotions
that are perhaps just as justified as the character you'd find relatable.
That argument isn't made over the course of an hour gameplay sequence.
It takes time and it takes a lot of effort.
And more than anything, it takes the open mind of the observer.
It may seem like a cliche for many people to say
"Well, if you didn't like TLOU2 when you quit halfway through,
you just didn't get it, and you were never going to like it".
However, I think there is a fair amount of truth in that.
But I don't know, let me know what you think.
What I do know is that at this point, in my first run of the game, I was highly exhausted.
Abby Sequences required a lot of effort, both emotionally and physically, to get through.
With the emotional tension and all of the gore,
it's an exhausting 10 to 15 hours of game play to get through.
And I will be honest, even I considered taking a break before continuing on with Abby sequences.
But I decided to put my head down and give the game the chance that it was asking for.
But regardless, this is the time when we begin playing as Abby.
The pace changes, the attitude changes, the tone changes.
And more broadly, even the style of character work changes.
In many ways, it's going to feel like a different game entirely both for better and worse.
But don't worry, we're going to get into all of it.
Seattle Day 1,
Abby wakes up and we begin the second half of the game
playing as who most of us will consider to be the antagonist.
However, this might change by the time we get to the end.
This whole game is, of course, about perspective in relativism,
and to that extent it works fairly simply.
We're going to be forced to play as Abby at least
until we either start to enjoy her as a character like her or even love her,
or at the very least, until we forget how much we hate her.
这样的转变不能一蹴而就
It's not going to happen instantly,
而是需要8-12小时的游戏内容去慢慢渗透
but over the course of the next 8 to 12 hours of game play,
你才能慢慢缓解你对她曾经的恨意
you're probably going to start to lose the hatred you felt for her at one point.
这里埃比和曼尼搭档 而他也在去杰克逊小镇的一行人中
Here Abby is paired with Manny, who was one of the assailants in Jackson.
你会在这种非常轻松的场合中遇见很多人 这种感觉有点魔幻
You'll see a lot of them in very casual settings here, it almost feels surreal.
你恨这些人 他们杀死了乔尔
You hate these people, these people killed Joel.
为什么他们跟没事人一样吃得下饭睡得着觉
Why are they so normal, and why do they seem so happy and relaxed.
You explore the WLF base where their station, which is actually built out of a stadium.
You're preparing to go out on a mission,
and so naturally you grab guns, a burrito and play fetch with a dog.
Now Mel is going with Abby and Manny on this patrol.
Of course, this is the same girl that we just saw Ellie kill.
Once again, it's a little surreal.
You just saw this woman get murdered, and Ellie freak out as a result,
and you also know that Abby freaked out as a result of Ellie's actions towards Mel and Owen,
so to see her seemingly fine in this particular instance, is a little startling.
Nonetheless, Abby and Manny debate for a brief moment
as to whether or not Mel should be allowed to go with them.
After all, she's pretty damn pregnant, as you can probably see.
But they dismiss it because they don't expect to see any action there
basically just going to go on a quick patrol,
make sure that there's nothing to concerning out there,
and if there is, they're going to call in support,
at which point it wouldn't actually matter that Mel is there.
In my opinion, it's still a stupid decision to bring what is a very pregnant woman
on what is effectively a military mission to scout out the surrounding area.
But that's just me, and it's actually Abby too.
At the end of this sequence, Abby actually gives me any crap for having brought Mel along
and says that she definitely should never have been allowed to come in the first place.
But nonetheless, they allowed her to go, from the outset.
Now, while speaking of Mel, the fact that she's pregnant and we just saw her get murdered by Ellie,
I think it's also important that we addressed the elephant in the room
that some have said actually ruins the game.
That is that knowing what's going to happen removes all of the stakes in the story.
After Ellie's whole half of the game, we know that most of these characters are going to die.
And more importantly, we know how they're going to die and when they're going to die.
And so going through these sequences where we're trying to protect them or do things with and for them,
it removes a lot of the tension, since we know how it's all going to end.
However, I strongly disagree with this idea.
There are countless stories where the conclusion is known before the story even really begins.
You could look at something as simple and kitschy as the movie Titanic,
a fascinating film about an albeit cheesy and captivating romance.
But at its core, we all know how that story is going to end.
The Titanic is not magically going to make it back to New York,
but rather it's going down and many people are going to die.
But it's still an interesting and captivating story
because it's not actually about the destination that the story reaches.
It's about the journey to that destination.
或者另一个游戏中的例子是2018年的《战神》
Or in a gaming example, we could look at God of War from 2018.
我们从游戏一开始就已经知道游戏结局是奎托斯和阿特柔斯
We know from the beginning of the game that the story is going to end with Kratos and Atreus
将菲的骨灰撒在九界最高峰
spreading Faye's ashes from the highest peak in the realms.
We know the ending from the start.
and yet the story is still captivating because it's not just about reaching that destination.
Again, to me this seems fairly obvious,
but it is actually a pretty common accusation against stories that have presumed endings.
In my mind, if you're going to allow a story to be ruined,
Simply because you know how the characters are going to end up at the end of that story,
you're not actually engaging and absorbing the media in the correct,
or at the very least, most effective way.
Regardless, Abby leaves on the back of a truck out on patrol with Manny, and Mel
and of course, the dog, Alice.
Remember, I said, that that dog that we found in the aquarium earlier that
Ellie actually stabs the crap out of
would come back again well … yeah, this … this is actually the same dog.
It's Alice, and she's cute and lovable, and Ellie kills the crap out of her.
Abby and Mel talk about how they're doing.
Apparently everybody's been struggling with sleep ever since they killed Joel in Jackson.
Abby and Owen are also going out on countless open assignments trying to keep busy
and exhaust themselves to the point where they don't have to think about what they've done.
These are hardened militaristic people
and the fact that they're so torn up over what they did to Joel.
It's interesting.
Because at the very least, it shows that they were somewhat distressed by what they did
and perhaps even some of them regretted.
This is the first step towards humanizing these people that you wanted to villainize from the start.
It's subtle, but it works.
It also breaks the perception that Abby and the crew are simply cold blooded killers.
They're humans, and yeah, they do so messed up stuff.
But some of them can feel regret over something that they felt was unjust.
Or at the very least, a bad choice.
However, this gets interrupted by a group of Seraphites, ambushing the group on horseback.
I personally hate these sequences.
The aiming is awkward, the damage feels unfair, and often it's just generally awkward.
If we compare it to other car sequences,
like the one earlier with Jesse traveling all the way down into the river.
It's not quite the same.
The one with Ellie and Jesse is very scripted from start to finish
and feels fair because it's so heavily scripted.
The player doesn't actually have that much agency.
However, if you don't do anything in this car sequence when you're ambushed by the Seraphites
you're going to be killed and have to reload.
So you have to be actively engaging with the game in its most awkward state,
which to me means that its subject and worthy of criticism since you're forced to engage with it.
Now, Abby and her group eventually get to safety.
You push through several different buildings,
and after fighting through multiple waves of infected and more Seraphites,
you find yourself in a gas station being ambushed by yet another wave of Seraphites.
Now a lot of this just feels like bloat.
And when we're talking about pacing,
that's the last thing that you want to be thinking when going through this stage of the game,
players need to be more engaged than they have been in the entire game to this point.
But I think most people are going to start to feel bored because it just feels like more of the same.
有一些轻佻有趣的时刻
There are some interesting moments of levity,
也有一些令角色展现人性一面的时刻
and there are moments where these characters are actually humanized a lot,
这或许是游戏这段内容的更重要的意义
which is perhaps more the point of this section of the game.
It's not really about keeping the player super engaged,
it's about making sure that the player starts to relate to these people that they previously hated.
I know it's a lot to ask that we get both an interesting game play sequence that keeps the player engaged
and humanizing sequences with these characters.
But nonetheless, I wish that there were something a little bit more engaging.
My favorite part is probably when Abby is discussing her fear of heights with Mel.
It's a small moment, and it's something that could be easily missed,
but I actually find it really endearing.
Once you hit the gas station and after a shoot out in a rail yard,
a crew of WLF members,
presumably alerted by the assault that happened just a few minutes before,
come in and save the day,
killing all of the Seraphites that we're about to get the jump on you.
And so you're all rescued, and you brought to the forward base as it's called.
Mel goes to get patched up while Abby and Manny go into see Isaac.
Finally, we're going to get to meet the head honcho,
the guy that we've been hearing all about
for the last 12 or so hours of gameplay since Elie got to Seattle.
On the way up to see Isaac Abby and Manny are told
that Owen was actually off with another member of the squad,
and that he shot that guy, Danny in order to save quote unquote "some Scar".
Needless to say, this could lead to a death sentence for Owen if proven true,
we don't really know what exactly happened.
But if Owen did actually kill a WLF member
simply to save what's considered a barbarian pest on their people,
It ain't good end a pretty bad for Owen.
And so Abby and Manny head up to talk with Issac
and Isaac probably has the most badass introduction of any character in this game.
Now Isaac doesn't want them to go and save Owen
because they are revving up for some big assault on the scars, and he can't spare them.
Abby says "Screw it" and they go after him anyways, because why not?
Now there's two things about this.
For one, Abby leaving the group to go and find Owen
explains why she seems to have gone AWOL in all of those sequences,
when Ellie was trying to figure out what was going on;
and why Abby was not with the rest of the group.
The WLF were upset with her and wanted to hunt her down
because she went AWOL and disobeyed Isaacs orders.
This, of course, doesn't mean that she's not a threat to Ellie,
but it does mean that she's not as interested in simply pursuing the goals
and hopes and aspirations of the WLF as Ellie perhaps initially thought.
Abby is much more of an individual,
and perhaps that's even something that Ellie and Abbey have in common.
The other thing about this is that it seems relatively easy for Abby to go AWOL
and disobey direct orders like this.
Maybe it's just that she's particularly capable,
and so she was able to sneak out with any major issue.
But she also doesn't seem particularly threatened by Isaac,
which is strange considering that our introduction to him is of him torturing a guy.
So whether its hubris or simply a lack of consideration,
Abby breaks out and decides to go find Owen herself.
Her hope, of course, being that she's going to be able to save Owen
and figure something out before the big raid on the Seraphites
so that she's never realized to have gone missing.
We then have a quick cutaway where we go to a short date between Abby and Owen.
They're on a Ferris wheel, and it's actually super cute.
Once again we see that Abby is terrified of heights,
and it's again a humanizing moment to see her chilling with Owen and also freaked out.
然而这就又到了讨论叙事节奏问题的时候了
However, once again, this is a point when the pace really starts to come into question.
这里在讲什么？为何节奏如此缓慢？
What is the deal here? Why is it moving so slowly?
为什么我们要融入这段我们不太了解 甚至多数人完全不关心的角色的回忆？
Why are we going through all of these cutaways with characters we don't particularly know,
and most people probably don't care that much about yet?
我们什么时候能进入一段更有趣更快速的叙事片段？
When we need to be engaged and going through a much more interesting and fast base sequences?
也许可能只有我这样 喜欢快节奏的叙事片段
Now perhaps I'm alone, in my tolerance for fast pace narrative sequences is much much higher.
所以我希望多多益善
So I need a lot more.
也许这部游戏就是这样 所以节奏上可能没我想的那么糟
Maybe that's what it is, and the pace isn't actually as bad as it seems to me.
但在即将到来的西雅图第2天和第3天的内容中
But in these sequences that are coming over the course of Seattle Day 2 and 3,
游戏中很多片段真的开始大大放慢节奏了
the games really going to slow to a crawl in multiple moments.
我也不是很懂……欢迎在评论区讨论
But I don't know, let me know what you think.
The date is relatively cute
and at ends within the aquarium with Abby and Owen talking about their feelings.
At one point, Abby breaks away, she's got something else on her mind,
and it turns out that she's still thinking about Joel.
They're trying to find some way of finding him so that they can enact some sort of revenge.
Owen doesn't seem particularly interested in that pursuit,
even though he did know Abby's father fairly well from what we can tell.
But he understands this means a lot to Abby,
and so he goes along with it, at least for the most part.
What is clear is that this is Abby's pursuit, and this is what Abby wants.
And she's not going to quit until she finds Joel and kills him.
She references multiple times that they need to get back to training,
which explains why she is currently not particularly shredded,
at least compared to what we see in the present day
quote unquote sequences of Abby going through and fighting infected,
and of course Ellie and her gang.
That's why in many moments I think her physical buffness and appearance
is a direct reflection of her mental state,
which is why later in the game, when she's led off of that revenge base pursuit,
she actually thins out a lot and is no longer as much of a meat head.
But other than the pace, this is actually starting to work.
I found myself actually caring about Abby and Owen,
and being involved and interested in what was going on within their lives.
It's kind of bizarre to say, but I was starting to feel bad for Joel's murderer.
We then cut to Abby and Manny at the outskirts of the WLF's territory.
She's going to find Owen, and for some reason Manny leaves her to go on by herself.
He claimed, so it's not to draw too much attention and to get them in trouble with Isaac.
Even with this excuse,
it seems like a bit of a stretch that Manny would leave her to go on by herself.
But I'm willing to let it slide, it's not that big of a deal.
Now the navigation in this chapter is actually pretty interesting,
and it's done in a subtle and beautiful way.
All you have to do is follow the sunset.
It's simple, it's elegant,
and it's easy to understand and follow as you explore a given level.
Because pretty much all of the lighting in TLOU2 is ambient.
You're always in tune with the direction of light that's coming in from the outside.
And I have to say while exploring multiple of these levels,
focusing on the sunlight coming in through the windows to reorient myself,
I found it remarkably natural and really cool at just how fluidly this worked.
I personally can't remember the last time
that a game used the sunlight to direct players in a particular way,
but I find that kind of refreshing.
Sure, a lot of games use cardinal directions to point players in the right direction.
They'll say, go north or go west,
or they have a compass on screen that allows you to figure out where you need to go.
But I don't think that that's the same thing.
For one, it forces you to look at the compass itself.
Look at a game such as Skyrim, if you ever want to reorient yourself,
if you don't happen to know the map like the back of your hand,
you have to glance up at the compass and figure out where you need to go.
This takes your eyes off of the map and in turn off of all of the amazing artwork
that all of the developers over at the studio spent years and years working on.
I've always thought of this as a real tragedy when it comes to open world game design
that a developer can spend all this time working on something,
only to have the player completely distracted from it by way of simple exploration,
something that should go hand in hand with it.
This is why I'm often a fan of completely mixing UI on screen.
I just don't think that it's worth it.
Especially when there's other alternatives such as having in game UI.
Look at a game such as Death Stranding.
Whenever you want to navigate to a given destination to complete a delivery,
you set the way point on your map.
Then, as you head out into the game world to reach your destination,
you find that all of the direction that you're given is interspersed with the terrain.
This means that the guidance you are given to get from one destination to another
doesn't pull you out of the game world or distract you from it,
but rather it pulls you in even more.
It makes you look at every hill crest, every ridge, every mountain top.
It's at that point that these open world games really shine.
And I honestly believe that's why Death Stranding even though its world is subjectively quite empty,
can still captivate players in such an intriguing way.
But if you want to hear all of my thoughts on that,
go check out my full length critique of Death Stranding.
It's over two hours' long, it's … it's a monster.
But if you're this far into this video, you're probably gained for it.
All of this to say, I think that the level design in the direction
that Naughty Dog gives the player in this particular sequence with Abbey
is phenomenal and I can't applauded enough.
Something as simple as having the player follow sunlight
is implemented so well, that I think it's absolutely astonishing.
Any studio could set up a scene where they demand that the player follow the sunlight.
But it's much harder to have that sunlight carry through in every scene, every area, every room
that the player enters, such that they know exactly where they need to go next.
And so it's with this guidance that Abby heads west to try to get to the aquarium,
where she thinks Owen is hiding out.
She wants to speak to Owen because she needs to figure out why exactly he shot Danny.
And whether or not there's two sides to the story.
Throughout this relatively calm sequence,
you're mostly collecting ammo and exploring buildings, grabbing some collectibles.
This really is the calm before the storm because after this
is when the game is really going to pick up and carry through to the final act.
And this descent into chaos begins when Abby's climbing through a crack in the wall.
And well, this happens.
I love these you-are-not-safe moments, I really do.
As we mentioned earlier, Ellie actually gets jumped while she's adjusting weapons,
and you're upgrading abilities at a workbench.
And now Abby while you're in what is presumed to be a covered, loading space,
and Abby even gets jumped.
I just, I think it's so cool, I … I know that maybe I'm in the minority with this,
but I really do think that it's cool to see.
这也让我回想起艾莉和乔尔之前的片段 两人在墙缝中缓缓前行时
This also reminded me of a flashback when Ellie and Joel were climbing through a crack in the wall,
原文有口误 是巨无霸不是循声者（Clicker）
巨无霸把墙里的艾莉一把拽出来
and the clicker punched through the wall, pulling Ellie out,
引发接下来的Boss战
and it starts in many boss fight.
Maybe it's a similarly between Abby and Ellie to make you think of them as relatable and similar.
But perhaps I'm reading too much into it.
At the end of the level you come upon a checkpoint from the initial quarantine.
There's a shrine set up here dedicated to the profit of the Seraphites cult.
There's also all of these notes surrounding the shrine that are asking her for various things,
and I think it makes the player realize
just how different the Seraphites are from the WLF and in turn Ellie.
Now we never get to see or meet the Prophetess, which I actually like,
similar to how we don't end up having a major boss fight or clash with Isaac,
something I think video games are definitely guilty of doing
whenever there's a notable character introduced.
If you see a bad guy introduced to the story at some point,
chances are you're going to have some sort of boss fight with him or her.
Otherwise they wouldn't have been introduced in the first place.
And maybe I'm alone, but I really appreciate that Naughty Dog bucked this trend
and made sure that these characters stood by themselves
and simply turn them into a trophy on your Playstation achievements list.
Now speaking of the Prophetess,
or as she's more commonly referred to in the game, just "the Prophet",
we don't actually get to find out a lot about her.
I did a lot of digging to try to figure out who this lady actually was,
and I say WAS because it's implied that she actually was killed before the events of this second game.
You see, it seems that soon after the outbreak and Seattle fell into absolute chaos,
this woman arose as the leader of a small cult.
She claimed that the infection was effectively a punishment on humanity
for their overreliance on technology.
因此 她自然而然地规定她的所有追随者从事长年累月艰苦的体力劳动
So naturally she prescribed all of her followers to years and years of hard manual labour,
躬耕于田 以符合自然本身的方式生产自己的食物
working in the fields to produce their own food in a way that was congruity with nature itself.
This obviously lead to a very strict lifestyle for all of the Seraphites,
but they were willing to do it because of her guidance.
However, she died, at some point, somehow.
As far as I could find, there's never a mention of exactly how she died.
If you came across something, please comment down below, I would love to know.
But in all of my digging in my multiple runthroughs of the game,
I couldn't find anything detailing specifically how she died.
What we do know is that soon after she died,
a bunch of other elders in the church of the Seraphites
took over and started ramping up the critical element of the cult, which was control.
Naturally, many of the new leaders started to fall into corrupt states.
They started to hog more food, they started to control different territories,
and before they knew it,
the Seraphites cult wasn't about living incongruity with nature,
but rather was much more about control and strict adherence to the guidance and dictum of the elders.
This is an interesting choice by Naughty Dogs riders.
Specifically because it makes it so that the Seraphites followers are much more relatable and sympathetic.
Whenever you feel as though
they're employing some very animalistic and barbarian tactic to achieve a certain ends,
such as gutting somebody to release them into the heavens for some reason,
you can always fall back and partially excuse it
because these are people simply following directions that they believe are coming from on high.
Most of the Seraphites aren't viciously evil and despicable people
trying to do despicable things because they enjoy it.
Rather, they're people simply trying to survive in a world that's really really messed up.
and it's no mystery that this is set up right around the time
when Abby is starting to feel sympathy towards members, or in this case, former members of the cult.
Again this game is all about perspectives.
And it's all about trying to get you to sympathise
with people that you didn't think you could possibly sympathize with before.
The point is, the Prophet is a very interesting character,
specifically considering the control that she seems to have over the Seraphites.
However, without many details on exactly when she died or how she died,
it's unclear at just how long she's been gone.
It would be one thing if she had been dead for just a few years,
and this is what starting to ramp up.
But it's an entirely another case for her to have been dead for ten or fifteen years,
leading to over a decade of power struggles, which eventually bred this new, morphed cult.
Regardless, I think the Seraphites are fairly interesting.
At the very least they are a little bit different and they offer a fresh perspective
on how a group of people might go about surviving in a world that's this messed up.
I especially like it because so often these types of narratives are completely drowned out
with cannibals and barbarians and looters and raiders,
and basically everybody that you encountered in the first game.
It's only in these more interesting and creative, in my opinion, stories
where you find something that's a little bit different.
Such as in Mad Max, the strange obsession and worship of gasoline and cars.
It's something that's just really cool, and different.
But I digress.
Abby pushes through this checkpoint and officially enters Scars' territory.
Here we'll fight a ton of Scars,
and believe me, you're going to be ploughing through them by the end of this sequence.
There's actually a great many boss fight here that I really enjoyed
with a woman that I can only assume is named Helga.
I don't actually know if her name is Helga by the way
I'm just saying that because she looks like Helga.
But regardless Abby bites off a part of her ear, which I thought was kind of funny.
But eventually a bunch of her friends come over.
They overpower Abby and knock her out,
which then leads straight into a flashback to four months before.
This would place this flashback right before the events of the prologue,
when Abby and her whole group left for Jackson.
It's Winter, Abby finds Owen in the aquarium with a bunch of pretty lights put up.
It's really relaxing,
and it really is this calming contrast that's the name of the game for the second half of TLOU2.
Something horrible will happen,
and then we'll see something pretty and relaxing,
and then something, even more horrible will happen.
and then we cut back to a nice winter scene, and so on.
In here there's actually many game where you can shoot some targets with a kitty bow and arrow.
It's pretty damn stupid, but it gives the players something to do that isn't just talking.
Otherwise this entire flashback would simply be Abby, talking to Owen,
walking up some stairs and then talking some more.
It's not to say that Naughty Dogs afraid of doing that in games or having a 10 minute cut scene,
but it seems to me that if they can avoid it, they will,
and they'll interspersed little mini game such as this to break up the monotony.
Now the point of the sequence, though, is to show that Abby found Tommy,
or, at the very least has a lead that he's living in Jackson.
And the point, of course, is that they hope that Tommy could help them find Joel.
Of course, we know that Joel was living there too,
But apparently, at this time Abby didn't know that.
至少我不清楚埃比在开场时是否仍认为他们只在寻找汤米
It's not clear to me at least
if Abby still thought they were looking only for Tommy in the opening sequence,
或者到那时她是否认为乔尔也可能在那里
or if by that time she thinks that Joel could be there too.
But I mean some of the dialogue seems to imply that she's looking for Joel primarily,
but that they only expected to find Tommy.
But again, I just don't think it matters too much.
The point is they're going to Jackson for Joel by way of Tommy,
and if Joel happens to be there, great.
But they mostly expect to find Tommy and hope to convince him to share Joel's location or whereabouts.
Regardless after breaking to Owen that she has a lead on Joel's brother
Abby also throws out the fact that Isaac approved the whole squad,
leaving for weeks on end to chase Joel down.
She exclaims that Isaac is more about justice than any one,
which is why he apparently approves of the plan for them to leave for weeks and weeks on end,
potentially months trying to hunt down a guy that did something terrible years and years ago.
To me, it seems like a stretch that he would be willing to let this many people go,
especially young whippersnappers, who were involved in the active patrolling
and maintenance of the WLF's defenses.
But regardless, maybe that's just me.
And may be it actually is within Isaacs character to let them go but it seems like a stretch to me.
After a brief debate back and forth, they settle on it.
They're going to Jackson, they're going to try to find Tommy,
and then they're going to try and find Joel, once and for all, and finish it.
Now we cut back to the forest.
This is actually the trailer sequence that we saw back when we first met Abby years ago.
I remember when I first saw this scene in the trailer,
I thought that Abby was going to turn out to be Ellie's mom in this flashback,
But … well …
I was wrong.
Like … really wrong.
The Scars start to string up Abbey for execution
when they're interrupted by a young girl that they've just captured.
Now we don't know what this means, but for simplicity's sake,
this girl Yara and the other apostate, whoever they may be,
did something to piss off the Scars.
After Yara spits in this elder Scars face, she is sentenced to having her wings clipped,
and I have to say,
this is probably the least clippy way they could have possibly clipped her wings.
The other apostate shows up who will eventually find out his name Lev.
Lev starts shooting arrows at the Seraphites,
killing a couple of them.
And after a brief tussle with the elder, she's also killed.
Following Yara's direction, left cuts Abby down, just in time for her to not die.
I mean seriously, she was really close.
They just kind of left her hanging here after she killed the elder little … little ridiculous,
but you know whatever she was just hang in there, and … and that's that.
After Abby's cut down, they all prep to fight some zombies,
just in case that you forgot that this game actually has zombies in it,
because at this point it's been a hot minute since they were featured.
And a fun little fact, and something to notice is that
this rash and brews over Abby's neck will actually remain for the rest of the main story.
It's a great detail, and it really helps with immersion,
especially as later scenes come and go,
you'll see Abby rubbing her neck because it still hurts,
because after all she was just hung from it.
It's this attention to detail that Naughty Dog is really known for
and that you have to compliment them on.
These scenes are filmed months apart from each other
in some cases, years apart after rewrites and reshoots,
and then changing the game and level design around them,
they have to reshoot it because the level design change.
This amount of detail that's thrown in shows just how much they care.
They made notes of absolutely everything that was going on with the character
so that months after the fact, they would be able to reference back and say,
"Oh, Abby's neck was sore here because she was hung from it,"
just a few hours of gameplay before this in the game's timeline.
So make sure that that's reflected in your performance.
That level of detail is something thats really rare you mostly only see it in Hollywood,
and even then you don't see it on very many productions.
But anyway, you escape the infected and come upon your old friend, Helga,
attacking Lev who was leaving the pack.
You have a quick fist fight where you eventually finish her with a hammer to …
well, the face.
And Abby gets her stuff back
because Helga just happened to be wearing Abby's backpack after capturing her earlier.
I actually thought this was kind of a fun touch,
since the normal way that you would find all of your gear after being kidnapped like this in a video game
would be to just find it in a chest or sitting on a desk somewhere.
Now there's some dialogue here about the Seraphites and the WLF
And it's strange for them to trust each other.
But at this point they've both saved each other's lives,
which is why it's a little more understandable.
Abby just saved Lev's life from Helga and Lev just saved Abbey from hanging.
There is a clear tit for tat here, Which is why I think this blood pact is formed.
Now Abby eventually asks Lev the obvious question
And Lev is being honest here,
but it's far more complicated than it seems.
But don't worry, we're going to get to that later.
Your new little crew fights through waves of infected and slowly begin trusting each other more and more.
The sequence actually climaxes with Abby carrying Yara while Lev keeps watch.
You all push into a small office trailer and set up camp for the night.
Feeling bad for them, Abby helps Yara set her arm,
which is clearly in some serious trouble.
After helping them with this Abby leaves.
Just as baffled as they are that she just helped a Seraphite.
In yet another reflection between characters,
Abby has found herself in the same position that Owen found himself in.
She seemingly helped a Scar,
which is something that the WLF is never supposed to do.
This is going to completely change the following scene,
but we'll get to that in just a second.
As Abby leaves Yara and Lev, her perplexion is palpable.
She cares for these two kids, and she doesn't even really know why.
It's the same emotion that the player is likely feeling towards Abby herself,
which is why it's so brilliant that it was done this way.
Abby is feeling the same confusion and inner conflict as the player.
But in this case she's baffled that she's been made to feel sympathy
for members of a group that she's supposed to hate,
whereas we, the player likely feel that conflict because we want to hate Abbey for killing Joel.
And maybe a part of us still does,
but at the very least we're beginning to sympathize with her and even care for her.
It's masterfully done.
And it's this subtle character work that makes this game what it is.
And why, in my opinion, you have to play it all the way through, even despite the pacing issues.
Now, eventually, Abby fights her way through a ton of infected in a shipping yard
and finds her way to a series of boats and ships.
You fight your way through another group of infected and stumble across a crossbow,
which is actually my favorite weapon in the entire game.
After you push through all of these infected you get to the aquarium where Owen is staying,
However, you can't find Owen anywhere.
Abby starts to kind of freak out, worrying that he's dead or just abandoned and went AWOL.
But eventually Abby stumbles on to him.
He's sitting in the boat that he's been trying to fix up fridges.
and it seems as though it's his one safe space left in the world.
Abby and Owen start talking,
and you know, I can't really explain this part in a good way,
so I'm just going to let it play … so …
So yeah, sexy times,
I personally didn't see that coming at all,
and I'll be honest I'm not entirely sure what to make of it.
It kind of comes out of left field because they were fighting and then they start … start banging,
I don't … good for them, I mean, I guess it makes sense.
There's a lot of tension and visceral emotion going on,
but it seemed to come out of nowhere to me.
Out enough, there's some deeper literary reason for this. I would love to hear it.
I'm not sure I've thought about it, but I don't really know what to make of it.
So … moving on.
Seattle Day 1 wraps up with Abby having a bizarre nightmare about Yara and Lev being killed and strung up
in the very same hospital room where her father died,
which to me seems to imply that she feels some sort of familial attachment to them.
Since in her dream they die in the same place that her father died.
I really don't think you can understate the significance of her seeing them in this space.
If she was stressing out purely about them being killed,
Why wouldn't she just have a nightmare where she imagines coming across their bodies
as she was heading back to the WLF base.
The fact that she has the stream and it set in the hospital is significant,
and I think it shows that she has a much deeper bond with these kids than even she realizes.
So after the stream she decides that she needs to go and make sure that they're okay.
Yeah, she's actually going to go and help Scars.
She's just as baffled as any other WLF member would be,
and it seems that she's coming to the realization that Owen also came to.
She's done with all of it.
Seattle Day 2.
So after Abby wakes up she rushes back to the shipping yard
to try and find Yara and Lev.
She encounters a ton of Scars, including several Brutes,
which leads to a fairly interesting combat encounter.
After clearing them out, Abby heads back into the office trailer,
and she finds Yara in really bad shape.
她的胳膊肿的像猴屁股一样
Her arm looks like a cherry laffey taffy,
and it's clear that it's going to need some … let's just say "severe treatment".
So she picks Yara up and she brings her to the aquarium with Lev trailing close behind.
Her plan is basically to have a Mel treat Yara's arm in whatever capacity that may take.
Needless to say, this is a pretty big gamble.
Because of Abby has found out and ratted out to Isaac and the other WLF members,
she's likely going to end up either completely ostracized from the group,
or downright executed for helping out their prime enemy.
Sure, you could say that they are former members of the group now
and that they should be helped because they are apostate from the group.
But it doesn't really matter.
In this type of situation, the enemy of the enemy is your friend.
In this case, the enemy of the enemy is not actually your friend.
It's just somebody that you should ostracize and kill
because complicated moral and ethical quandaries aren't worth the trouble.
in a post apocalyptic world.
Regardless after taking a look and not initially freaking out,
Mel determines that the bone is completely shattered and that the arm has to come off
if she has any chance of surviving.
Mel then explains what she needs for this operation.
She could just take a knife and hack at it and try to cauterize the wound with fire,
as Owen points out.
But this would likely lead to infection very quickly.
If they're going to do this, they might as well do it right.
So Mel requests to saw and some other surgical equipment.
Abby, says that she could get it from the hospital.
Problem being that the hospital, according to the WLF routes that are in place right now,
is gonna take roughly a day to reach and then a day to return from, far too long for Yara.
It's at this point that Lev offers help
by giving access to the bridge system that the Scars used
to navigate the city from the rooftops.
It's not clear exactly what this is going to be or what form it's going to take.
It also, it's a little strange to me that the WLF member, such as Owen and Abby,
don't seem to be aware of this bridge system whatsoever.
They are aware that the Scars are able to navigate the city very quickly
so quickly that it seems almost supernatural
but apparently never occurred to them that
they might be using bridge systems above the city by using the rooftops.
The point is that Lev offers to give them access to this bridge system.
Lev knows these routes very well and says that
they should be able to reach the hospital in around 2 hours if they were to follow the route.
And so without much hesitation, Abby agrees and leaves.
As they're leaving the aquarium, Owen stops Abby and tries to talk,
but she is not interested in addressing what happened a night before with the sexy time.
And it seems that she's found her new family and obsession.
This is the first time that we've really seen her move past Owen
and behave in a way that doesn't seem completely obsessive towards him.
It's kind of refreshing to be honest.
Prior to this, it's very clear that Abby still has feelings for Owen.
And even in the first chapter when we originally met Abby and Owen
when their overlooking snow-crested Jackson,
We saw that Abby and Owen shared a strange tension.
Have you know one could never really get on the same page after her father died.
And quite obviously, since Joel's death, nothing has changed.
This is lead Owen sticking with Mel, even though they're pretty clearly not compatible
and even don't seem to particularly like each other.
I'm not entirely sure if this was intentional or not,
but the fact that there's zero chemistry between Owen and Mel seems pretty obvious to me.
And if the writers are even somewhat competent, as I believe they are over at Naughty Dog,
surely somebody noticed this.
So either it was masterful performance on the part of the actors and the writers to make sure that
these characters didn't seem to have that much in common didn't seem to get along particularly well,
and that they had an immense amount of tension brewing between them.
Either that was completely intentional or it was an accident,
and it was the result of a misfire and the writing.
I think it's the former personally.
I think that Mel and Owen are supposed to come off as a little strange.
Everyone else in the group seems to be aware that their relationship is a little bizarre
and that Owen and Abby seem to have feelings for each other
and they're confused as to why they are not just together.
But that tension will eventually be resolved, just … just wait.
After leaving the aquarium, Abby and Lev head to the tower
that they need to climb all the way to the top of
in order to gain access to the aforementioned "Bridge".
It's pretty damn high up there, and it happens to be covered by clouds and fog.
This is a nice and coincidentally thing because it adds to the tension of the situation.
But it doesn't answer the question as to how the WLF weren't aware of this bridge system.
Because chances are, it's not always cloudy and foggy
to the point where you can't see to the top of these skyscrapers.
Surely somebody saw these bridges when the sky was clear.
It seems bizarre to me that the WLF didn't feel the need to explore these bridge systems
that seemed to go perfectly between skyscrapers and buildings very high up,
especially when they would have been visible from the ground.
But I guess that's just me.
Now. as Abby and Lev are heading to the top of this tower,
they climbed through multiple buildings, explore some different areas,
and they share in a few interesting conversations.
Now there's nothing really crazy here, it's mostly awkward small talk,
but it mostly serves to show that they are growing more comfortable with each other.
My personal favorite moment is when they come across somebody's apartment,
who was clearly very into gaming.
In fact, they even still have their D&D game set up
and they have their Playstation gear scattered throughout the apartment.
It's kind of cool.
And personally, I would like to think that this whole apartment is modeled
after one of the developers apartments.
I've heard stories of developers from Bethesda and Rocksteady doing this type of thing
where they take an environment model it after their own personal environment
because after all, that's what they know.
It's a little piece of the real world in this imaginary world,
and I just think that it's super cool.
And I thought that this particular building was especially detailed.
The two travel through a plethora of buildings,
they push through some rapids,
and they eventually land on a construction site that's next to the target building.
Now it just so happens that in this construction site
is one of the most interesting combat arenas of the entire game.
There's a ton of verticality here and there's a lot of Seraphites scattered throughout.
Some of them are Brutes, some of them have short range weapons,
and some of them have long range weapons.
It's really interesting how they laid all of this out and on harder difficulties.
Let me just tell you it kicked my ass a few times.
But it's important to say that it felt fair.
It wasn't as though I was getting my ass handed to me, and I felt like I was being slighted
like a poorly designed boss that's able to clip through walls or something.
This level feels completely fair.
It just seems like a difficult situation where Lev and Abby have to work perfectly in tandem.
And when that happens, things work out.
But after clearing this area,
the two get into an industrial elevator that they can take all the way to the top to reach the bridge.
Now, if you remember from earlier Abby's worst nightmare is heights.
Here, Lev actually shares a bit of sweet advice to try and take out his mind off of the terror
that she feels due to the enormous and ever increasing heights.
Now, at the top of the skyscraper, they begin crossing the bridge,
which is actually just a partially collapsed crane.
This again reaffirms the point that the WLF probably should have seen this crane on a clear day
and been intrigued enough to go and investigate it.
Maybe even claiming it for themselves.
Maybe there's a line or something that mentions why the WLF haven't used this bridge,
and I just missed it or I couldn't think of it or remember it when writing the script.
But either way, if there is something, let me know.
Now, understandably, Abby starts crossing the bridge and begins to completely freak out.
To be honest, any normal person would probably be freaking out at this point.
I don't think it's just people who are afraid of heights.
But the fact that Abby is completely and utterly petrified by heights,
I think just proves the point that this is not a good time for her.
And it's actually while crossing this makeshift bridge,
that Lev throws out one of the funniest lines of the entire game,
at least as far as I'm concerned, because it comes out of absolutely nowhere.
Hah … I love it!
Now after crossing the first bridge,
it seems as though they've finished and gotten through the hardest part.
But … NO.
Now this is one of the few times I really remember
being completely blown away by a set piece in this game.
The bridge is beautiful and yet creepy at the same time.
and the hospital in the distance is also all inspiring,
and serves its purpose very well in informing the player of where they are within Seattle.
I will say, though it was a little disappointing
because there was some artifacting in Z fighting on the textures when I first played,
but I can get over it.
It's pretty rare to see a graphical glitch like this in a Naughty Dog games
so I'm letting it slide.
但事实就是如此 埃比跨越了这座桥
But just like that, Abby crosses the bridge.
她在勒弗的帮助下战胜了恐惧
She's conquered her fears with the Lev's help.
她完成了自己以为不可能完成的任务
She's achieved that which she thought was unachievable
成功跨越了这座巨大的……
that she could cross this grand expanse …
我勒个去她摔下来了！
… Oh, my God! She fell!
So, yeah, she … she falls.
Good thing there is a penthouse pool right?
Now the new dynamic duo decides
to work their way to the bottom of the tower now that they've crossed
Once at the base, they are going to be able to head straight for the hospital.
Throughout the descent, there's a few hordes that you fight through of infected.
Abby also finds a flame thrower, which is probably the best hoard weapon in the entire game.
Because it has such a widespread.
It makes it really easy to handle crowds and large numbers of infected.
But I will say that ammo is so limited.
It makes it really hard to use it in any sort of consistent way.
I'll also say that this tower actually excited me.
I thought there would be some really cool opportunities for
different combat sequences with a lot of verticality.
And maybe some platforming with the rope mechanic … some thing,
but really there's not much here.
You just kind of make your way to the bottom of the tower, and that's it.
After fighting through a few rooms of infected, seems like a missed opportunity.
But regardless, they get to the bottom, and they come out right by the hospital.
And this is actually the same exact area that Ellie entered the hospital earlier
or in continuity I guess after this.
Then this is probably a good time to bring up the fact that there are a lot of reused areas in the game.
This has been something that a lot of people have criticized.
That Naughty Dog seems to just be recycling the same maps and levels with different characters,
or in this case just between Abby and Ellie.
But I don't think it's actually fair to criticise them purely because they reuse levels.
A level in a video game at least seems to be, in my estimation,
a collection of different items, a lay out of a map,
and in general, a pool of possibilities.
Different things that the player can do to interact with that level to achieve a set goal.
A really simple level would just be a room with a door.
You walked to the door, open it and leave, you've completed the level.
However, a complicated level would be one in which you have a complicated goal,
such as making it out of this area alive.
And then the developer complicates the achieving of that goal
by introducing many different enemies that you could fight complicated traversal,
or maybe even a puzzle that you have to solve in order to get through the door.
This is how you take a level from something as simple as walking through a door
into something more complicated and engaging for the player.
For this reason,
I don't think it's completely fair to say that Naughty Dog is purely reusing levels here.
Because Abby and Ellie interact with these levels in completely different ways.
When Abby's walking through the hospital here and eventually finds Nora,
she's not actually fighting these people.
She's not shooting them,
she's not throwing bombs and molotovs on them.
She's just walking and talking,
not to mention that you also go to areas of the hospital that were unseen by Ellie.
And when you compare this to Ellie traverse this level,
well, it's pretty different.
Now if your point is that they are clearly taking short cuts in terms of development
by putting these characters in the same levels and structuring the story in that way,
I think you can make that point, and perhaps that's fair.
I don't see the inherent problem with reusing a level if it makes sense in the story
or if you write the story in a way where that makes sense
because a quality game can be set in something as small as a couple of hallways.
Look at something like PT, which was technically just a playable teaser,
but even that was considered to be wildly successful,
and it only really took place in two hallways, a back room and a bathroom I suppose.
That's really all there was to it, and yet it was phenomenal.
You can knit pick something as simple as
how many times a particular mesh is used throughout a game,
or you can argue your point based on how the game uses that asset.
I think the latter is much more reasonable and much more defensible.
But I digress.
Abby heads into the hospital alone, leaving Lev behind because quite obviously,
if Lev were seen anywhere near the hospital, we wouldn't survive for very long.
Abby plays it cool with all of the WLF members.
But it's only a matter of time before everybody finds out that Abby's disobeyed Isaac's orders.
I think Abby knows this, which is why she's moving through the level pretty quickly,
trying to find the materials that she needs and leave.
I mean not to mention also that the girl that she's getting the materials for
is on death's door that probably motivates her,
her rushing a little bit, but by who am I to say.
You walk through here, talking a few people and … oh look!
It's the Vita girl that Ellie stabbed and crap out of earlier, or I guess later,
because he or she is still alive, that's … that's funny.
Now Abby doesn't make it far into the hospital though.
She's arrested once they check in with Isaac
and find out that she has actually been AWOL since the day before,
so she's locked up in the elevator.
She's basically gonna held until they transport everything back to the front base with Isaac,
where she'll be dealt with.
Again this is something that was mentioned several times,
not just to Abby, but also that Ellie overheard there is something going on with WLF
where they need all of their supplies at the front base.
And they're also collecting all of the WLF members to that same front base.
感觉要发生什么事了 伊萨克在动员所有人
There's something happening, Isaac's mobilizing everybody.
大的要来了
Something's about to go down.
Isaac mentioned earlier that he's planning on doing one final push into the Seraphites' island
that they have to finish the war once and for all.
It's a pretty big deal because without a doubt,
many hundreds or even thousands of people are about to die.
I could have seen an alternative timeline or storyline
where Abby instead of going after just materials to save Yara
decides to go and try and stop this invasion to save all of the lives of the Seraphites
and the lives of the WLF that will be wasted in this endeavor.
But I understand that this is probably a little more relatable,
especially because when you can emotionally attached the player to one character,
in this case, Yara, and in another instance Lev.
You can do a lot more compared to if you are trying to make the player
feel emotionally engaged and attached to an organization
such as the WLF, or a cult, such as the Seraphites.
Now, while Abby's locked up in the elevator, Nora I just happened to come by.
And she comes in clutch, and let's Abby go.
This is actually why she was in trouble with the WLF members
back in Ellie section when she was climbing through the vent.
It's because they think that Nora let Abby go, because well, she did.
Again I think it's really cool to get a fresh understanding of
everything that was going on with this new perspective.
Yeah, you don't need to know everything
that was going on to have an enjoyable game, play experience or narrative experience.
There's plenty of examples of books that don't really explain much of anything of what's going on.
They just cannot leave it there and leave it for your personal interpretation.
In TLOU2, however, everything's been thought through,
at least to a certain extent such that you're able to go back through with this new perspective,
learn more and figure out why these characters were doing what they were doing.
They weren't just moving materials from one location to the other to be convenient for the game story.
But rather there is an overarching theme and idea behind it,
even though that invasion has nothing to do with Ellie
and really would never have been brought up if Ellie stories where the game ended.
Now, Nora leads Abby to the basement to let her collect the stuff that she needs for Yara's arm.
She doesn't know exactly who she's helping out or why she needs everything that she needs.
But what she does know is that these surgical materials
are probably going to be used for the betterment of somebody's life.
And she knows also that all of the other materials in the rest of the hospital have been picked clean
and are being brought to the forward base where Isaac wants them.
And so the only place that's left for Abby to collect these items would be the basement.
Problem being, when the outbreak initially happened in 2013, on outbreak day,
everybody was brought to the hospital.
With this obviously, there was a massive outbreak within the hospital itself
and eventually everything was quarantined off.
The doors were locked and the stairs destroyed such that the infected couldn't reach the upper levels
and would be trapped in the basement indefinitely.
如果你玩过初代的TLOU
Now, if you played the original TLOU,
你就知道感染者不是葡萄酒越陈越香
you know that zombies don't tend to age like a fine wine.
实际上在TLOU的世界里感染越久的感染者就越可怕
The more serious and severe zombies in the world of TLOU come with age.
也就是说你接下来即将在地下室看到的感染者
This means that all of the zombies and infected that you're going to see in the basement
很可能已经被关在那里25年了
have likely been there for a quarter century.
里面很可能隐藏着整个这座城市最最危险的感染者
That makes them some of the most dangerous and severe infected in this entire city.
其他人我不清楚 但在我想通这一点的一瞬间
Now I don't know about you guys, but the second that I figured this out,
我就知道我们可能即将面对全新的感染者 或者至少是新boss
I knew that we are probably going to end up finding
a new type of infected or at the very least a new boss.
And I was damn ready for that.
The infected in TLOU2 seemed to be a bit of an afterthought.
There's not a whole lot of focus on them, and I get it, there's a lot more going on.
But I kind of miss how central the zombies were in the original game.
So the idea of having a brand new type of infected introduce that we have to go up against
was pretty interesting and I was damn ready for it.
And so Nora leads Abby to the basement
to let her collect everything that she's going to need for Yara's arm.
and it's at this point that she leaves Abby to it.
And of course, as we know, she heads back upstairs to be confronted by Ellie.
Now it's at this point that Abby enters with Naughty Dog labeled this level as which is Ground Zero.
She heads into the basement where all of these, in fact,
that have just been sitting since the initial outbreak.
And even Abby knows that there's probably going to be something pretty serious in here.
And it's only verified and reaffirmed
by the fact that she starts seeing and hearing strange things almost immediately.
Now Abby pushes on and explores the area, trying to find the stuff that she needs,
and eventually she reconnects the power and pushes through some locked doors,
only to find …
Yeah, the door has been ripped open.
There's something really big here, and Abby knows it.
However, there is nowhere else to go.
So Abby pushes through the tunnel and eventually finds the tools that she needs in an ambulance.
But of course, because timing is perfect in every horror situation,
this guy comes along.
Yeah, this horrific monstrosity comes out and poses the next boss fight to the player.
It's a coagulation of multiple infected and clickers,
and it's pretty disgusting looking,
and I actually think that it's pretty impressive all things considered.
Something I did not see coming to be honest.
However, I'm sorry to report that this disgusting creature
is not actually that difficult all things considered.
He moved so slowly that he can't be considered a major difficulty
unless you're on, for instance, Grounded.
He moves so slowly that I wouldn't even really consider him much of a threat.
He is a bullet sponge to be completely honest,
but if you have enough ammo, you're just going to run around the building,
eventually hurling things item,
especially since they have dynamically generated crafting materials scattered throughout this floor.
This means that you can always collect items, run to a corner, craft,
run to another corner, equip it,
and then throw pipe bombs and molotovs item if you need to.
And I think more broadly,
difficulty in this game tends to come from the quantity of enemies.
And ah …  Motherfu …
Yeah, it's real nasty.
So you onload absolutely everything that you have into these two until they are eventually killed.
And so Abby heads back up to the surface with all of the gear that she came for,
she reconnects with Lev, and they head back to the aquarium.
It's with these new-found tools that Mel is able to successfully amputate Yara's arm,
and she does survive it.
It seems as though Abby's new family is going to be okay after all.
Except totally not! That's not how anything in this game works.
You should have known that by now.
But of course, to finish out Seattle Day 2 there's another flashback slashed dream
where Abby is in the hospital where her father died
heads into the room where her father was found dead,
except this time she sees him alive, and smiling,
which to me actually represent something very significant.
Something that I do not think you can understate.
Seriously I think this one little flashback slash, flash sideways, slashed dream.
I think this is probably the most important moment of Abby's entire character.
If you listen to anything in Abby sections, it's this, allow me to make my point.
This moment to me seems to represent Abby,
having finally made atonement for her sins and the death of Joel,
while at the same time coming to complete peace with her father's death.
I mean, at the very least, she doesn't seem to be struggling with sleep any more,
because she's not having nightmares.
She's actually having a good dream where she reconnects with her father.
That's not a good dream, I don't know what is.
Furthermore, the last time we saw Abby, rushing into the room, where her father was found dead,
she witnessed Yara and Lev strung up and disemboweled.
As we established back when that scene took place,
it seemed as though that was implying that
Yara and Lev were starting to have a significant impact on her psyche.
And that's the tone down version.
I would argue that they seem to be starting to take a place in her mind and life
that was previously occupied by her father.
It's a familial place that only is reserved for those that you truly care about.
And whether it makes sense, whether it's justified or not,
Abby does feel that intense connection to Yara and Lev.
Maybe it's just because they saved her life when they didn't need to.
Or maybe it's because there is something more going on,
an actual interest and appreciation of each other.
But regardless it's there.
Abby, seeing her father in this setting, looking at her with a caring face,
a face that says everything's going to be okay,
I think is incredibly significant.
She just saved Yara,
and in turn, seems to have saved Lev at the same time,
everything seems to have worked out.
And as far as they know, the next day they're going to be able to load up in Owen's boat
and head off to Santa Barbara.
It really does seem as though we're going to have a happy ending.
And with that, Seattle Day 2, ends.
SEATTLE Day 3, Abby wakes up to drama brewing.
She slept well, but Mel is pissed.
And basically she just wants Abby to leave her Owen and the new kids alone.
She says that if Abby sticks along for any longer than she's going to screw everything up.
So she might as well leave them to go to Santa Barbara by themselves and remain here with the WLF.
I mean the drama kind of makes sense, considering that Abby just slept with Mel's baby daddy.
And I don't know if she knows this, or if she know and talked about it.
But either way, it upsets Abby pretty significantly, and Abby actually starts to cry,
one of the first times we see a crack in this facade that she puts forward,
and I think this hits hard for Abby,
because she probably knows that it's true, at least to some extent.
I mean she is kind of toxic,
she literally dragged a group of her closest friends halfway across the country,
just to murder a dude.
Meanwhile, Yara is dealing with Lev, who's come to the naive conclusion
that he can convince their mother to join them in abandoning the cult.
Yara, of course, realizes that this is a naive and stupid estimation
of what they could do with their mother.
But nonetheless Lev is convinced that there is a way.
So Abby and Yara look for a gift that they can give to Lev, to make him feel better and stay.
Now it's during this chapter that the elephant in the room comes out,
and it's something that I'm sure many of us saw coming,
especially if you've been listening to the passive dialogue for the last few hours of gameplay.
You see, Lev is trans.
In some of the previous combat sequences when you're moving with Lev through,
for instance, the construction site in fighting a lot of Seraphites,
there's times when the Seraphites will actually call out to Lev, referring to him as Lily.
Now if you've been kind of mentally checked out for the majority of the game,
this might come as a total shock, or it might just be confusing
as to why they're referring to this character as Lily and not Lev.
But it's for that very reason that Yara and Lev left the group.
Lev was to be married off to one of the elders.
Naturally, Lev did not agree with this or like the idea,
and so started acting out eventually, cutting his hair,
and fully transitioning, wanting to be referred to entreated as a male Seraphite,
going out on patrols being trained and used as a soldier.
And in what comes as absolutely no surprise to anybody,
the Seraphites weren't exactly the most supportive of this transition.
So they decided that they were going to severely punish Lev,
or at the very least, we're not going to allow this alternative lifestyle, shall we say.
And so Yara being a supportive and strong sister decided to come out with Lev and help them escape.
This is, of course, why they're constantly referred to as apostate by the Seraphites,
and why so many of the Seraphites in combat sequences
will call out and ask Yara and Lev why they're doing what they're doing.
Because as far as they knew up until very recently, they were just fine.
Now there's been a lot of hubbub about this plot point.
There has been a lot of debate,
both left and right of centre as to whether or not this was handled well.
And to be honest,
I'm not really qualified to come to a determination on that point.
But to me it seemed to be handled relatively well,
though in this particular scene in the aquarium
when Yara and Abby are talking about it.
It does seem a little heavy handed.
When I first figured it out for sure was a few hours before this,
when Lev and Abby were exploring the tower together and Lev actually asks Abby,
whether or not she heard what the other Seraphites were calling him.
This, of course, was referencing the fact
that the Seraphites constantly referred to Lev as Lily, or as the apostate.
Abby said she was aware of this, but that she didn't need to talk about it.
我认为这是一种相当谨慎的处理方式
That I thought was a pretty discreet way of handling something
勒弗可能并不太愿意谈论这个问题
that Lev probably isn't too excited to talk about,
而且坦率地讲 这对他们的最终目标并不那么重要
and that frankly, isn't that important to what their end goal is.
And this is one of the things that I've liked about Naughty Dog's work in the past
when they have more diverse cast members or characters within their stories,
it's usually not the defining point of that character.
If there's a gay character in the original TLOU,
it's there for you to see and you can put it together if you're paying any attention whatsoever.
But it's not the defining point of that character.
When somebody is purely defined by one trait of themselves,
whether that something like sexual identity or their religion or their appearance,
it's always a bad thing because people are far more complicated than that,
and you shouldn't boil yourself down to just one trait.
You're far more interesting than that.
This is why generally, I feel that Naughty Dog's approach to these types of things is good
because they don't make it the defining characteristic.
However, in this most recent gained TLOU2 and in their previous title, Uncharted: The Lost Legacy,
they fall prey much more to these heavy handed traits
where they make a character define themselves purely by an external trait.
And while I have no problem with whatever that trait may be by itself,
I think that defining a character that you are crafting
and putting it into a story by just that one trait is lazy writing.
And I think it does a disservice to the people who actually share that trait in reality.
But nonetheless, I think it's handled relatively well, if not a little heavy handed.
But it doesn't seem to be that crucial of a reveal,
and as far as I can tell, most people don't particularly care.
I also can't help recognized
that Naughty Dog saved this reveal quote-unquote for much later in the game.
Chances are, if you've made it this far, you're going to be much more understanding
whereas if they put this reveal much earlier on in the game,
it would be troll fodder without a doubt.
Maybe that's smart, maybe it's cowardly,
maybe it's just a coincidence that its revealed later in the game.
I'm not sure, either way, I don't particularly care,
and I don't think it matters.
Well, after they find a nice gift for Lev,
they eventually push out to the edge of the aquarium and realized that Lev's taken a boat
and is headed straight for the island that the Scars are based out of.
Lev's going to try to save his mom,
But it really is …  it's just stupid to do this.
This was one moment where I was a little confused,
just because Lev doesn't seem like a naive or stupid person.
Yeah, Lev's young, but that isn't necessarily directly correlative.
If you can be young and wise beyond your years.
Look at Ellie, for instance, in the first game she was young,
but she was not naive whatsoever.
I do not think that Ellie would have made this same rash decision.
At the very least, you would have taken some time to plan out some way
of dealing with this potential problem of leaving her mother forever potentially.
However, because Naughty Dog needs a reason to show the player that Seraphites' island
and this huge raid that the WLF are going to be carrying out on the island.
They just put this together and say, Well, we'll have Lev race to the island.
And then you follow Lev and you'll get to see all of this crazy stuff.
I think that this one is again a little bit of a coincidence and
seems to reek a little bit of the writer's trying to force characters into a situation
that hasn't naturally percolated through the circumstances of what's going on.
And that's why this timing here is so important.
It's because Abby's group is going to try to leave Seattle before the storm picks up.
That storm is going to be used as cover for Isaac's final push on to the Seraphites' Island,
and Isaac is not going to be delaying this push whatsoever at all.
He's done with fighting as he told us earlier in the game.
That's why all of this gear has been moved to the front base.
It's because they're going to have one last, wipe-out fight
to finish the Scars for good and be done with them.
And at the same time, Abby can use this storm as cover to make her escape to Santa Barbara.
However, this is much more of a lesser point.
Because realistically, Abby and Owen, Mel, Yara and Lev
don't really need that much cover to escape.
If they have a boat, they can just leave.
The WLF as far as I've seen in this game, don't actively patrolled the water.
They do have boats that they use, which is after all,
where Abby and Yara are going to grab a boat here in just a minute,
but they don't seem to patrol it actively.
I don't know, if they do patrol it actively,
and that's why all of these people need the storm to cover their tracks.
That would be interesting, but I'm not aware of any time when that's directly referenced.
If you know, please let me know in the comments section below.
And so Abby Signora naturally decide that they need to go and get Lev,
because if Lev steps foot on the island,
chances are he will be killed within the first twenty seconds
of being witnessed by any of the other Seraphites.
And so Abby in Yara start to push for the marina.
They eventually hear some sniper shots and Yara determines that she needs to stay behind.
She, after all, only has one arm at this time,
so it's a little harder for her to navigate these complex passageways
of latter stares and rafters that she has to jump across.
You eventually cross into a wide open inner state
and are instantly tackled right as you pop out by … who else but Manny.
This is where the sniper is.
He's got to pin down and has apparently killed all of Manny's guys.
And so Abby and Manny worked together to push up and take out this sniper.
It's actually pretty crazy sequence, it's very detailed too.
I mean just look at how the snipers shooting an abbey here as she advances through this ditch,
even shoots the body that's laying right on it and part of the body's head blows off,
which made all of this way more intense for me.
I don't know if this happens every time for everybody,
or if it was just a coincidental thing that the bullet happened to land right here.
But either way,
this spooked me and made me feel as though I was right in the thick of it.
Now quick sidebar, remember why Jesse and Ellie separated just a few hours ago
was because they heard that there was a sniper at the marina,
and they assumed that this sniper had to be Tommy.
So Jesse and Ellie separated.
So Jesse could go and find Tommie and Ellie could leave and go to the aquarium.
Also remember the previous sniping section that we had with Ellie in the flashback.
Remember, I said that that wasn't just a one off sniping tutorial,
even though it wasn't really going to be used at any other point in the game?
Well, it was for this very reason.
They needed to establish that Tommy has sniping experience and is good at what he does.
And sure enough, who do you think this sniper is?
Whether or not the player realizes this in this particular moment,
I don't think is too important because either way you the way you push up.
But I think it's actually probably a cooler moment,
if you don't realize it's Tommy handling the sniper rifle.
When you're thinking of it purely as an NPC sniping at you,
you have a much easier time just plowing through chasing him,
shooting at him, trying to kill him.
But once you realize it's a character that you also know and kind of love,
but is actively threatening the life of another character that you're starting to enjoy and care about,
it's that interesting conflict that makes TLOU2 such a strange and bizarre story.
Abby and Manny push up and eventually get the sniper cornered.
However, right as they reached the point,
when they feel as though they've got him, this happens …
Just like that, Manny is dead.
And now Abby is mad.
This is in my mind, just like the sudden death of Jesse.
It comes out of nowhere and is a total shock.
Again, similes all over the place.
Ellie lost a close friend out of nowhere very suddenly,
and the player has to also deal with it suddenly and shockingly.
And now Abby is losing a close friend of hers and is forced to deal with it in the same way.
So you start around a little bit.
And Abby pushes through the door.
If you just look on her face, you know, Abby knows who this was.
She knows that Tommy is here and that that is very bad.
This is especially bad because Manny just said a few moments ago
when you were in the interstate,
that there's more than one trespassers in town, killing WLF members.
This means that even if she killed Tommy just now, which is a stretch,
there's a lot more people that are in town, killing WLF members.
And if Tommy's here, chances are it's other people from Jackson
coming to get revenge for what she did to Joel.
Regardless, Abby doesn't really have the time to freak out about this.
She puts it out of her mind and heads to the island in a boat which they take from the pier,
the same boat and peer that the WLF members use, apparently, occasionally.
Her goal is simple, she needs to find Lev and get out.
If she can do that quickly, shall avoid Ellie and her entire revenge crew completely.
Abby and Yara reach the Scars' island.
Yara takes the lead, and brings Abby into the heart of one of their major camps.
And the most interesting thing about this actually is that Yara and Lev still buy into the cult,
even though they've rejected the leadership.
When you're lost in the darkness.
And to be honest, I don't really know what to make of this.
I've heard stories of people that were involved in cults that get out and still partially believe it,
even though they feel as though it was corrupted somewhat.
They feel as though they're still truth to it.
I am not totally sure, but I thought it was interesting
because after all, these kids were raised in this cult from the time that they were born.
So it makes sense that just because they decided to leave under threat of death,
they still have some adoration, or at least respect for the cult leaders.
But nonetheless, once in the belly of the island
Abby and Yara witnessed the Seraphites heading into their armories
to prepare for the incoming WLF attack, which is beginning.
They see WLF members heading into the island and are taken by complete surprise by this.
Honestly it's little surprising to me that the Seraphites didn't see this coming in at least a little bit.
They have a huge infrastructure throughout the city,
as we've seen with bridges that co from rooftop to rooftop and they're very sneaky,
So it seems as though they should have been able to realize
that the WLF was mobilizing for some sort of offensive.
After all, they were bringing all of their supplies in all of their soldiers into one central area.
如果这都没让赛拉菲特的首领警觉的话 那他是干什么吃的
If that doesn't spook you as the leader of the Seraphites, I don't know what will.
But regardless, they're preparing for the offensive.
This gives you a little bit of space to explore the island and push through to Abby and Yara's house.
While you're doing this, you find through multiple arenas of Seraphites, all fairly stealth oriented.
But nonetheless it gives you something to do
to shake up the monotony of just walking through sequences in watching small cut scenes.
Eventually you come upon the house, and the following scene plays out.
And this doesn't really surprise anyone, she was never going to understand.
But it's also important to note that this severs all ties for Lev,
which signal to me that they were actually being set up to leave Seattle completely
without leaving any baggage behind.
Whenever a game or a story starts to sever familial and friendly ties to a character
usually it means that they are preparing to make some sort of big transition
so that they aren't left with the baggage or having to explain that baggage way.
I, however, don't think that this was particularly necessary.
I think leaving Lev and Yara's mom behind really wouldn't have been that big of deal.
After all, she's a member of a cult, a cult that wants to kill them.
Regardless, Abby, Yara and Lev pushed together to the docks
where they want to find a boat and take that boat back to the aquarium.
I was never super clear on why
these characters couldn't just return to the boat that they had just taken to shore.
But nonetheless, they want you to push to the docks,
grab a separate different boat and escape using that one.
I'm not sure if there was damage to the boat when you reached the island
or why they can't use the boat they just took from the peer from the WLF.
But nonetheless they can't for some reason.
To me, it seems like more of an excuse
just to get these characters to push into the main center of town
so that they can see a new set piece as the WLF and Seraphites' clash.
I get it, it makes sense, but it just doesn't seem to logically follow
considering that they just took a boat to the island
that's much closer than the boat they are trying to push to.
I don't know.
If there's some really good excuse as to why they can't go back to that original boat,
just let me know.
So the three star pushing through an old town that's been completely abandoned,
and it looks as though the Seraphites don't even actively patrol it
since it's from the old world.
Everything's quiet, until …
于是现在开始我们和勒弗搭档对抗我们曾经的队友——WLF成员
So now we're paired with Lev against the WLF members
we previously considered our friends.
但说实话 这段实在是游戏中情感上的一大困惑点
Be honest, it's a really emotionally confusing chunk of the game,
因为相当多的人都在讨论 不知道埃比为什么要这样做
since there are so many people constantly yelling at Abby asking why she is doing this.
我们可能不认识这些人 但埃比认识啊
Now we may not know these characters, but Abby does.
她在戕害曾经和她一起工作过的 她所了解的
She's killing people that she worked with, that she knows,
并没有做错任何事情的人啊
who haven't really done anything wrong themselves,
而这一切只是为了勒弗 一个跟她没有任何关系的人
all for the sake of Lev, somebody that she's not even related to,
她根本没有任何理由要去关心他
and for whom she has really no reason to care.
这太离谱了 兄弟们 这是人干的事吗？
And that's pretty crazy, I mean, who would do that?
谁会为了某个不相干的人而杀死自己以前曾一起共事的人
Who would kill people that they've previously worked with
for somebody that are not related to
只是因为你俩建立了某种联系所以你关心他？
and just care because they've built a connection to them?
哦对
Oh.
So Abby and Lev come upon a view of what Isaac's group has done.
They're torturing the whole place, they're literally going scorched earth.
And so as we push to the marina to get the boat that we need to escape,
we fight multiple waves of Scars and WLF members at the same time,
sometimes coming across them, fighting each other when we interrupt just trying to pass through.
Really, it's kind of cool,
to see all of these enemies interacting with each other and just wiping each other out.
It's kind of crazy.
Now the sequence has actually got a fair amount of crap because there's no infected here,
but that to me doesn't make any sense as an accusation or criticism.
This is an island, and it's an island that the Seraphites have lived on for a long time.
They likely cleared out the infected on the island very early on and have kept it contained.
Sure, it's a little weird to play what many people thought was just going to be a zombie game
and to not see zombies for hours and hours on end.
But I think it makes sense, at least in the world that they've built.
TLOU is far more complicated than just a story about zombies.
It's really upsetting to hear boiled down to that basic and estimation.
Now, eventually, Abby and Lev find a horse,
hop on it and ride into the heart of the Seraphites capital.
This really is a visually stunning sequence and I really can't complemented enough.
The lighting is ridiculously good.
It's probably the most impressed I was visually across the entire game, just this one sequence.
So Abby rides the horse all the way through to the edge of the docks.
After killing more and more WLF members, more Seraphites,
climbing through a burning house.
You eventually find one last many boss in this chapter.
He's a Brute in the same style as Helga.
And there's actually some pretty impressive messed affirmation systems at play here.
As he gets cut on his body, it actually becomes more and more mutilated.
The skin flays open.
It's pretty impressive.
And it's unfortunate that this type of feature couldn't be applied to absolutely every character
at this fidelity level as you attack them throughout the course of the game.
I will grant you the mesh deformation system and the gore system in TLOU2 was pretty incredible.
But if it was on this level it would be another world.
Hopefully we get to see this level of quality in the next generation of consoles.
I have a feeling as though we're going to get it, and it's going to be pretty bad ass.
Probably the best example of this system working is when you use a scythe to gash his mouth open.
Now it seems to me that this can't be just a coincidence that the gash occurs at this place,
considering that the Scars got their name "the Scars"
because they actively and willingly mutilate their mouths with this type of scar intentionally.
Now I took this as a way for Abby and Lev to in essence repay the Seraphites
for all of the physical and mental damage that they've applied upon Lev and Yara.
In other words, taking what the Scars, considered a sacred right,
and turning it into a way to strike back.
Or maybe I'm just reading way too much into this.
Regardless, after defeating this Brute, Abby and Lev grab a rowboat
and they head back to the aquarium with the island burning in the background.
We don't really find out what happened after this or how this battle resolved itself,
but I don't really think it's important.
But we do know is that Isaac is dead.
And so the WLF began crumbling upon realizing that their leader was gone.
I would therefore assume that they lost the fight and the Seraphites held their ground.
But I don't think it matters.
Back at the aquarium, Abby comes across the bodies of Owen, Mel and Alice, the dog.
She's absolutely devastated, and it seems as though the writer's job has worked.
These characters that we didn't really care about just a few hours of gameplay ago,
when Ellie came in and killed them,
now actually have a place in our hearts.
We know these characters.
You don't care that much about Mel, you don't really care that much about Owen,
but you have started to care about Abby and Lev.
Abby is devastated by this, and I couldn't help but feel bad.
And the crazy thing is that at this point,
She doesn't even really know that a lot of the other crew members are also dead.
She doesn't know, as far as I am aware,
that Nora was brutally bashed by Ellie;
She doesn't know about all of the others that Ellie came across and killed on her way to find Abby.
And to be honest,
I'm not sure if Abby ever found out about those characters deaths
because as far as I can tell. after the following sequence, she left.
They went to Santa Barbara and started a new life.
The point is, Abby is devastated, and she starts to go into a rage driven mode.
Remember that map that Ellie dropped and left behind
when Tommy and Jesse took her out of the aquarium?
Well, Abby finds it.
She picks it up and conveniently Ellie has marked in a huge circle exactly where they're staying.
And so, Abby and Lev go to the Jackson-Knights' hideout, expecting to find Tommy alone.
Again, as far as they know, it's just Tommy here and some other helpers he has.
They do know for a fact, though, that Tommy's here.
So my assumption would be that Abby really only expects to find Tommy.
After breaking in, they find everyone.
First Tommy at the counter in the lobby, then Jesse, and Ellie as they come through the door.
This is when the game reaches its climax.
You play as Abby as you chase Ellie deep into the depths of the theaters, props and storage room.
And it's here that we have to play as the character we initially hated and tried to defeat,
and then flip that on its head,
trying to hunt down and kill someone that we fell in love with almost a decade ago,
that character being Ellie.
Though based on the pole and the responses that you guys wrote to that survey,
there is actually a fair number of people that reached this point in the game and refused to continue.
They'd played 20, 25, 30 hours of this game,
got to this point and realized that they were being asked to kill Ellie, and they refused to do it.
Now at one point, I think that that's a testament
to just how phenomenally well connected these characters are, to us, the players.
We care about them, and we don't want to see them mistreated.
Now it's really too bad that there wasn't some alternative state
where you could actually choose not to continue this fight, forgive Ellie, and move on.
Thing that could have been a cool moment in terms of player agency
to resolve this dispute peacefully.
But with a linear narrative game such as this, that doesn't really work too well.
And so, you're forced to engage in this boss fight,
where Abby, the protagonist in this instance,
is chasing after the antagonist, which is Ellie.
It's not to say one is right or wrong,
because protagonist and antagonist are purely based on the perspective of the author.
Now as to whether or not this point in the game works, I think there's an active question here.
It's probably going to be a little different for everybody.
Some people probably are going to connect to Abby and Lev
far more than they connected to Ellie over the course of TLOU2.
Now of course, if you played the original game,
you're probably still going to have a lot of that baggage built up from the original game,
when Ellie was far more likable.
The sad truth is that Ellie isn't very likable in this game
as I've said multiple times throughout this critique.
But for me I found myself just sitting and staring at my screen for a moment
when I realized what I was being asked to do here.
And I think it was because the game didn't completely succeed in what it was trying to do
the first time I played the game.
Namely, Naughty Dog, wanted to make the player feel as though killing Ellie was justified
at the very least, just as justifiable as Ellie Killing Abby.
但我认为这并没有起到太好的作用
But the reason I don't think this has worked too well
因为艾莉杀死的埃比那边的人实际上都是配角
is because the people that Ellie has taken from Abby
were all effectively B-Class characters.
欧文？是的 他很不错但他仍然是配角 而且也不是特别有魅力
Owen? Yeah, he's great, but he's supporting and he's not particularly charismatic.
显然不是一个主导角色
Definitely not a leading character.
However, on the other hand, if Ellie shot and killed Lev right as they enter the theater,
I can't help but feel as though this would have worked much better.
Likely the player playing as Abby in this case
would feel much more justified in chasing down Ellie if this had happened.
总之 埃比还是在boss战中追杀艾莉
But nonetheless, Abby hunts Ellie down in a boss fight
这场战斗与第一部中冬季篇结束时对大家最喜欢的食人魔王的战斗基本相同
that's basically identical to the one that ended the winter chapter in the first game
against everybody's favorite cannibal king.
I don't know if it's just lazy, repetitive game design,
or if this is meant to be an actual reversal and similarly in and of itself.
I don't know.
But it does seem shockingly similar in terms of how it's laid out
and the structure of this boss fight.
Maybe it's a coincidence, maybe it's something very intentional, I'm not sure.
But at the very least, I thought that it was a direct parallel.
The whole thing wraps up with one of the hardest to watch cut scenes
in all of gaming as far as I'm concerned.
She stopped short … after left calls out to her,
She realizes that this isn't going to help anything.
Just like killing Joel didn't help her get over her father's death,
the moment she moved on from her father's death, or at the very least accepted,
was that first night after she met Lev and Yara
when she realized that she could have a family again.
United not in hate and vengeance, but in love and unity.
So she lets them go.
Abby and Lev leave, and Ellie and Dina are left, bleeding out on the floor.
We cut to black and the game moves into the final chapter.
Now I don't think I can stress enough just how weird the player likely feels at this point.
It's a mixture of a let down with being blue, bawled all at the same time,
and if I'm being honest, I really didn't know what to make of it.
There are a lot of other people also pointed out
that this was somewhat similar to how Red Dead Redemption 2 started to wrap up its story,
with Arthur's death coming seemingly wrapping up the main story.
And then the player entering into an epilogue that seemed important, but not crucial.
In fact, I asked several friends of mine,
whether or not they actually played the epilogue or not,
after they got through the main story of Red Dead redemption 2,
and you'd be surprised how many of them said that they stopped playing after Arthur died.
On the one hand, I get it.
You've been following one character for the entire length of the game,
and that character's story has seemingly come to an end.
So why do you need to continue playing through
what is objectively a much more boring sequence for multiple hours at a time
if you don't feel as though it's necessary?
And when that game came out,
I couldn't help but feel as though it was either a very conscious decision on the part of Rockstar
to have this epilogue so clearly separate from the main story,
or it was a complete and total oversight.
In the case of TLOU2,
I don't think it's direct comparison, but I do think there are similarities.
In my estimation,
Most players have been going through TLOU2
with the hope that it will end in a climactic scene between Ellie and Abby,
where everything gets resolved, preferably where one kills the other,
or at the very least, there are some sort of reckoning.
But I wouldn't say that this scratches that itch or satisfies that demand.
I don't think it's controversial to say that Abby, pretty clearly won this exchange.
And if she wanted to, could have killed Ellie and Dina easily.
But out of some sense of dignity or grace and forgiveness, pride,
whatever it may be, she decided to spare them.
So while this may be a resolution of the conflict from Abby's perspective,
she's moving on and wants to forget about all of this.
It's not a resolution for Ellie, for Tommy, or for Dina,
as we'll see in the following scenes.
And I think the really frustrating thing for the player is that the entire story has been building
to this moment, this exchange, this fight, throughout the entirety of the game play time.
And now that we've reached it, it doesn't resolve itself at all.
And instead, Ellie, Dina and Tommy are left bleeding out on the floor,
and in the case of Jesse, he's dead.
And especially considering how emotionally exhausting the scheme is to play,
it's really difficult to ask the player to buckle down for another
however many hours it's going to take to get through what is effectively the epilogue.
And I know it's not technically an epilogue because the story hasn't resolved itself.
It's still part of the main story as we move into this next chapter.
But still it feels as though it separate from the main game.
And after a lot of contemplation, I am not sure if Naughty Dog wanted this to be the case,
or if they even meant for this to feel so different from the core body of the game in Seattle.
It seems to be pretty clear that shifting pace very sharply after all of the events of the core game,
is going to hit the player in a fairly significant way such that they're going to feel very differently.
It's something a good number of developers have spoken of
in GDC conference, speeches, and things like that,
where they express this frustration with working on a project for years and years and years
and losing perspective on it,
such that they forget how it would actually feel to play it for the first time.
In other words, when you're working really hard on something,
you develop a sort of tunnel vision and you lose perspective on what it looks like from the outside.
It may seem great to you,
but just because you're so focused on the little details,
you might have lost sight of the overall picture.
Or vice versa, you are focused on the broader picture, so you lose sight of the minutiae.
Regardless, this final fight leaves the player feeling kind of strange,
at least it did for me;
and based on a lot of your responses to the survey,
it left a lot of you feeling very strange as well.
And I don't know about you,
but often strangers into feeling I would associate with quality.
But with all that said after this initial chunk of the game is over,
the player's left with a lot of questions unresolved.
For instance, is Dina okay?
Is she going to survive having her face bashed into cement multiple times?
While it's technically it wasn't cement, they put down a particle board
so that they could have an excuse as to why she survived, its good detail.
I'm glad that they put this in there
so that it's not totally unbelievable that she survived a cracked skull.
But still this is a pretty rough thing to go through, especially when you're pregnant.
So the player's left wondering whether or not she's going to be okay.
You also have to ask yourself what's going to happen to this couple
when the incoming baby comes along now that Jesse's gone.
How is Jackson going to handle
having so many of their best and brightest, decimated by an out of state group?
Can, or will they ever be able to adjust?
I mean, we don't ever really get to know.
Because in the following sequences, we never return back to Jackson.
And perhaps the most important question is what does Ellie do now?
Is she capable of moving on?
Is that something that Ellie would even want?
Is that something that would even satisfy the player?
Or are we setting ourselves up for one last hurrah to try and resolve everything
in a desperate attempt to justify the events of the core game itself,
just like Red Dead Redemption 2.
It's gonna end up being the latter.
Answers to these questions will mostly come, but for now we're left in the dark.
After cut to black, after this fight, we open up on a farm.
There's an expansive wheat field with a farm house off in the distance and a barn behind it.
It's very calm and picturesque.
Inside we see Ellie,
she seems, healed up and relatively healthy,
and she's holding Joel's old broken watch that he got from Sarah in the first game.
This is a not so subtle way of reminding the player that Ellie is still thinking about Joel,
and that she hasn't moved on.
Also, there's a baby now.
This reaffirms that it's been a good long while since the events of the previous scene.
Furthermore, we see Dina in the kitchen,
and it seems as though she's recovered just fine,
and she also has her mom jeans coming in clutch.
I mean maybe, it's stupid, I'm honestly not sure what it is.
But when I saw Dina in this scene, I thought that she just she looked like a mom.
I don't know what it is, maybe they bushed up her eyebrows, and that did it.
Maybe it's the strange outfit she has on or the fact that she's doing dishes.
I don't know what it is.
But they seemingly did a good job of making her appear as a mother,
I guess props to Naughty Dog.
And to be honest, everything seems calm and relatively happy,
but nothing ever ends happily in this world.
So of course this won't last for long.
Ellie does some routine chores, you dance with Dina a little bit, and you explore the house.
Fun little note here is that Ellie actually has a good amount of art in the house
that was taken from Joel's house.
It's a nice touch,
and it makes sense since she would likely want to hold on to parts of him,
as we just saw earlier when she had his watch.
It's just a really sweet little detail,
especially considering the fact that the player will likely not notice this,
at least on their first run through the game.
I only noticed it once I spent a lot of time recording footage for this video
going back through environments very carefully.
I noticed that in Joel's house there are a lot of really nice looking paintings that I liked.
In fact, I even reference those earlier in this very video.
But then when I went back through this section, I noticed that those paintings looked similar.
And I initially thought that they were just reusing assets which is pretty common in game development.
But upon further inspection and deliberation,
I realized that this was actually an artistic choice,
because Ellie is trying to keep and bring parts of Joel into her life even still.
Now, after exploring the house and chilling with Dina for a little bit,
Dina asks Ellie to bring in the sheep from outside and put them into the barn.
So Ellie goes, and does this with the baby.
And after doing it, Ellie spots one little straggler.
And there's probably leads to the fastest mood shift of the whole game.
I really think that this moment is meant to hit the player just as hard as it hits Ellie.
Everything seems fine, calm and relaxed.
It seems as though they've moved on from a lot of the struggles of the core game
and that their living a happy, satisfied life together.
But now everything is falling apart.
Ellie's mind won't let her forget what happened to Joel,
and she's clearly been unable to move on.
Dina knows this and is understanding because she knows that Ellie can't help this.
It's something beyond her control,
just like anybody else who suffers from panic attacks can't really control it.
It just happens when it happens.
But the game keeps carrying along, relatively quickly.
We jump to the next day and there is a guest in the house.
It's Tommy.
Yeah, he's survived the shot to the head.
He's currently got a lot of damage that he's dealing with and he even struggles walking.
I mean, he took a bullet to the head, so … it's understandable.
Clearly he's not in good shape,
but he does not want to let Abby get away with what she's done.
He says that he's tractor to a location in Santa Barbara.
Now, even though he doesn't state it outright,
it's pretty clear that he's unable to go and chase her himself.
He can barely walk after all, and he's missing an eye now,
so he wouldn't exactly be much help if he were to go.
And so he's come to Ellie to proposition her for this revenge plot.
Now initially, this might seem relatively far fetched
that Tommy was able to track her down to a city that is very far away from where they are at.
Apparently they're just outside of Jackson in the surrounding area,
so they're local, but they have moved out away from the core group.
However, I don't think this is as far as stretch as it might initially seem.
Tommy has a ton of connections to the Fireflies.
If you remember from earlier,
Owen said that he wanted to go to Santa Barbara on the boat with Mel, Abby, Yara and Lev,
because he thought that there were going to be a lot of Fireflies there
that they could connect and join up with.
Using the same contacts, it seems Tommy was able to track
a very buff woman with a small young Asian individual by her side to this area.
So it seems relatively plausible that they would be able to track her to this point,
especially if Tommy were to put out an APB on this individual trying to find her,
which he's clearly done.
However, after hearing his proposition, Ellie and Dina strongly reject the idea.
They are done with that.
Or at the very least, Dina is, and Ellie going along with it.
Now they have too much to lose.
They have a house of family and of course each other.
They've been there, done that.
In the last time they tried to chase Abby down, it didn't end well.
Tommy leaves furious that they're not going to do anything.
He feels betrayed, and even calls Ellie out,
since she told him that she was going to do whatever it took to get revenge.
It's an understandable reaction, considering that Tommy is still furious about his brother's death,
and that she has now permanently scarred him.
But it is a little startling to see Tommy react in such a sharp way towards Ellie.
In fact, I can't think of a time when we've ever seen Tommy
react or talk to somebody in this way throughout the entirety of this franchise.
The closest example would be in the first game when Joel and Tommy got frustrated with each other
when they initially visited the power plant.
But even that wasn't this sharp or direct.
Dina asks that Tommy leaves and then yells at him for a brief moment outside
where it can still be overheard by Ellie.
But Ellie is still caught up in all of this.
She knows that Dina is not OK with her going and trying to end this once and for all,
but she's still pondering everything.
In fact, in the next scene,
we see her walking aimlessly through the house in the middle of the night,
unable to sleep and unsure of what to do.
She wants revenge but knows that it may cost her everything.
她用乔尔的旧吉他弹着小调 想让自己忘掉一切
She plays a little ditty and Joel's old guitar to take her mind off of everything.
But it doesn't seem to do anything.
In fact, it seems to make everything worse.
We then jumped to the scene of the Jackson Winter Ball
that we have only heard discussed up to this point.
It plays out just like we saw in the trailer before launch,
except that now we see the events described in the first hours of the game.
After the happenings of the trailer, culminating in the kiss between Ellie and Dina,
an old man makes a disparaging comments about Dina and Ellie kissing.
Joel steps in and pushes them which upsets Ellie for some reason.
Likely because she feels as though Joel is once again keeping her from fighting her own fights.
But don't worry, we'll talk about this more in just a little bit.
So, back in the present, Ellie has decided that she has to take Abby on,
to finish this once, and for all,
Perhaps reminded of this confrontation with the old, bigoted man,
she realizes that she needs to fight her own fights and finish this,
otherwise she won't be able to live with herself.
However, this time she's not just leaving Jackson behind,
she's abandoning her entire family, this whole thing that she's built up.
Once again it's hard to feel sorry for Ellie here,
especially since most people I think
would say that she should have left well enough alone and not chased Abby again.
Literally every single person I've talked to about this final decision by Ellie
to leave everything, and Chase Abby down again
has said that this was the wrong decision, and that they didn't want her to do it.
They wanted her to forgive Abby to move on.
It's yet another example of how emotionally exhausting the scheme can be to play,
because when you don't agree with what the characters are doing,
you start to lose sympathy with them.
And that makes it harder to empathise with everything that they're going through.
Ellie starts packing up her things when Dina finds her.
Dina clearly knows that Ellie's been considering this
but is terrified to see her actually going through with it.
Dina begs her to come back to bed,
to move on, to forget about everything, to stay with the family and not do this.
But Ellie says she has no choice and has to.
Dina makes it very clear that she's not going to do this whole thing again.
She's not going to go and help her.
And if Ellie decides that this is what's most important to her,
she shouldn't expect to find her and the baby there when or if she gets back alive.
She is effectively giving Ellie an ultimatum.
Choose Abby, or choose Dina,
and the family, and everything that she's built up with her.
Ellie chooses Abby.
Again, giving the player very little reason to feel bad or sorry for her,
Losing Dina, and for all of the pain that she's likely to encounter
in the next few hours as the game wraps up.
So Ellie leaves, Dina's left devastated.
And Naughty Dog pulls a fake out.
We jumped to California.
It's a market set difference, everything's very dry and dead.
The chapter opens up with the camera focused on a pair of Converse.
Anyone who's played the first game knows that this is Ellie signature shoe.
But the camera pans up,
and we see that it's Lev wearing the shoes and Abby's walking alongside him.
Now this is a bit obvious for me,
but it's clearly setting up the parallel between Abby and Joel and Ellie and Lev.
Whether you think those are fair to draw as comparisons or similes is up to you,
but that's clearly what the writers are doing.
Ellie is known for her Converse,
and in fact it's one of the staples of her outfit in the first game,
and even throughout most of the second game.
To so clearly show these shoes to me is hitting the player over the head with this simile.
Now Abby and Lev are looking for the Fireflies
hoping to find a new home to which they can belong.
Again, remembering that Owen suggested Santa Barbara way back when.
Now they had a tip that 2425 Constance in Santa Barbara
was a hideout for the underground Firefly network.
And so after Abby and Lev fight through a few infected,
they worked their way to the basement of the house,
and the pair discovers a radio.
And after a few attempts they connect with somebody.
And it seems as though Abby and Lev have found their new home and will be safe after all.
But again, no, everything is sad and terrible.
Nothing's gonna end happily, so just get ready, everything is going to go terribly wrong.
So the two set up a meet up point where they're gonna head to meet up with the Fireflies.
As the pair leaves the house,
they are intercepted by a small gang as they exit out the front of the house.
It seems that these people are involved in the slave trade,
which, to be honest, I'm stunned took this long to be featured in the game.
They're beaten, tied up and taken away,
presumably to be entered into the slave trade and used for manual labor.
We then cut to Ellie, who was closing in quickly.
She's found their boat and begins pushing into their location
after finding a map that has 2425 Constance marked on it.
As you push through multiple houses and streets,
this is the last zombie hurrah combat in the entire game.
So be sure to enjoy it.
Because after this Naughty Dog is going to be sticking with human enemies exclusively.
Except for one small exception, which I'll point out in a moment.
But still, it's going to be pretty much all humans after this.
Ellie pushes her way through an initial neighborhood and starts climbing down a hill.
When this happens.
Now these guys are obviously super dome.
But you have to ask yourself as the player, what's keeping you going?
Other than just going through the motions of continuing to do what the game asks you to do.
One of the best things about the early hours of TLOU2 is that the player is completely on board
with Ellie's drive and mission to take out Abby.
And as the game goes on,
you also start to lose that motivation once you start to sympathise with Abby and her crew.
So you end up very conflicted in that final boss fight
where you don't want to do anything or hurt either one of these characters.
But now the players still feels like that.
And yet the game designers are asking Ellie to chase down Abby,
even though it's caused her to lose everything at this point
and will likely not result in the conclusion
that either the player or Ellie he would be satisfied with.
Some people have said that this is a pacing issue,
but I don't think that that's the right way to phrase it.
If anything, I think that this is a motivational issue.
I think the player doesn't feel motivated to continue on this mission
that they're being asked to embark on.
Now of course, you could have a game
that motivates the player to continue playing purely by way of its game play,
and there is no narrative reason to continue at all.
However, that's not how Naughty Dog games work.
Naughty Dog games are entirely about motivating the player by way of this narrative drive.
And I'll be honest, it's really too bad that this falls so flat
because this should be the climax of the game.
But instead it feels as though it's a total chore,
because the player doesn't feel as though Ellie is justified in what she's doing.
And certainly Ellie is even frustrated with her own decision.
The only reason Ellie is continuing on it is because she feels an obligation to Joel,
an obligation that's going to be resolved very shortly.
But even so, the player pushes on into the slave trader camped known as "the Resort".
It's not a sassy or funny name,
it's just that it's an old resort, so they call it "the Resort".
It's pretty simple now this section does feature my favorite gun of the entire game,
but it's so damn powerful that it removes any need for any finesse whatsoever.
So with this new found super weapon,
you fight your way through the Resorts main building where all of the slaves are housed.
And to be honest, the section is actually pretty bad,
especially when considering that it is the final section of the game.
This is the final game play section of the game other than the final boss quote-unquote, "fight",
and its painfully uninteresting.
The only thing that shakes it up a little bit
is having zombies chained up that you can release on the human NPCs.
But other than that, there's really nothing that's interesting about this level.
And even though zombies, you shoot off their chains or disconnect them,
and they started attacking the other people, the other NPCs
and then you just end up having to kill zombies before they come to you
if they are not already killed by those human NPCs.
So it even by itself doesn't do anything new or different.
It's just bland and it's unfortunate because it really should be the climax,
but instead it just lands super flat.
I was really surprised to see this
because usually Naughty Dog is pretty good about sticking the landing.
They go crazy, big and elaborate in the final sections of the game,
whether you're looking at Uncharted or even the original TLOU game
where they really push the boundary of difficulty.
But here it just doesn't work.
But even so, after killing countless slavers, Ellie finds her way to the beach.
She's told by several other prisoners
that this is where Abby and Lev have been moved after they tried to escape.
And usually the slaves are left here hung up until they die.
And I gotta say it's pretty surreal once you reach this beach
and what Ellie finds there is pretty upsetting.
Now there's actually a fake out with the girl in the center that has the braid.
It looks like Abby, especially Abby the last time that we saw her.
But it's not Abby.
Abby in fact, you just walked past.
And she's in much worse shape.
Truely, she doesn't even look like the same person.
Now it took a moment that Abby recognizes Ellie here,
but she's not interested in fighting.
Instead, the moment that Ellie cuts her down, she goes to help Lev.
Abby then carries Lev into the distance despite her weakness.
And they come up on the same boat
that we've seen in the title screen every time we booted up the game to this point.
Even now, Abby is purely concerned with taking care of Lev,
making sure that they are able to get out safely.
She even leads Ellie to the boats to help her escape.
I'm aware that Ellie has come to kill her
and enact the revenge that she sought out initially.
As far as we know, Abby may think that Ellie was being housed as a slave herself,
and has escaped to this point.
But whatever it may be,
Abby gets down to the boat area
and Ellie still wounded from the tree branch that she was impaled with,
and Abby, wounded from the weeks or months of torture,
at their very end, have to face off in one final painful battle.
Ellie demands to fight with Abbey to finish this once and for all.
She even takes out her switch blade and threatens to kill Lev if Abby doesn't engage with her.
And so left with no choice,
Abby decides that she'll fight Ellie, not for her, not for Ellie, but for Lev.
If you show to player this fight scene at the very start of the game,
it would probably give them a lot of pleasure.
It would feel good for the player to literally hack and slash the person that killed Joel to pieces.
But instead, it's absolutely horrible.
It's pathetic.
And no part of this feels like a comeuppance or like justice.
And I think if anything, this means that the game's arc worked.
It actually went from me wanting to kill Joel's killer
to wanting to forgive her and move on.
It's simple, but it's powerful.
And as this fight continued on, all I could ask for was that they would just stop.
But the fight continues,
each growing weaker and weaker until the fight comes to its inevitable conclusion.
We're now back at the farm house.
It seems to have been quite a while, since everything is so dilapidated.
That house's empty, the paint chipping, the woods warped,
and I think all of this is meant to show that Dina moved out with the baby
and that Ellie is now alone.
But regardless, it's been quite a while since anyone's been here.
And so while it may be meant to show that Ellie is alone
and that the ramifications for her actions
have taken much more of a toll than just the loss of a couple fingers.
I think it might not be that simple,
and this might actually be a happier ending than it might initially seem to be.
But we'll get to that in just a few minutes.
Ellie walks through the empty house,
eventually coming into one room that has what seems to be most of Ellie's old things,
and a lot of Joel's items that were collected throughout the house.
She takes up Joel's guitar
and plays a strained version of the song that he played for her in the beginning.
Her missing fingers, now a permanent example of the distance between Joel and Ellie
and their inability to truly connect,
she can't even play the song properly or fully now.
We then cut to the most important scene of the whole game.
A scene that I couldn't do justice
even if I were to spend weeks riding it outward for word.
So instead, I'm just going to let it play.
And just like that, the game is over.
Closing in on the same shot that the game opened up with,
a focus on Joel's guitar as he was cleaning it at the very start,
describing what happened the hospital at the end of the first game.
The last scene demonstrating how Ellie was going to try and forgive Joel
and move on the very night before his passing.
The story reaches a surprising conclusion.
This is why, back at the beginning of the video,
I told you that Ellie wanting to have a movie night with Joel was so very important.
It was going to be their first step towards healing.
They were going to try and bury the hatchet,
which is why Ellie was so unbelievably distraught
when she lost Joel before this healing could take place.
But it seems as though,
after all of this contemplation, all of this nervousness,
all of this stress, all of this hatred that had built up over months,
and at this point, years of struggling with Joel's demise
that she's realized the best way to deal with that grief
is to accept that he's gone and to move on,
living her life happily, not seeking revenge,
but living it with people like Joel, who loved her, for her.
and where she could enact and practice that very same love and affection that she received.
And as she walks off into the distance,
she's leaving everything behind, all of Joel's old items, everything that he left her.
She has moved on.
And it seems as though, after a very long journey,
Joel and Ellie story has finally come to an end.
And just like that the game is over.
I mean, I really don't know
how to break down where my mind was when I first saw these credits roll.
And I feel as though the best way to kind of wrap all of this up is by talking with you guys,
one on one in an unscripted way, or I can just wrap up all of my thoughts.
Because I think that this game is truly exceptional,
again in the purest sense of the word, where it's an exception to the rule.
Most games, you can give a thumbs up or thumbs down,
you can say it's really good or it's really bad.
And TLOU2 is a game I think is very, very good.
It's an enjoyable game play experience, I think.
For the most part, it works really well, except for some pacing issues.
But a lot of those pacing issues are problematic, primarily because of the narrative
because you want to focus on one character and you're having to keep swap between the two.
But even so, there's some gameplay pacing issues,
such as having problems with climax building
and making sure that the final boss fights are really intriguing and interesting, and things like that.
But all told, as far as the game is concerned, it's very well done as a game,
and most people who have a problem with TLOU2
don't deny that they accepted and agree with it.
So that doesn't seem to be where the criticisms tend to come out.
I think we're most criticisms find themselves presented …
our with regards to the direction Naughty Dog chose to go in.
Because the writers, of course, had the option,
they didn't have to go the direction that they did.
They didn't have to kill Joel off for one,
they didn't have to make you empathize with Abby,
they didn't have to make you play as Abby for the second half of the game,
they didn't have to do any of that.
But that's the direction they chose to go in.
And I think as far as I can tell,
most people were hoping and expecting that the game would be about Ellie,
and that's it.
They were interested in playing and getting to know this new character.
And I think that that's just the frustrating thing about it
is that a lot of people were hoping and expecting to
have exposure and experience with Ellie.
That was not just dreadful through and through,
But instead they were forced to go through this very frustrating and
very emotionally taxing journey with her,
which I think is probably where I land.
Because I really cherish Ellie as a character, I care about her,
and I connected with her on a level
I didn't realize I could connect with the character in the first game.
And her actions in the second game make her very difficult to sympathize with.
Because she's doing things that are objectively pretty dumb and stupid
that aren't for the betterment of her and the people around her.
She's being fairly selfish in what she's doing,
and she does feel a an obligation of sorts to Joel to continue on in her revenge journey.
But still, it's not the same as the actions of Joel in the first game
where he goes after Ellie, even though he's killing a lot of people to get to her and to save her
from the Fireflies and everything they are about to do to her.
At least there you can understand why he's doing it and you might even agreed
because you care about Ellie too.
And you might say I care about her so much,
I would probably do the same thing if I was in his shoes.
With Ellie in this game, many times, I found myself saying I would not have done that.
That was the wrong choice, I don't agree with that.
I care about you Ellie, and that's why I disagree with what you're doing.
She's on a self destructive, borderline suicide mission throughout the entire game,
and that just makes it so hard to sympathize with her, if not impossible.
And when you don't sympathise with somebody,
you shouldn't be surprised when people don't connect with them,
which is why, for a lot of people,
they found themselves feeling as though that this wasn't a TLOU game, even by itself.
It wasn't a sequel, it was a completely separate story.
Ellie had grown up and become a different person,
and she was almost unrecognisable from the character she was in the first game,
which is why Naughty Dog keep springing up all these flashbacks
to kind of remind you of what Ellie used to be like.
But that isn't enough, because you're playing in the current timeline.
And if that Ellie is not enjoyable, isn't sympathetic, and you don't care about her,
you don't care about her.
So when we bring up the question,
whether or not Ellie is is a well written character in this story.
I think for the story they were trying to tell she was well written,
and it accomplish the purpose which for Naughty Dog
was to make you sympathize with somebody that killed a character you loved and cared about,
to make you see the other side of the story,
to understand all the perspectives, and to get that sometimes violence isn't the answer.
And sometimes, terrible things happen and are somewhat justified.
Or that you could even find yourself in the shoes of that character doing that thing
if you were put into some sort of like different circumstances, you know.
And I think that that's a really interesting story to tell.
And I think that's a fair story to tell.
And that's … when I think of the game that way,
I find myself much more impressed with it and thinking that it's absolutely a masterpiece.
But I think my frustration is that it was a TLOU game.
And that they sacrifice not just Joel but also Ellie at the altar of that story.
Because I don't think that creating new characters
and telling the story from start to finish with new characters would have been as successful.
I think part of what makes that story arc of "Forgiving the Unforgivable", the title of this video.
I think that's part of what of what makes it so impressive is that
you are dealing with characters you've known effectively for a decade at this point.
You've known for seven plus years,
by the time you're watching this magnum for … for longer than that.
And I think that that's just what's really frustrating, but understandable is that
they sacrifice these two characters that you love for the sake of telling this story,
when they reassured us prior to launch that they were doing
what was best for the characters that they weren't going to do them dirty,
that this was what was best for Joel and Ellie,
and they wouldn't be making the game if they didn't feel as though it was the right story to tell.
So I can understand the frustration on that end.
很多人也感到沮丧的是游戏似乎没有一个圆满的结局
A lot of people also are frustrated that the game doesn't seem to have a happy ending
艾莉失去了一切 然后继续前行下去
that Ellie lost everything then moves on.
她忘记了乔尔 忘记了蒂娜
Forgets Joel and forgets Dina,
抛弃了一切
and leaves everything behind and
也失去了一切
seemingly has lost everything hasn't gained, anything other than
把乔尔的东西留在农场的房子里 继续前行下去
maybe coming to grips and peace with what happened with Joel moving on,
leaving all of his stuff behind in the farmhouse.
But I actually think that there's remnants of a happy ending here,
and it's something that's a small detail,
and it's something I didn't really consider until a good number of people had tweeted it at me
and … had … mentioned it on Discord.
And it's something that once I started to investigate it, I was kind of blown away,
and I thought that it's actually really interesting theory.
Because you see at the end of the core story of TLOU2 after Ellie and Abby have their fight out,
Ellie is not wearing any sort of adornment, she is bare arrested.
But when you see her back at the farmhouse, in the final scene of the game,
she's actually wearing this very bracelet,
which is why it's interesting that they included it as part of the Collector's Edition.
This is actually dina's bracelet that she has.
And the one that they include here, I mean, it's just it's a crappy little Collector's Edition.
You know, trinket, but it's still it's still fun.
But Ellie is wearing that.
And Ellie wearing it even though seemingly she's split up with Dina,
And Dina moved away and has completely cut ties.
And the theory basically goes that
they've returned to the house after a good amount of time, at least Ellie has.
The house is cleared out, and they've decided to completely move on from Jackson.
They're moving out, which is why the house is much more dilapidated.
And Ellie has decided to leave all of Joel's things behind because she needs to move on,
and she needs to stop bringing this with her.
And so her wearing of the bracelet isn't just meant
to symbolise that she still feels a connection with Dina,
or that she misses Dina or wishes she had made a different decision.
But that it's actually a direct message that she and Dina are back together.
And that they've decided to move on together.
Dina has forgiven Ellie, and that they are effectively living happily ever after.
Now is that a stretch, perhaps … perhaps.
Not many things in TLOU, at the world of TLOU, have happy endings.
But I think the tone of the end of the game is very uplifting,
very bright and sunny.
And the title screen at the end of the game goes back to a sunny beach right outside the Resort,
where the game reaches its climax,
which I think symbolizes the same thing.
It's a bright, happy ending, morning has come.
The light is always after the darkness, the sun has risen after night.
Use any analogy or simply you want.
So,
I'd like to think that the story actually has a happy ending,
and that Ellie and Dina and the baby all got back together.
And they're off living in some cabin in the middle of nowhere.
They've left Jackson and they've moved on
and they're just not going to be burdened by any of this anymore.
That's at least what I choose to believe,
because I think Ellie deserves that ending after all of this,
and so that's what I'm going to go with until I learn differently.
And I think the fact that the designers included the bracelet on Eli's wrist at that ending farm scene is directly indicative of that being what happened?
I think it's a little nod may be a little hint.
hint that things actually ended happily,
but who knows I'd like to think that things ended happily.
But all told,
the game is very.
Difficult to come to terms with because it wasn't what I was expecting and perhaps even hoping for.
But even so,
I think it succeeded in what it was trying to do.
As I said earlier in the video,
I think the mission was to get you to sympathise with Abbey and to flip the script so that you went from hating Abbey to caring about her.
And so when you reach this conclusion that you initially had hoped for for l to take on Abby and kill her.
It feels empty and hollow and unsatisfying.
Because you realize that this isn't as simple as just revenge,
and I think that that in and of itself as a narrative decision is truly remarkable.
It really is whether you love it or hate it.
You've got to give Naughty Dog credit for having the balls to do something so unbelievably risky that has obviously polarized the fan base.
Pissed off a lot of people.
I can only imagine the hate mail that they've received since this went live,
but they knew that it would.
They knew that it would,
and.
They chose to do it anyways.
when they didn't need to,
they could have done just an obligatory.
You know sequel where Joel and Ellie embark on some new journey may be Tommy gets murdered by Abby,
and then they chase him down and may be right.
Before the final scene,
Abby kills Joel,
and then Ellie gets revenge.
I'll Abby wipes her out.
and it's kind of the uncharted style ending where everything wraps up,
but a character died in it.
It makes you feel more appreciative of what you have,
and they could have done that.
That would have been the easy way to go,
though,
and while I think it would have been received well,
the gameplay would have been really solid.
I don't think it would have challenged so many of us to think about video game narratives in a different way because,
as I've said for many many years at this point and by many many years and be like two or three,
ah,
I think video games are the evolution of narrative storytelling.
I think gaming is a remarkable tool.
For storytelling.
And I can't help but feel as though the last was part.
Two takes a huge leap forward in the types of stories that can and will be told on the platform,
especially moving into the next generation,
though some people think that that's terrible,
some people hear that,
and they think why cant stories just end happily ever after?
Nowadays,
everything's going to be so dark.
Everything so dreary,
everything,
so sad.
And while that's true for some stories,
I think more than anything,
it's just trying to push narratives to the point where they can be.
Thought provoking in a way that very few happy go,
lucky stories are,
I enjoy uncharted?
I'm making a whole series of uncharted critiques.
and that's what I was doing before.
The last was part two launched,
and this whole video experience began.
But those stories don't really make you ponder they don't make you think.
I've never played an uncharted game and then sat back and just.
Wow,
what does this mean?
What do I think of this?
I don't.
Even though I'm so conflicted.
I have so many thoughts and emotions.
Going on usually uncharted.
Emotional repertoire consists of action and excitement,
and there may be some light heartwarming moments with some witty banter back and forth between two characters you like,
and that's kind of it.
I think Naughty Dog is trying to push the boundary and tell a story that does a lot more than that,
and I think they're successful,
and I think it's pretty remarkable what they've managed to accomplish.
So while I am frustrated with the last was part two for pacing issues for flip,
flopping back and forth between character so frequently that you start to lose focus.
I do think that it's truly a remarkable game,
and I think it does far more good than it does bad.
And while a couple of things are handled,
Kenneth Clinically and I think some characters aren't as reliable as they were hoping,
for.
instance Owen and Mel.
When they get killed,
you're supposed to feel really bad as far as I can tell.
and I just even after playing through Abyei sections.
it just didn't really hit me hard.
What hit me hard with seeing Abby so upset about it,
It wasn't saying Owen and Mel killed that upset me.
and I think that that's more a failure of Naughty Dogs writing than a success.
I don't think that was intentional.
As I said earlier in the video,
but all told,
I think the game is pretty amazing and it's taken me months of playing through it multiple times to come to that conclusion,
and I'll tell you right now.
When I finished the game the first time I was not.
I was not in the same place I am now.
I would not have said that I thought it was a masterpiece.
I would not have said that I thought it was amazing and remarkable.
I was pretty frustrated and emotionally torn apart,
but after playing through the game a couple more times it really is kind of like an acquired taste.
It's like a fine wine or caviar or something.
It's it's something where the more that you engage with it,
the more you realize and appreciate all of the little details,
all of the interweaving plot lines and character arcs.
And for that reason I think the game is truly remarkable.
Will it take my game of the year?
I don't know I'm really hoping that Cyber punk twenty seventy seven comes out and just blows us all away.
I love CD project read,
and from what I saw behind closed doors at age three last year of Cyber Punk,
I think it has the possibility of being really impressive,
but I'm also worried that hype is getting out of control,
which is very possible with that game.
But we'll see who knows,
by the time you're watching this video,
you've probably played through Cyber Punk,
or you might have played through Cyber punk,
and you'll be laughing at what I'm saying,
or maybe they'll be like.
Yeah,
no,
it is terrible,
It's awful.
I have no idea,
I have no idea.
But what I can say is that I think the last of us does a lot to move the industry forward.
I think that the risks that they took our truly.
A plausible if that's even a word,
I appreciate that they took those risks that they didn't play it safe.
and while I think a lot of us probably wish,
they had gone a different direction,
I respect the hell out of them for what they did and I think it worked.
And while I wouldn't have thought to go this direction,
I'm in the end.
I think glad that they did.
But even now I am,
I'm very conflicted and I think the point of art is to make you think to make you ponder everything that went on in the story that was being told to ponder your place in this world and everything that's going on,
and I think the last of us part two.
Does that in a way that literally no game has ever done for me,
and for that I just have to say thank you to Naughty Dog.
They've done something truly incredible.
truly,
so that's all from me.
Thank you for watching this monstrosity of a video at me and everybody that I've worked with on this video.
We truly appreciate it.
I big thanks to Jacob,
my editor for all of the hard work he's done on this video,
he's edited a lot of sections that you've seen and been watching for the last few hours.
So.
Big thanks to him and thanked all of the patrons and all of the viewers who have been so patient.
because this has been the video that's eaten up all my time for the last few months.
as I was getting ready for a wedding as I was starting a new job.
This is consumed all of my time.
and while I think the last of his party was incredible in a lot of ways,
I'm at,
I am ready to move on and to tackle the next big thing.
so.
It's bizarre to be done with everything it's bizarre to be at the end of this video.
I hope that you enjoyed it.
If you did please at the very least hit the like button.
If you really enjoyed it, hit the subscribe button.
I don't mean to sound entitled,
but after all of this, if you really did enjoy this video and got to this point,
I would like to think that you would at the very least,
subscribe and maybe even ring the bells he get notified of the next video.
But truly, thank you.
Thank you for watching.
Thank you for sharing the video.
Thank you for donating thanks for doing everything that you guys do,
you're truly amazing and I love you all more than you could possibly know.
I'll see you in the next video, which will probably be a fair amount, shorter.
Truly, thank you,
I love you guys,
and I'll see you in the next video.
Bye bye.