------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
我曾经对《死亡搁浅》持非常怀疑的态度 甚至一度批评过它
I was very skeptical and even critical of Death Stranding going into it.
我曾对这款游戏各种浮夸的预告与故意模糊游戏内容表示强烈谴责
I bashed it for pretentious marketing intentionally vague explanations of gameplay
我也曾强烈批评小岛秀夫他自己竟无法
and I heavily criticized Kojima himself for his seeming inability
简明扼要地阐明这到底是一款什么样的游戏
to concisely or even coherently define what Death Stranding was.
乍一看它就是一款完全靠“小岛秀夫”这名字为卖点的游戏
It seemed to be a game sold entirely on the name of its creator
这点实际上与他自己的信念相悖
which is actually antithetical to Kojima's own beliefs
至少是与他在2014年发布PT时的信念相悖
or at least the beliefs that he described in 2014 with PT.
当年他在PlayStation商店发布PT这款试玩版的时候
You see when he released the Playable Teaser onto the PlayStation Store as a free demo,
他刻意隐去了他的姓名 他的工作室 他的发行商名称
he intentionally hid his name, his studio and his publisher's branding
游戏本身的宣发材料中丝毫找不到他的踪迹
from every piece of the demo's promotional materials.
据他说 让玩家不知道游戏制作人是谁 玩家就可以不受任何预设的影响
And according to him he did this so that players would be free of any presuppositions
they may have going into a title knowing who created it.
换句话说 他希望玩家能享受PT这个游戏本身
In other words, he wanted players to enjoy PT for what it was,
而不是冲着游戏制作人去的
not for who it was created by.
但到了《死亡搁浅》这里情况就不一样了
However this is not so for Death Stranding.
《死亡搁浅》完全就是以小岛秀夫的名字和他天才般的游戏制作能力为卖点的
Death Stranding was sold entirely
on Kojima's name and the brilliance with which he crafts his games.
这是一个实实在在的重要转变 不容忽视
This is an important and remarkable shift in the pure sense of the word,
and it's one that cannot be overlooked.
坦率地讲 这改变了我们所有人游玩这个游戏时的看法
This frankly changes the way that we all will look and play the game
因为小岛自己就改变了他向我们展示游戏的方式
because Kojima himself is changing the way that he presents it to us.
当然 当一个人的名字能和这款游戏紧紧联系在一起时
Now of course it goes without saying but when any individual is tied so inextricably to a game,
玩家就不得不预先戴上有色眼镜来看待它了
you have to look at it through that lens.
所以我决定作为一个公正的观察者 甚至作为一个评论家来玩玩《死亡搁浅》
And so I decided to play Death Stranding as an impartial observer or even as a critic.
我从来都不是小岛的粉丝
I am by no means a fanboy of Kojima
也从来没真正玩过他的任何其他游戏
and I have never actually played to completion any of his other games.
不过我在准备这期视频之前的确玩了大概五小时的《合金装备V 幻痛》
Although I did play roughly 5 hours of Metal Gear Solid 5 in preparation for this video.
如果你关注了我这个频道 可能知道我在开始时并不是《死亡搁浅》的粉丝
Now if you followed this channel you'll know
that I was not a fan of Deaths Stranding when I began.
实际上我花了大概八小时才开始对游戏有一点点的喜欢
In fact it took roughly 8 hours for it to click
and for me to begin enjoying it even in the least.
我甚至做了一期视频痛批了游戏的前两小时内容
I even made a video where I roasted the first 2 hours of the game,
“痛批前两小时内容”的视频链接在下方
原视频在字幕制作时YouTube差评率接近1/4
弄得不少游戏粉丝不开心
much to the chagrin of the game's fans.
然而过了8小时候 也就是我玩到游戏中期的时候
However after this 8 hour mark in other words once I got to the mid game,
我开始期待早点下班能玩到这个游戏了
I started looking forward to playing the game when I got back from classes.
游戏也开始变成了我的解压玩具
And it actually became my relaxation outlet.
不停爬山送快递真的特别解压
Hiking and delivering packages was effectively stress-relief.
简单来说 《死亡搁浅》于我而言就像垃圾食品一样
Simply put, Death Stranding for me is a junk-food game.
吃个没完但又没啥营养
It's easy to consume nearly impossible to fathom
但又管不住嘴 可劲吃 好像多有营养一样
and it leaves you feeling as though you must consume more to gain any sustenance whatsoever
可惜实际上干货并没有多少
even though there isn't actually much there.
不过没有游戏是完美的 《死亡搁浅》也不例外
Now no game is perfect, Death Stranding included.
这款游戏在为整个行业引入一些新奇想法的同时
And while introducing some interesting ideas to the industry,
的确存在着一些严重缺陷
it does have some serious flaws.
这期视频里我将非常诚恳地告诉大家
Now I'm going to be very honest in this video,
我热爱这款游戏 我认为很多对其表示批评的人都有合理的观点
I'm a fan of the game and I think most people who are critical of it have reasonable points
但《死亡搁浅》也有做得好的地方
but there are also things that Death Stranding does well.
我们将在这期视频中讨论这些内容
And we'll discuss all of these things in this video.
But the point is if we're not honest about the game's shortcomings
we can't help Kojima with whatever his next game is.
And if you've played Death Stranding for any length of time
you should be aware of some of the plethora of issues.
And I just want to reiterate that
while I am very conflicted on many of the design choices made here
and I am going to spend most of this video explaining all of the problems with the game.
I really did enjoy my time with Death Stranding on the whole.
If I had to describe the game concisely
I would say that it's a repetitive relaxing and uncomplicated game
that is overly reliant on ambiguous storytelling
and falls victim to some very bizarre directorial decisions at the hands of Hideo Kojima,
a man so closely tied to Death Stranding that he and the game are inextricably tied,
mostly due to his own statements saying as much.
It's also probably important that I mentioned my qualifications for making this video.
I've put in well over a hundred hours into Death Stranding on two separate PS4s,
a Slim and a Pro, to get an idea of what this game can do technically,
something will touch on lightly later.
I read all of the Emails, completed all of the premium deliveries,
fought all of the BTs, drove all of the vehicles, talked to every celebrity,
shook all babies hunted down the memory chips,
five-star the locations, explored the whole map and after all of that,
I can say confidently the Death Stranding is by far,
the most ironic game that I have ever played in my life.
You see the game was advertised as a new genre of game,
something that would focus on positivity and connecting people from all over the world.
But instead it's become one of the most divisive games of the last decade, maybe of all time.
Some will say that the world is empty boring,
and the gameplay is repetitive and the writing is terrible.
While others will say the Death Stranding is a triumph,
a game that try something new and succeeds,
a game focused on connections and fulfillment.
And the amazing thing is that everyone here is kind of right.
And I know that sounds like an oxymoron or completely nonsensical
but I think I can actually defend that statement throughout the course of this video.
But this is my primary point,
the Death Stranding was advertised and held up as a game that would bring people together.
And I can't help but find it extremely ironic that it is done the exact opposite.
Now as we move forward into the video
I ask that you please hear me out on all the critiques I have for the game.
Furthermore I'd also like for you to
contribute all of your critiques and contributions down in the comments section below.
I will be reading through all of them.
Now if you'd like my concise recommendation
I'd say that you should only play Death Stranding
if you have already been intrigued by it.
Which if you are, chances are you've already played it.
The unfortunate reality is that if you're skeptical of death stranding to any degree
or if there are things that have repelled you thus far,
the game isn't going to convince you otherwise.
And the bizarre thing is that
it seems as though this was a conscious design choice on the part of Kojima Productions.
That or it's just blatant stupidity something that we're gonna discuss in just a moment.
However if there is any chance that you're going to play this game
you should do that first before watching.
Don't worry, this video will still be here once you're done.
Also a couple of things that you should know
I did conduct a massive survey with over 2400 respondents.
Thank you, by the way, for all of you who contributed.
And I will be mentioning it throughout the video.
I have posted all of the data collected from this survey on my website lukestephens.net
so that you can sift through and hold me accountable.
If you want to participate in the next survey for the next critique,
make sure to follow me on Instagram, Twitter and Discord
so that you can be notified of when I publish it.
I also have a section in this video where I go over some descriptive analytics
that I performed on data that I collected while playing.
This is dense and kind of complicated stuff, I get that,
so rest assured that I'm going to try and make it as accessible as possible.
And lastly I want to thank all of these Patreons for funding the creation of this video.
Straight up, it wouldn't have been made
if these people didn't step up and contribute over on Patreon.
Thank you to all of you.
And a special vocal shout-out to Zachary Johnson, Mike Holland,
Christopher Scott and Paige Richardson for their extreme generosity.
Understand that this is a long video
so I have timestamps below so you can jump around to chapters that you find most appealing.
And of course it should go without saying
but this video is going to spoil pretty much everything.
So consider this your spoiler warning.
But with all of that said, let's get into it.
The first impressions that a game gives the player are extremely important.
They're important for a variety of reasons
but chief among them is that they serve to convince players
who are skeptical of the game's quality that they should continue playing.
Now normally for a $60 release,
if somebody has gone through the trouble of paying that amount of money for the game
chances are they're already fairly confident that they're going to enjoy the game.
So what's the point of having an extremely polished first two hours or so
if players are already forking over cash.
Well for one I would hope that the artists creating the game
would want players to be intrigued by the title that they've put forward.
But furthermore, Death Stranding is such a polarizing game,
and the gameplay was such a matter of debate before its release
that many people watched streams and clips of the introductory hours of gameplay
to decide whether or not they were going to try it.
This is … pretty freakin gorgeous.
I mean for real, look at this, Norman Reedus,
the real-time rendering of pubes on a man's face has never looked so good.
And the unfortunate reality for Kojima Productions is that
many people started playing the game and decided to quit within the first few hours.
This is a selection of responses from the survey I mentioned earlier.
Of players who quit playing the game after starting it,
among the chief reasons why people stopped playing
were that they said the first few hours were uninteresting, slow, boring, confusing,
and even not as advertised.
Now it's fair that every game is going to have some players who drop off after starting it.
That's completely unavoidable, even for a masterpiece.
But the key takeaway is that going into the game,
the major contention on everybody's minds
were whether or not this game was going to be uninteresting, slow, boring, or confusing.
And the first few hours of the game certainly didn't help these preconceived notions.
But what specifically did Kojima do?
Well, he started the story in a very strategic way,
where Sam is just another porter performing normal deliveries like everybody else.
And it's implied that there's essentially an army of these types of porters
that are delivering packages across the continental United States.
Now I'll be honest, I like this more than the alternative.
Like in the old school God of War games, like God of War three
where you have all of the abilities up front and then they're ripped from you
after you've tasted the forbidden fruit
of what the player could look forward to having later in the game.
But it doesn't change the fact that this starts very slow.
In the opening cutscene, Sam loses his bike.
And you're forced to transport cargo on foot for the first few hours.
Furthermore it goes on for a while.
The first two hours really do feel like a trudge.
And I don't think that this is a controversial thing to say
even if you are a fan of the game.
Again, I enjoyed my time with Death Stranding, but this is simply a reality.
The first few hours, the pacing is all over the place.
There also aren't very many interesting gameplay mechanics introduced here.
In fact the only missions that you're sent on
are to deliver a small package of drugs to a dying president,
assist a corpse disposal crew, you watch some cutscenes,
and then you are asked to incinerate the president's body after she's croaked.
And I don't really have an issue with these types of deliveries.
In fact I actually find them fairly relaxing and satisfying as I mentioned earlier.
But it does reaffirm the stereotype that Death Stranding is just a walking simulator,
especially because there's no real dynamic encounters,
there's no animals that you'll encounter in the world when you're going on these trips.
It's just you, walking with some type of cargo strapped to your back,
trying to keep balance as you walk across a large open field, scattered with rocks,
that are just there to make it slightly tedious for you to walk from point A to point B
Again, not inherently bad, it just reaffirms the preconceived notion
that Death Stranding only has walking to offer in terms of gameplay.
Even though as we'll find out later in the game, there's much more to it.
Now the baseline gameplay loop
is made up of course of transporting cargo from one location to another
or going to one location receiving cargo and returning it, in other words, a fetch quest.
Now some people have heavily criticized the game for the core gameplay loop,
being made up of this very simple task, which I actually disagree with.
Any activity can be turned into a game.
Given enough attention and time whether it's farming, hunting, or even talking,
all of these things can be turned into an experience that's worth playing.
Furthermore, Death Stranding's gameplay system grows more complex over the course of the game.
They had guns, grenade launchers, monster boss fights that are dynamic,
BT zones, and even humanoid enemies known as mules
that track your every movement and can hunt you down.
However, you will need to get past around the 10-hour-mark
to see most of these things in full capacity.
And some of these things such as grenade launchers
aren't even introduced until 25 to 30 hours in.
And this is one of the necessary frustrations with Death Stranding,
and it's a result of the studio that made it.
Like many Japanese titles your time is required to buy into the world and the gameplay.
And I actually have a few examples.
Monster Hunter World for instance is a Japanese action RPG that I love to death.
And it requires a steep learning curve and a lot of effort on the player's part
if you want to learn what all of the different components are
that contribute to a fully mid maxed build.
I've put in roughly a hundred hours into Monster Hunter World
and I'm still learning new things that the game has to offer.
Or look at Persona 5's introductory section
that can last by itself 15 to 22 hours depending on your play style and pace.
And yes, that's considered the introduction.
The point is, Japanese game development is different than westernized game development.
Their games tend to have a lot of meat to them
and they require a lot of time on the player's part
in order to buy into and understand everything that there is to offer.
And this actually causes a lot of Western players to be turned off by these types of games.
Like it or not, western gamers are very impatient.
And if a game is not grabbing a player within the first hour or even maybe two hours,
they're just gonna walk away.
And I don't think there's anything wrong with that,
it's just a feature of our culture I suppose.
But the point is Kojima even knew this,
which is why he roasted Americans for not having the quote-unquote "artistic sensibilities"
on the level required to appreciate games such as Death Stranding to their fully extent.
And here's confession time, I live in the United States, in Colorado.
I'm a western gamer through and through,
and I am used to most of the coolest stuff in a game being front loaded
to make sure that my attention is captured, to show me what they have to offer.
Look at Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order,
the first two hours are polished to high heaven and they are great.
Or The Witcher 3, where the Griffin fight is front-loaded as with some …
butts … which naturally sold me on it.
Or Grand Theft Auto 5 where the robbery sequence is front loaded
to show you what you can look forward to later in the game.
The point is, a majority of AAA western titles,
specifically the ones that are critically acclaimed,
often feature front loaded gameplay sequences.
Like it or not it's sort of a standard of Western titles at this point.
And the strange thing is that Death Stranding kind of meets this halfway.
What I mean is that the gameplay system is not very robust,
or extremely dense and complicated,
requiring hours upon hours of intensive research and studying to understand it.
Rather it's pretty simple,
and just requires the player to mindlessly deliver packages from point A to point B.
What does require a huge amount of investment on the part of the player is the narrative.
For instance, the best moment in this introductory section
is the Voidout that we get to witness up-close.
It's bizarre and fantastic.
Really, there are a lot of interesting things here
and we're gonna go over them in detail in just a few minutes.
Now I don't know about you but when I saw this first
I was concerned that they weren't actually going to have answers
for most of the things that they were showing.
But they actually do, and it looks like Kojima thought most of this through
at least in as bizarre way as you would expect from Kojima.
You just have to wait roughly 38 hours to get those answers.
Other problems also arise due to the fact
that the game was developed narratively and written in Japanese
and then it was "ported" … get it? … over to English.
This is actually incredibly important to understand
and I think it's a reason why a lot of the writing in Death Stranding has been panned.
This is a Japanese written story.
Thus the dialogue is translated from the original writings of Kojima and his team
into English for the actors.
And this can at times lead to some really strange and clunky phrasings.
But don't worry we'll get to this more later.
Now you could argue that Death Stranding front-load some of its more flashy cinematic sequences
and I think that that's fair to say
especially with that Voidout sequence that we just looked at.
But in my opinion front-loading gameplay would have been a better idea
due to gamers' preconceived notions that the game is slow and has uninteresting gameplay.
I don't know, that's just my opinion though, let me know your thoughts below.
Beyond this, even with elaborate cutscenes shown off that are very flashy interesting
and even visually intriguing shall we say,
these first 2 hours of Death Stranding are very bland, And even downright confusing,
which i think is actually okay because it is a prologue after all.
And I think if a prologue wasn't at least somewhat confusing and intriguing
it probably wouldn't be doing its job.
But from here the story progresses.
Mostly through cutscenes featuring the main cast,
people like Sam, Fragile, Amelie, Mama, Deadman, Die-Hardman
Heartman, Higgs, Cliff and some others.
Some of these scenes are actually really well acted.
I mean there's a reason that Mads Mikkelsen won the game award for best performance.
But some other scenes are … well … not.
For instance, Léa Seydoux's scenes are universally awesome in spite of the writing.
Not because of I think that's important to understand.
I'm fragile
In fact, her scenes are even up there with Mads Mikkelsen's, which I think is high praise.
She has a very dry and yet emotional way of delivering her dialogue.
And while it does seem stilted at times
I think that's mostly a result of the dialogue she's being fed.
There's no question that most of these actors are highly qualified to be in this piece
whether you're looking at Mads, Léa or Norman,
all of these guys are qualified and are very talented performers.
So perhaps I'm being unreasonable,
but to me it seems fair to blame most of the stilted lines and delivery
on the direction and the writing as opposed to the performances.
However some of the performances that we see are downright bizarre and laughably bad.
In my opinion, one of the worst performances we see in the game is that of Bridget / Amelie.
These scenes are bizarre, they're staged strangely,
they're written in extremely verbose ways.
And they're presented in a manner that makes it seem like it should be very profound,
yet it appears to the viewer almost comedic.
In fact at the end of the game Amelie rambles for roughly 40 minutes,
slathering the player in unprompted exposition.
And when I was playing this for the first time I was actually in my bedroom,
and my fiancee Nikki was sitting on the bed watching me play.
And, well, this was her reaction to Amelie
finally finishing one of her 10 minute monologue diatribes.
10 minutes to go?!
And a lot of things actually follow this trend in Death Stranding:
inexplicably bad pacing, dialogue and hilariously weird directorial choices.
有些人可能会辩解说这是小岛的风格
Now some people will say that this is just Kojima's style.
他们这样说是为了给游戏古怪的设计辩护
They say this to defend the game's more eccentric design choices,
而这对我来说简直太怪了
and this is one of the weirder things to me.
这些人完全是在为没有任何意义的东西辩护
People are defending something that doesn't hold any weight themselves.
我指的"游戏中的奇怪设定"是说
What I mean is that of all of the things to conceive as weird design choices,
比如游戏角色拉屎的时候给你插播一条广告
it would be something like a planted ad while a character in the game goes poop.
这种设定大家都会觉得是"奇怪"的
That seems like something we could all agree is a weird thing to include.
但这时候一些小岛的狂热粉丝就会跳出来说"这是小岛的风格"
But the hardcore Kojima fans will defend this as part of his style,
说些"不喜欢就是没理解"这些难懂的话
and if you don't like it you simply don't get it.
我真不想在这再解释这些了
Now I don't need to explain that ad nauseam,
这明显就是一种诉诸权威谬误
the fact that this is an appeal to authority fallacy.
完全无法理解 愚蠢至极
It's completely incomprehensible and in fact it's the height of stupidity.
不过我相信如果你已经看到这了
Chances are if you've made it this far into this video,
那你肯定不是那种张口闭口就是"不喜欢就是没理解"这些话的玩家
you're not the type of person that's going to be defending a choice like this
with the defense that if you don't like it you just don't get it.
我还是要强调一下
I can't reiterate this enough.
一个东西好坏跟是不是作者风格没关系
Just because it's his style doesn't mean that something is good.
比如我现在就可以搞个风格 比如录所有的东西都不做剪辑
For instance I can have a style that's very unique like filming everything without cuts
或者所有画面都加个贼辣眼睛的滤镜
or having an extreme color grade placed on all of my footage.
这可以叫我的风格
This may be my style,
但你并不能说这种风格在当前情况下就是最好的
but that doesn't always mean that it's the best option in a given situation.
这就是为什么多数大导演都有自己的风格 但仍能灵活多变
This is why most great directors have a style but they remain flexible.
无论是在应用他们的风格 还是在应用其风格的内容方面
Either in the application of their style or in the content to which they apply their style.
那些差点杀死你的 会使你变得更怪异
What doesn't kill you make you stranger
Joker~
无脑给你做的各种事情上搞点噱头
To mindlessly apply some sort of gimmick on everything that you do
然后说这是我的风格
claiming that it's your style
在我看来算不上什么艺术表达
doesn't seem like an artistic expression to me.
更像是在摆烂
It seems like a crutch.
但这只是你看到的小岛周围这种饭圈行为例子之一
But this is just one example of this sort of sycophantic fanboy ism
that you see that surrounds Kojima.
简直迷惑行为
It's really bizarre.
我都不知道这帮脑残粉到底是杰夫·基思利请的一帮水军
And I don't know if it's just an army of accounts that Geoff Keighley has created
还是真实存在的大活人
or if there are actual people out there that
小岛放个屁都是香的
defend everything Kojima does as holy and infallible.
有请我们的行业标杆——小岛秀夫先生!
( Please welcome our industry icon, ) Mr. Hideo Kojima
总之 这种行为真的很缺乏理性
But regardless it is the height of irrationality.
Even now I'm sure if you look in the comments section of this video you're going to see people
defending things that Kojima did in this game and problems with Death Stranding,
saying that "if you don't like it, you just don't get it".
Now if you don't know what Stockholm Syndrome is,
it's basically when somebody develops feelings of admiration or respect for someone with whom
they should have negative feelings.
So I'm going to call what we're seeing with these sick of fantic Kojima fans "Kojima Syndrome".
Maybe somebody else has come up with a name for this that's more fitting but …
I'm calling it "Kojima Syndrome" because it's like Stockholm Syndrome
and I find it kind of funny.
Let's try applying this to several examples.
There are little to no animals in the game.
Even though we see a plethora of them in the introductory cutscene of the title.
Is this a lazy short coming due to technical restraints or budgetary restrictions?
Or is it a meta discussion of the emptiness of nature without conscious life
and mankind's role within nature on a larger scale?
Who can say? Kojima Syndrome!
Or the fact that all of the boss fights are extremely clunky
and don't actually put the player in much physical danger
with the extremely generous reload system that they've put in place with the repatriation.
Again, is this just bad gameplay design? A shortcoming of the development team?
Or is it a statement on the helplessness of man in the face of death?
Kojima Syndrome!
Or lastly, the fact that you mostly interact with humans through holograms,
copy and pasted throughout the world whenever you deliver products back and forth.
Is this simply lazy copy and pasted content to speed up development and get a game out quickly?
Or is it a commentary on how reliant we are on technology that brings us all together?
Again, Kojima Syndrome.
If you're not convinced of this that's fine.
Just keep an open mind moving forward through the next few sections.
But I do have many more examples of when Kojima Syndrome rears its ugly head.
But having said all of that I want you to know
that I do have some fond feelings for Death Stranding.
I found my time relaxing even rejuvenating.
But there are objectively bad elements the Death Stranding has that deserve to be called out.
Kojima isn't immune to criticism, just because Konami screwed him over.
And despite largely enjoying my time of the game
I do have an obligation to call these things out and to critique the game fairly.
So while it may seem that I'm only criticizing the game remember that
for one this is a critique, and that's well kind of the point.
And two I enjoy Death Stranding writ large, and I'll be elaborating more on those parts later.
Overall the game is interesting and it lays out some original ideas.
But initial impressions don't do much to help it.
But I don't ever settle for the surface level,
and if you've watched this channel you'll be well aware of that.
So, let's go through the whole game.
I know this may seem like overkill and excessively detailed
but if any game ever deserved such a deep dive it would be this,
the most polarizing game of this generation.
So the game consists of 15 main story driven chapters,
each of which contain a plethora of orders that you need to complete.
They are as follows the prologue Porter,
and then episodes Bridget, Amelie,
Fragile, which is by far the longest chapter in terms of content and orders to be completed,
Unger, Mama, Deadman, Clifford, Heartman, Higgs, die Hardman Clifford Unger Bridges,
Sam Strand, Lou, and the last chapter Tomorrow is in your hands,
which is sort of a chapter but also not, we'll talk about this more in a minute.
Now most people including the official Death Stranding wiki moderators
tend to separate all of these episodes into one of three acts.
Act 1 is the prologue through Episode 4,
Act 2 is Episodes 5 through 10,
and Act 3 is Episodes 11 through 14
with Episode 15 being the perpetual end game state of the game
which again we're gonna address later.
Now each act has its own focus.
Act 1 is focused on introducing the gameplay systems and the story,
and in my opinion this is the shortest and worst of all the three acts.
This is often what people are talking about
when they say most players have to get over the hump.
Act 2 is gameplay focused,
and it introduces a ton of new areas both visually and in terms of gameplay.
It features upgraded equipment and really lets the line out for the player.
This section is the most dynamic
because the player can add in as many of these standard ordered quests as they want,
or they can engage with the dynamic quests which are centered around
finding other players abandoned packages and delivering them to their original destinations.
These can be as numerous or as scarce as the player wants.
It's a nice way of reminding the player that there are other people that exist in the world
even if you don't see them which is what we're going to talk about later.
But to be honest I really like this.
The idea that if I drop a package it's not a total loss.
And that somebody else may come along pick it up and deliver it for me.
They'll get likes out of it which is the social currency that features in Death Stranding,
and I will also get some likes because my package has been delivered.
It's the basic you scratch my back I'll scratch yours mechanic
that you see in many many games.
But in this case it's used to make the player feel as though
they're connected with players from around the world
who they will never see, speak to, or interact with
in any way other than these indirect interactions,
through signs, pieces of equipment that you craft
such as generators zip lines post boxes and the like.
And of course also these packages that you pick up dynamically throughout the world.
Now in terms of specific placement of all of these things,
it seems pretty random and I actually did a lot of math to back this up
which again we'll talk about later.
I know I'm saying that for everything but I promise we'll get to it.
Act 3 is narratively focused with lots of smaller sections pieced together.
As many varied chapters in all different locations
that span from World War I to World War II, to Vietnam all the way to a snowy mountain site.
These really are the narrative reward for the players who have made it this far,
this far, being roughly 20 to 25 hours.
There are a ton of very long cutscenes
that span anywhere from 5 minutes to 15 to 40 minutes long.
So make sure you've got your popcorn popped before you head into the last few chapters.
But I do want to say there are some fantastic performances as I said earlier.
I'm looking at you Mads.
Now through all these chapters you're exploring the map,
Death Stranding was of course made with the Decima Engine
which is the same engine that was used for Horizon Zero Dawn
which itself featured a plethora of highly varied biomes
and made the world feel as though it spanned a much larger area than it actually did.
And I might be picky but it seems as though this world really isn't as varied
as it was initially made out to be.
Even though it's meant to span effectively the entire United States,
it really doesn't feel extremely large.
In fact at the very end of the game one of your final assignments
is to cross back over every square inch of the map that you've traveled
to get back to the east coast on foot.
I like the meta implications of this assignment
because it makes you go back and see how far you've come.
But when I was doing this I realized it only took me 20 to 30 minutes to travel all that way.
And again maybe I'm being picky,
but it seems as though for a map that's supposed to represent the entire United States,
it really isn't very big.
But I digress.
We'll discuss that more later in the gameplay section
when we address the worlds layout and construction.
But for now let's discuss the opening of the game.
As I stated earlier, the opening of Death Stranding isn't very effective.
But this does beg the question: what would be effective?
Now by effective, I mean what do the opening hours have to achieve
and in order to convince players skeptical and not
that it's actually worth playing past these opening hours.
Now in my estimation it seems that for each game
this is going to be different depending on the context.
What I mean is that the opening hours of Fallout 4 or Cyberpunk 2077 are going to be different
depending on how they were pitched.
The public's perception of the company that's publishing and creating the game.
And it can even be influenced by something as generic as the price tag.
For a $60 game for instance, one would expect an extremely expansive polished experience.
Whereas if Kojima were to only charge $40 for Death Stranding,
people would go into it with a lesser expectation.
This is why Naughty Dog when they released the Lost Legacy
which was actually a standalone Uncharted game even though most people haven't heard of it,
they were able to get away with an experience that's only 6 hours long
and is very very narrow compared to that of Uncharted 4,
all because they only charged $40 for the game out of the gate.
They set the expectation and then the game was able to live up to that expectation.
With Death Stranding, there are a lot of preconceived notions
that players have and had going into it.
To me it seems as though Death Stranding should have tried to convince a lot of skeptical people
that the game isn't that which its critics claim it to be.
Of course fans of Kojima's work were going to be interested regardless.
They were going to play it all the way through no matter what.
And this is reflected in the pole that I took of players of Death Stranding.
But new players have to be convinced of its worth.
And I don't even think this is a controversial thing to say
but I'm sure there will be some disagreeing in the comments.
But at least hear me out.
Specifically what I mean is that Death Stranding has to prove that
死亡搁浅必须证明其拥有有价值的游戏循环流程
for one, it has a rewarding and worthwhile gameplay loop;
and for two, the narrative makes sense and has been thought through.
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑
Specifically number one because this was referred to as a walking simulator
by many before launch,
which I actually disagree with, but again I'll discuss that later.
I know I've said that a thousand times but I will.
The point is for new players coming in such as myself
having had no major experience to Kojima other than with PT and smaller projects,
they are going to have this in mind from the very beginning.
they're going to be approaching Death Stranding with the preconceived idea
that it is a walking simulator with gameplay that's unsatisfying and boring.
All Kojima would have to do is create the opening hours of Death Stranding in such a way
that players would be convinced that
there was more to this gameplay system than initially seemed present.
Kojima could have done this in a plethora of ways.
For one he could have started the game with a massive BT battle,
not just a cutscene of it, but an actual gameplay system
showing how you can fight these things as you do later on.
Or he could have kept the large cutscene that shows off these BTs in the first couple of hours
and just added some interactive parts to it,
quickTime events in effect, same thing that Naughty Dog does with all of their games.
Again nobody was skeptical of the fact
that Kojima had a really beautiful and bizarre world to play with in Death Stranding.
What they doubted was the gameplay that backed that story up.
Now some of you may think that all of these things shouldn't be very important.
But this is what is either going to hook players into a 50 hour playthrough
or rappel players after a single hour of playing.
And before the pedantic comment comes along where somebody says
that an hour isn't enough time to determine if the game is good or not,
I respectfully disagree it, should be enough.
An hour is a long time after all.
Though often the pacing of a game can be so awful that the first hour is terrible
yet the later sections are great.
But I will admit that this is a personal preference.
Some people are willing to grind through dozens upon dozens of hours of content
before they get to the meat of the game,
while I personally think that that's unacceptable.
Regardless this all should be easy enough to do, right?
Kojima should be able to create an opening sequence that pulls people in.
He just would have had to show players some flashy gameplay,
and hook them with an intriguing narrative mechanism.
But no, Kojima completely fails at this, and I think I can convince you.
To do this, I want to go through the opening sequence of the game.
And I'm actually going to keep these two things that Death Stranding has to prove up on screen.
死亡搁浅必须证明其拥有有价值的游戏循环流程
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑
That way as we go through this
死亡搁浅必须证明其拥有有价值的游戏循环流程
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑
you can consistently ask yourself whether or not these checks are being met.
Because like it or not this is the mental check that players are going to be applying
as they go through the opening sequence consciously or not.
Death Stranding opens with what is presented as a profound quote from Kobo Abe's poem "Nawa" …
I don't know if I'm pronouncing that name right …
I'm gonna be perfect Kobo Abe's … Kobo Abe … I have no idea.
Regardless it's not that relevant at the moment.
And even when it is explained and tied back into the narrative,
it fails to feel completely and truly profound,
specifically when Deadman quotes it at the very end of the game.
总统一定知道会发生这样的事。
很讽刺，不是吗？
引发危机的这把枪，最后成为了拯救你的关键。
亚美莉……她说过这把枪有别的用处。
它不是武器，是救生索，就像棍棒变成了绳子。
我想可以这么说吧……
After the excerpt is shown and plays off,
the credits rolling with a ton of beautiful landscape shots,
and I don't know about you
but initially I thought these were all in engine or in-game screenshots or clips
to show us the lands that we were going to be exploring as we went through the game,
and I got really excited.
However upon further investigation it actually turns out
according to most people on the forums I've read through
the consensus seems to be that these are actually the reference photos
that Kojima Productions took when they did a company trip to Iceland
to get reference photos for the landscapes within the game.
They put in some references to the later games such as the Chiralium hands and things,
but … there really isn't much here, it's just photos of landscapes.
Regardless, it's pretty and it shows you what they were trying to mimic,
and the fact that it looks as though it could be in engine says everything.
It's really impressive that the engine is able to push things that could look this good.
Even if in effect and in practice when you're playing through the game,
they don't hold up to this standard.
After these shots, the game opens up with Sam Porter riding a motorcycle
across a lush green rocky mountain side.
It's really pretty, and it shows just what kind of cinematic experience you're in for.
It's raining, and this rain you'll come to find out is known as "Timefall",
which makes everything it touches age at an extremely fast rate.
This has a ton of implications on game play in addition to the story
but again we'll get to that later.
As he's riding you see the timefall take effect on his hair, the grass, the plants,
and of course the animals that you see running across the mountainside.
Even though you're not going to see hardly any of these things later on,
it's still really cool and it shows you just what this rain can do.
Sam speeds off and then all of a sudden …
Yeah, you seemingly run into her.
Turns out she can teleport away to a beach which is this game world's effective purgatory.
Basically when somebody dies they go to their own Beach,
and this is the intermediate place between this life and the afterlife.
Some people in this world can actually interact freely with their beaches
and use it to teleport around or to even at times come back from the dead
which is what is referred to in the game as "Repatriation",
Sam, being one of them which is how the game explains
how you can die in gameplay and come back to life.
Regardless the bike goes over the side of a cliff and is destroyed.
However if you know anything about video games,
you'll realize that you will eventually get access to one of these soon enough,
because why the hell not?
The developers spent all this time making the bike,
surely they would not just have done that for a cutscene.
Realizing that you now have to travel on foot,
you collect the packages that fell off and you start walking.
You eventually stumble into a cave and you talk with fragile of it.
Here it's explained that Sam cries whenever he's exposed to something called Chiralium,
and fragile has the same allergic reaction.
We also see our first "BT", or "Beached thing".
Yeah, Kojima loves his abbreviations as you'll see.
Now these don't make a lot of sense to new players …
'hell maybe they don't even make sense to late-game players.
But mostly they don't try to explain these things at all in the opening sections of the game.
They leave it all up to the imagination of the player
and ask them just to take it on blind faith that this makes sense.
One would think that if a story features monsters who are invisible,
and apparently have hands as feet, and consents life-forces and pastime with their touch,
that they would have some sort of massive or mind-blowing explanation
of how these things came into existence, what they are, their role in the world,
and how the people that inhabit the world, interact with them.
No I'm not saying that Kojima Productions has to explain all of these things immediately.
In fact I think that would make a pretty terrible story
if everything was exposed at all at once.
But it does make Death Stranding appear as though
it is suffering from a severe case of "lost-itis".
Namely that they were doing and establishing really weird things in the world
just because it looked cool and was crazy and eye-catching.
This is actually something that the developers over at Guerrilla Games,
the creators of Horizon Zero Dawn, hazard against vehemently.
In fact if you watch the documentary explaining how they created Horizon Zero Dawn
you'll hear them discuss what they call "the rule of cool".
This is basically the idea that you should never put something in the game
just because it's cool.
And this is also true of the story.
If you start falling victim and prey to the rule of cool,
all of a sudden the game is going to be nothing but dinosaurs that shoot lasers
and have flamethrowers and everybody is half-naked.
It's gonna get out of hand really quickly.
Furthermore, you can get yourself into a lot of trouble
trying to write your way out of this hole.
The TV show Lost ended up in this exact position.
When they had a lot of really cool crazy things they were showing off,
even though they had no idea how they were going to explain it later on.
Now some people will just accept this writ large.
They'll accept that it makes sense within the world,
and they'll experience the game the way that the writer wants them to.
However the reality is that a lot of players are extremely skeptical of Kojima
and his writing ability.
So love it or hate it this doesn't do much of anything to convince players
who were skeptical of Kojima and the world that he's established here
that he's actually thought everything through and that this makes sense.
And I suffered from this fear as well.
As I play through these opening hours,
the fear was real that they hadn't actually backed up any of this stuff.
I mean seriously how are they possibly going to explain a bunch of babies
that are carried around in tanks on people's bellies
or monsters that swim in tar that somehow disappears instantly
after some arbitrary distance has been achieved.
But I'm happy to report thankfully Kojima did think all of this stuff through,
and he does have some answers as to why these things work the way they do
even if they are vague and kind of insane.
However as to whether or not those answers are good is another question entirely.
And this is a slight tangent but we need to discuss this at some point so why not now.
With a world as strange as Death Stranding's, players rightly have a certain expectation.
Namely that the world is thought-out and consistent.
No one cares if a world is unrealistic or crazy
that's never held back sci-fi or fantasy stories before.
Rather, we just ask that the world live according to the rules that are supposed to govern it.
For instance if you were watching Star Wars,
and the evil Sith Lord is chilling out on a spaceship with a bunch of aliens,
while sensing other people's energy using a magical power called the Force,
and traveling at Lightspeed through an imaginary galaxy, you wouldn't care!
Because the laws of the universe that that story takes place within allow that.
But if the Sith Lord all of a sudden was able to freeze time itself
by beatboxing and rubbing his nipples, you would immediately be turned off …
Well … maybe not in … in that way, but nevermind!
Point is you have to be consistent.
I'm fine with Death Stranding having magical interdimensional whales,
rain that causes time to pass at crazy fast rates and even Norman Reedus.
But all I ask is that it's thought out and justified.
Anyways moving on.
Once you're done talking with fragile you grab up your stuff and deliver it to the city.
You walk through a beautiful Valley as music plays and you enter it.
This music is really peaceful the scenery is beautiful.
But again, you're just walking with a package on your back.
Does this achieve either of the two things outlined earlier?
死亡搁浅必须证明其拥有有价值的游戏循环流程
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑
I don't think so.
As you walk into the complex, you realize that the compound is actually remarkably bland.
死亡搁浅必须证明其拥有有价值的游戏循环流程
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑
And it looks dead, there's no one here.
In fact pretty much everyone we're going to be talking to
in any of these places throughout the entire 50 hour campaign,
they're all gonna be Holograms.
We're not even going to meet them in person for reasons.
Again, Kojima syndrome.
You assisted body disposal crew and take a dead body out of the city to have it incinerated.
You don't know exactly what the big deal is but they seem to be taking it very very seriously.
So, you play along.
There really isn't any player control here you at one point can control the camera
while you're watching a cutscene play out.
I guess this was their way of avoiding a 40-minute cutscene again?
But it is still a cutscene so … it doesn't really do it for me.
You drive out of the city and eventually your car is assaulted and crashes.
Here along cutscene plays that introduces us to Higgs
who's named after the Higgs boson, a nerdy reference that I appreciated way too much.
And this cutscene raises a lot of questions,
but I think it achieved something very good, at least for a video game.
It's intriguing who is this guy, Higgs, what is he doing,
why can he fly, how is he summoning these monsters,
why does the rain make this guy turn old instantly,
why did the guy start stabbing himself trying to kill himself
the second that he started getting lift in the air,
why is he being lifted in the air,
why is it that when bodies begin to decompose they start shaking violently,
what the hell is this.
All of these are fair questions
and I think they motivate the player to want to play more to have these questions answered.
Again the role of a prologue I think often
is to pose a lot of these questions to the reader player or whoever is experiencing them.
I don't think they have to all be answered
and I wouldn't even want them to all be answered in the opening sequence.
However with Death Stranding's specific circumstance,
this doesn't do much to shake the preconceived notion again,
死亡搁浅必须证明其拥有有价值的游戏循环流程
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑
that this is all just crazy and done for the sake of being cool.
死亡搁浅必须证明其拥有有价值的游戏循环流程
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑
Anyway, a bunch of weird stuff happens.
This results in a massive crater and a handprint indentation in the land.
This is actually why everybody throughout the game freaks out
whenever you actually kill someone with a lethal weapon.
Again I know I've said this a thousand times but more on this later.
There's some cutscenes and exposition
but essentially you meet some more characters such as Deadman.
You get given drugs to deliver to the president because she's dying I guess, and needs heroin.
And so you deliver them.
You're in the Oval Office, but it's also a hospital at the same time.
You talk with the president who it said also raised you.
It's implied it's your mother but it's also left ambiguous enough that
it could just be a woman who raised you.
But regardless, you go through the sequence a cutscene plays out
as she explains how you need to help them save the world by connecting things I guess.
While this has happened to the president ask that everybody leave the room
so that it's just Sam and the Madam President.
And then she kind of freaks out.
She tackles him falling out of the bed in one of the clunkiest and worst blocked scenes
I've ever seen in any entertainment medium … like ever.
Seriously, even if you love Death Stranding's story,
how can you defend this … like it's … it's so bad.
Just watch this clip, this is from my roasting video.
Okay clearly she's dying, but I swear to xxx,
if she dies during this cutscene, I'm gonna scream.
I hate coincidences like … sweared mother …
Oh Je … what? … What???
Why is she on the floor crowl' …
Ohhhhh oh my god …
Oh my go … she died oh I …
I gotta … I gotta calm down, I know, but it's like so stupid!
I hate it when stories do this,
when they're like a character is dying go meet with them.
You meet with them and it just so happens during that like three-and-a-half minute time period
where you went and said hello, they died, because it's convenient for the story like …
Why isn't it that you leave, say goodbye, and then she has a heart attack.
and … I just … come on!
Oh well … then again! Kojima Syndrome!
Check the comments I'm sure you'll see many people defending it
So she dies and after this you learned that you need to take her body to the incinerator
to avoid what happened in the earlier scene.
You load her up and you take her to the incinerator's location.
It's actually a really peaceful sequence.
After you've strapped her up, there's a little ribbon blowing in the breeze.
And you're walking across an expansive green pasture covered in rocks,
as a nice calming piece of music plays.
It's actually pretty relaxing, but again!
死亡搁浅必须证明其拥有有价值的游戏循环流程
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑
人们先入为主地认为游戏只是步行模拟器的观念有没有动摇？没有
Does it do anything to shake the preconceived notion that this is a walking simulator? No.
Now while you're delivering the president's body to the incinerator
死亡搁浅必须证明其拥有有价值的游戏循环流程
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑
you've also been asked to take a BB, or a baby and a jar,
to this location, to have it also decommissioned.
You're not told a whole lot except that this is malfunctioning and it's no longer in use.
However before Sam has a chance to do this, BT show up.
And you use this BB to escape the area.
Again, Kojima loves his acronyms.
And I actually really like this sequence.
This is the one moment where the player actually feels as though
there's going to be more to the game than just a walking system.
However it's over before it even begins.
Seriously I was able to get out of here within about thirty seconds.
In my humble opinion, it seems as though
Kojima Productions should have spent a lot more time showing off what the BT system could do,
and how the gameplay could be extremely varied.
But regardless I think this BT sequence is really pretty.
I think it serves a purpose and I really like it so … thumbs up!
You escape, make it back and you learned that you need to
quote unquote "expand the Chiral Network", to fulfill Bridget's vision for America.
You're also introduced to Amelie which is a character that is … PAINFULLY unlikable
and has less charisma than a summer squash.
I know that this is probably more personal,
but I found her performance is all extremely stiff.
But again, I don't know if this is just her fault for performing poorly,
or if this is a writing issue and came from the direction of Kojima.
Again! Kojima Syndrome!
Now a quick sidebar, the characters are all asking Sam to cross
the entire country an extremely
dangerous post-apocalyptic country mind
you and save it and while they're doing
this they're all stiffer than me during
Rocky Horror Picture Show what's pushing
players at this point what's pushing Sam
we've been told that we need to help
connect America after a major event
known as the Death Stranding okay we
know that Amelie is Sam's sister even
though they don't seem particularly
infatuated or caring of each other but
okay to me it seems as though the
operative question is whether or not
this world america in this case is worth
saving where's the humanity that is
worth saving and this is actually my
biggest problem with death straining the
game writ large it fails to give the
player any clear evidence that the world
is actually worth saving that all of
this trouble is worth it now I get it
there are not that many people now that
the world has ended basically but still
there are very few moments that attempt
to humanize these delivery recipients
I mean hell if you're gonna ask the
player to go through the trouble of
delivering packages mindlessly back and
forth between locations it seems like
you should at the very least try to
emotionally motivate them to do so
however all of your interactions with
all of the people that you interact
with these deliveries show up as
Holograms you don't even get to see them
in person but again was this a result of
poor gain design lazy copy and pasted
formatting of locations and interactions
or is it a meta discussion on the
hopelessness that people have and how
empty the world is without connections
again
Kojima syndrome the clearest example of
Kojima seemingly attempting to humanize
this world and failing miserably is when
you're delivering things to the scrapper
you see he has a woman that he loves and
that he thinks is dead you find out that
she's alive
but her performance has got to be the
worst I've ever seen in a triple-a title
I'm not joking I'm not trying to be
funny I'm not trying to be mean
this is just awful
and I get it English is probably not her
first language but this performance is
one of if not the worst I have ever seen
truly horrible nothing personal it's
just that bad watch
are you hurt thanks bridges I can't
believe you're alive that's my life City
I thought you were dead
my mom told me you're getting close
always
but after the attack it stopped working
I thought about fixing it getting the
sand flowing again but it felt too much
like moving on like forgetting you well
now I can boss move on together you and
me if you're ready
of course damn I knew this hazard jump
he fixed the things made him like new
again
picking up sub pieces in the makings are
most of them that's what I do best - but
this is one piece we don't need now this
could have been a moment to prove to the
player that they're still loving caring
people in this world instead we're left
thinking that maybe we should put these
people out of their misery because
clearly they're poisoned with arsenic
now I know I'm being harsh but this
happens repeatedly throughout the story
where there's a chance for the small
characters to prove that this world is
worth saving but they universally fail
again the question seems to me is the so
writing issue on the part of Kojima is
it his fault is it a directorial fault
again landing on the shoulders of Kojima
or is it just that their performances
are that bad with this particular
instance I think you could say the
performance is just that bad but at the
same time Hideo is the one that would
presumably have cast this woman in this
role so again the fault still lands on
his shoulders point is I think that this
is inexcusably bad and whether Kojima
was happy with this performance and this
narrative structuring in the way that
you interact with these smaller
characters the blame still lands on
Kojima shoulders now thankfully the main
cast is phenomenal and they try very
hard to deal with the wordy and at times
nonsensical
that Hideo threw at them Sam cliff
fragile mama dead man Hartman die
Hartman Higgs they're all fantastic
pretty much with the exception of Amelie
/ Bridget I think the main cast is
pretty solid and it makes sense they're
the main cast for a reason but when
you're trying to motivate the player to
save an entire country because they want
to save the country you have to give the
player some reason to love and to care
about said country and its inhabitants
and in my opinion I know that some will
disagree deaths training fails miserably
at humanizing the world that it's trying
to convince you to save furthermore this
world is so void of life it's kind of
ridiculous we see wildlife in the
opening sequence of the game as I
mentioned earlier so we know that it
exists in this world but we never
experience it in the world like ever
or at least I didn't you never see deer
you never see a lot of birds flying
through the sky you never interact with
them in any way there are also very few
original assets in Death Stranding a lot
of things are repeated from the repeated
bunkers to vehicles to landscapes to
rock formations to mule camps everything
is just copy and pasted around the map
now we'll get into this in detail a lot
more later don't worry I've done a lot
of math surrounding the placement of
these items and it's really telling but
the point is it begs the question was
this developed by a small team that
simply didn't have the manpower to put
more stuff into the game or was this a
budgetary concern or was it some
combination or was it part of Kojima's
broader vision again Kojima syndrome
regardless Sam agrees to help expand the
chiral Network begrudge idli at least
and the mid-game begins after a plethora
of tutorial missions that introduce to
you crafting inventory and loadout
management course charting and much much
more it's slow but it's probably
necessary to be perfectly honest before
releasing the players into the mid game
and let me be clear there's nothing
wrong with a long intro sure it can be
frustrating especially during repeated
playthroughs but it isn't inherently bad
look at Assassin's Creed 3 the game bit
has an inch
that lasts roughly three hours before it
even gives you control of a basic
stripped-down assassin that it
advertised pre-launch it's not
inherently bad it's just inefficient the
only reason efficiency is important is
to convince the a fer mentions sceptical
players to continue playing again look
死亡搁浅必须证明其拥有有价值的游戏循环流程
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑
at those two goals I put on screen does
a long dry intro achieve either of these
死亡搁浅必须证明其拥有有价值的游戏循环流程
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑
probably not but I didn't want to just
take all of this on assumption so in the
survey that I conducted again all of the
data is up on Luke Stephens net if you
want to check it out yourself
I asked players who hadn't finished the
game at the time of polling and twenty
eight and a half percent of them said
that they either weren't going to
continue playing or that they were
unsure if they would that's over one in
four players who didn't feel compelled
to continue now no matter how you look
at that no matter how you split it with
a sample size of 2,400 people that is a
straight-up failure of the game's pace
and design I don't care if you're making
a video game a song a movie or a book if
somebody gets just a couple hours into
it just dipping their toes into it and
over 1 in 4 people are unsure or
straight-up reject the idea of
continuing you have failed furthermore
the poll shows that over 36% of players
who gave up on the game had put less
than five hours in and roughly 66% had
played less than 10 hours before
stopping sure you can argue that this
game simply wasn't meant for them or
they were never going to enjoy it no
matter how polished or how much they
reworked the opening sequence but I
think the fact that so many players
dropped out in the first few hours of
playing the game shows that something
was wrong with the first few hours again
these people are paying $60 presumably
to play this game they put their money
on the line which by itself lends these
opinions credibility at least in my
opinion but this brings us to the mid
game were episodes 5 through 10 this
really is deliveries galore you're
slowly expanding the map exploring it
deliver
packages to your heart's content this is
where the game shines this is where the
gameplay reaches its highest potential
you unlock all sorts of new tools
vehicles and things that you can do
crafting and much much more this was the
act of the game that I found myself
enjoying the most mostly because I was
able to just look forward to making some
deliveries and relaxing as I ran across
the open countryside when I got back
from a long day I racked my brain a lot
as to why this was so relaxing to me and
why I enjoyed it because on its face it
really is pretty simplistic sure you
might occasionally encounter some mules
or BTS that require some stealth
approaches to getting around them but
writ large this is just a game about
delivering packages from one location to
the other it is extremely repetitive so
why did I enjoy it it was a little
baffling to me but after a lot of
thought I think it's for the same reason
that hiking is enjoyable because the
game allows you to play it in just
passive enough a state that you can let
your mind wander you'll find yourself
daydreaming about other things as you
explore this vast expanse and it's
relaxing
plus it's no mystery that the world of
Death Stranding is very beautiful
especially in a lot of individualized
places that are heavily trafficked other
less trafficked areas show a significant
lack of polish in terms of the graphic
fidelity but we'll get to that later but
here I'm actually gonna say something
that makes me sound like a fanboy and
that's that if you don't see the appeal
of Death Strandings gameplay system I
think you might need to try it now I'm
not saying that you should go out and
pay $60 for the game or 40 if it's on
sale just to try this and that if you
don't do that your opinion is invalid
that's not what I'm saying what I am
saying is that the relaxing nature of
Death Strandings gameplay is something
that you will only experience if you are
the one doing it in the same way that
watching somebody hike isn't satisfying
in the same way that hiking itself is if
you want to enjoy nature you have to be
the one in it if you want to enjoy the
world of Death Stranding you have to be
the one exploring it this is why for a
lot of people
who say that they watched people played
the game on Twitch and they don't
understand the appeal of the gameplay
system even though the streamer enjoyed
it it doesn't make much sense to me
because having played it it's pretty
self-explanatory if you want to enjoy
the world you have to be the one walking
through it building things in it driving
your motorcycle across it you have to do
it but as to whether or not this is
something that's going to appeal to
everybody is a much larger and more
difficult question to answer and it
seems to me that this is something that
just isn't going to appeal to everybody
which is why I said at the beginning you
should rely on your instincts if the
game has repelled you or has been simply
uninteresting to you it likely isn't
going to change that opinion even after
10 hours anyway throughout the mid game
you make a ton of deliveries you go from
location to location unlocking new areas
and meeting new people I'm hesitant to
use the word exploring even though
that's definitely the word that Kojima
Productions wants you to use for one
because in my mind exploring is
something that you initiate yourself
it's not something that you're pushed to
do just because a quest can ask you to
go from one location to a remote
location to me that doesn't make you
explore those locations that's just
having you traverse to that location
exploring to me seems like something
that you're going to do for the sake of
itself an example would be like in
breadth of the wild when you find
yourself just exploring the world going
through it without any quests without
anything specifically to do just
exploring it for the sake of interacting
with and exploring it it's adventure in
its purest form Death Stranding really
doesn't encourage you to do this ever
there are very few secrets very few
things that you can interact with and of
course there are basically no NPCs or
individuals that you can interact with
within the world that make it worth
exploring but again I know I've said
this a billion times we're gonna talk
about that more at length in just a few
minutes but once we plow through all of
that we get to the finale of the game or
in other words act 3 the
ding that never ends this is comprised
of episodes 11 through 14 and it has big
reveals such as Amelie and Bridget being
the same person okay you find out that
Alma Lee / Bridget are an extinction
entity and that they can bring on the
end of the world which again is okay and
a lot of things are revealed in this
sequence which to be honest I'm not
entirely sure I could explain concisely
even if I spent a week writing it out
chances are if you made it this far into
the video you probably already have a
decent idea of what happens in these
final hours so I won't bore you with
explaining all of it over again the
point is that Kojima actually explains a
lot of the stuff that goes on during
these sequences now don't get me wrong I
think he could have done it in a tenth
the time but I'll take what I can get
there are a few things however I do want
to touch on for instance the endless
cutscenes at the very end of the game
the last three or four hours of the game
are almost exclusively cutscenes or
sequences within which there is very
little player control or interaction
there's no big gameplay finale other
than a large bTW fight I guess you could
say qualifies as a boss fight there's
also the sequence with Haig's fistfight
with them which is clunkier than almost
anything else in the game it's really
terrible
but I don't want to address all of that
I want to talk about the purgatory
cutscenes that Amelie presents to you as
you run around the beach basically
you're sent to your Beach with the help
of fragile and everybody else and you're
just sitting here and they play off some
credits and it's very peaceful and it
does feel like purgatory because as you
run from one end of the beach to the
other you will eventually just get
spawned back further it's basically the
story of Sisyphus and it's actually
pretty cool
I really liked this when I first came to
this area however after the first 10
minutes or so it starts to get pretty
horrible again is this just a poorly
designed way of forcing the player to
sit through all of the credits rolling
incredibly slowly or is this some sort
of meta
discussion of the purgatory that we all
experience when talking about
post-credit scenes in games and move I
don't know point is Kojima syndrome and
every time you get transported back
after a few minutes Amelie will show up
and present a cut sequence where she
offered some exposition again I'm glad
that all of this is here and that it is
expositor and there are reasons that all
of this stuff in this world take place
but I think it could have been done much
more efficiently now after all of this
happened to end up talking with Amelie
at length and there is what vice
referred to as the gameplay mechanic of
the year Thank You Ryan on Twitter for
sending me this I thought this was
pretty funny basically Amelie describes
that she's going to end the world and
that you can stop her or you can not and
let it happen
of course most players are gonna try to
stop her but I don't know let me know
what you did below point is you have a
gun and you can choose to shoot her or
you can run after her and hug her
which is what Vice referred to as the
mechanic of the year now she gives a
bunch of forewarning and she says that
you should have known how this was going
to play out and you know what to do
because it's the entire point of your
journey and looking back on it it makes
sense she's saying that it's all about
connecting people forgiving and
embracing others so going up to her and
hugging her seems like the natural
choice however this didn't work for me
at all
pull the rope or cut the noose but
whatever you do don't hesitate and I
hesitated and I even tried to save
because I decided immediately after she
said I know what to do to shoot her six
times and empty the gun in the back of
her head which doesn't actually do
anything at which point I ran up to her
to try and punch her into submission to
stop the world from ending but that also
didn't work and instead I was prompted
with a hug button at which point I
pressed hug and I was made to feel as
though I just made an incredible and
generous decision when in reality it was
kind of an accident now maybe I'm the
weird one here
but this made the ending sequence really
awkward because it feels as though I
kind of broke it it didn't expect me to
shoot her in the back of the head empty
my rounds and then go up to her trying
to punch her only to find out my only
option was to hug her it was completely
unintentional that I saved the world
which made this all very funny but after
all of this you are saved and the world
doesn't explode and everything's okay
at which point you're eventually saved
by all of the people that have helped
you this far
fragile dead men everybody and this is
actually what those people off in the
distance on the beach are we saw this in
a trailer way back in the day a couple
years ago and it seemed as though it was
an explicable how they ever explained
these people just floating over the
ocean but they actually do explain it
and it's kind of cool and after this Sam
is saved you're brought back to the
world of the living you go to a
presidential inauguration for Die
Hardman and you get some more exposition
but eventually you find out after giving
the president a pep talk that you need
to take Bibi to the incinerator because
it passed away or I guess in dead man's
words it is no longer functioning and
I'll be honest Kojima actually wrote
this pretty well the player had built a
relationship with Bibi having carried it
with him for almost the entire game save
for the sequence where it's removed from
you and it's sad to be walking this
deceased Bibi or dysfunctional Bibi
however you want to phrase it off to an
incinerator davit burn it's kind of a
sorrowful event but I will be honest
it's actually kind of cool to walk back
through where you started for those of
you not aware this is the exact same
path that you walked with Brigid strand
when she died to take her to the
incinerator so effectively the last
mission of the game is mirroring order
three which is cool because that was
basically the first order that you
completed yourself there are no mules no
BTS no threats you're just hiking along
a large green mountainside and it's a
nice way to finish but once you arrive
at the incinerator a cutscene begins
playing which
you a new perspective on the smaller
cutscenes that you've seen throughout
the entire game every time you had a
load screen coming out of a private room
for instance now we get a new
perspective and we see all of these
sequences play out in order and it's
actually pretty heartbreaking this is
the place where Mads Mikkelsen actually
earns his game Award for Best
Performance he really nails it here it's
beautiful it's sweet it's sad it's
endearing it's everything it's
incredibly emotional and I really
enjoyed this but after all of this ends
and you learned that the BBU was Sam and
that Clifford was just trying to correct
his mistakes from his past everything
comes back into the world of the living
and you realize that Lew has been taken
out of the pod and is now cradled in
Sam's hands he's frantically trying to
revive her doing everything that he
possibly can to wake her up however
nothing seems to work and he eventually
gives up cradles her as he begins to cry
at this point after a brief beat you
start to hear Lou crying
she's back Sam is stunned and holds her
in unparalleled jubilation as a bunch of
BT's watched them from the background
which is actually pretty cool because it
seems as though this is what has broken
the cycle of all of these B B's having
their souls effectively destroyed in the
incinerator holding Lu Sam walks out of
the incinerator into the open air and
it's actually raining although the time
fall doesn't seem to be having any sort
of effect it's just normal rain
furthermore there is a full rainbow
behind them which is extremely bright
and also shows the color blue which is
something that none of the other
rainbows in the game show now what does
all of this mean well it seems as though
the Death Stranding has officially come
to a close and B B's revitalization has
effectively restored the stability of
humanity or something however I will be
honest this is so vague that there are
probably a million different ways to
interpret it and it's not particularly
important because everyone will have
their own interpretation which is kind
of the point what I will say is that
it's a very calming peaceful and
emotional end even if I don't completely
understand what's going on
why was BB able to be restored even
though necrotize ation was starting to
set and B B was clearly dead what
brought her back why does the time fall
all of a sudden end at this point why is
blue all of a sudden present in the
rainbow just because a baby came back to
life I'm not entirely sure but again
that's probably not the point I would be
interested however in hearing your
theories as to what exactly happened
when BB was saved here I'm sure some of
you have thought this through and have a
reasonable explanation I would love to
hear it below and then the actual
credits roll and after all of that
happens we are greeted with episode 15
prompted up to us and
a quick reading that shows two weeks
before and this is what I meant earlier
when I said that chapter 15 is basically
indefinite it goes on forever even
though it's just two weeks before the
presidential inauguration this is
effectively Death Strandings endgame
state it goes on forever and it will
allow the player to continue making
deliveries five-star locations find and
hunt down all of the memory chips and
complete any other things that they
might have left undone now overall the
story while it is kind of bizarre and
crazy it is thought through and it does
have justifications and rules that
govern it which is what I said at the
beginning I was looking for however
there are a couple of missed
opportunities I can't help to wonder why
Kojima didn't explore more they might
have been that it just felt like it
wasn't focused or it might have been
something that never occurred to him I'm
not entirely sure specifically something
such as the discussion that has to do
with BB's and slavery this is briefly
touched on but it's not really
elaborated upon specifically babies come
from mothers who died while pregnant
which is why those mothers are called
still mothers there are also other times
that this concept is applied within the
world of Death Strandings such as with
mama who we know was to give birth but
was trapped in rubble after the death
stranding which resulted in the baby
becoming caught between the world of the
living
and the beach or the world of the dead
this is of course why babies are able to
detect BTS and can show them to the
operator that has them strapped to their
bellies
now while Kojima does have a lot of
writing in here that discusses the
inherent value of human life even as a
baby he never really touches on the idea
that you are literally taking an
independent human as prisoner and you're
going to dispose of them once they're no
longer useful as Deadman says it's a
tool
that's cuz we're partners partners Sam a
B B's a tool not a human-being
bridge yes baby no and they don't really
explore this very much they do touch on
the idea pretty aggressively that the BB
is becoming sentient the 3b is becoming
human and it's going to start growing
like a regular human very soon this is
of course why Deadman has to take the BB
away from the player roughly halfway
through the game in order to perform an
operation to separate it from the
humanity that's pulling it out of the
world of the dead and closer to the
world of the living and this is what
partially makes me think that kojima had
thought of this and simply decided to
focus on the more pro-life discussion
having to do with the bb's the idea that
these infants still have value as human
life even though they're just infants
they're contained within a tank they
don't have much of anything by way of
autonomy but they still are valuable so
it could be that Kojima just decided
that the discussion on slavery would
have been too much and wasn't worth
pursuing or maybe he just didn't think
to add it in I'm not entirely sure
either way it could have been cool to
see him explore the idea of beb├ęs being
enslaved to a more powerful master and
not having any way of fighting it or
claiming their own independence I'm not
really sure let me know your thoughts
below another thing that struck me is
weird throughout the course of the story
is the fact that they break the fourth
wall all the time and I'm not entirely
sure why now of course you could say
that this is just Kojima style and
that's what he likes to do so to judge
it is simply unfair however as I
discussed earlier the world that death
straining is taking place within has to
be consistent and it has to live by its
own rules preferably at all times and
for the most part it succeeds in this
the game seems to want players to be
immersed at all times with the realistic
graphics and the traversal system being
very realistic but at the same time
Sam breaks the fourth wall constantly
though in fairness it is mostly
relegated to the private room it feels
weird ride with Norman Reedus AMC
as an ad on the bathroom while he poops
it's really weird and out of place I'm
not really sure why it's here plus if
you leave the camera sitting on him too
long he'll gesture at you and he'll
stare at you make funny faces at you
it's fun but it's weird if I were
directing the game I would have cut all
of this because in my opinion it's not
worth the trouble it pulls the player
out of the game and while you are in a
private room when these things happen I
don't think that that's an excuse though
I will admit that this is probably a
matter of personal preference
some people will mind it such as myself
others don't mind that at all and some
I'm sure really enjoy it now of course
these fourth wall breaks and these think
outside the box mechanics are nothing
new to Kojima as somebody sent me on
Twitter Metal Gear Solid has a sequence
like this when snake is fighting mantis
you actually have to change the port
that the controller is connected into in
order to complete the game and continue
on which is kind of funny imagine doing
that today it's weird because Kojima
talks about being an artistic purist and
describes how he thinks Americans don't
have artistic sensibilities but he's the
one putting paid product placement in
his games with the monster energy drinks
and the AMC ads can you imagine what
people would say if Todd Howard started
putting Tesla ads and fallout or elder
scrolls people would rightly lose their
minds
the only reason Kojima gets a break is
again Kojima syndrome now don't get me
wrong fourth wall breaks can be done
well even in narrative focused games
look at the lost legacy tower sequence
for instance here there's a tower you
can find and there's a very narrow route
that you can climb up optionally and if
you get to the top of it and you hang
out there for an extended period of time
Chloe will start to tease you and will
actually break the fourth wall however
things like the otter hat that you get
from Conan O'Brien with in death
stranding are somehow both weird and
perfectly in place it's really bizarre
but you can't help but feel as though
Kojima didn't take all of this very
seriously which I also to appreciate I
mean their video games and all
customization is like this from changing
paints
two glasses two otter hoods it's all fun
and though it doesn't mean much in the
story it's a welcome addition even if it
doesn't make sense in terms of bridges
having standardized uniforms that
everybody is expected to wear but the
point is while the fourth wall breaks
may bug me I can understand why they
might not bother other people I think it
is a matter of personal preference it
just bothers me though it might not
bother you but with all of that let's
discuss the gameplay and the systems
that make Death Stranding work so
obviously a lot of people have said that
Death Strandings gameplay loop is
quote-unquote boring to determine if
this is true let's look at what your
average mission is going to be comprised
of let's start with story missions in
this case we're going to look at a
random order in the mid game now in this
order we have 60 minutes to collect
medical devices from one character in
the mountainous area and then deliver
them back to the area where we accepted
the order in other words a fetch quest
now this is actually one of the more
elaborate order types that you can get
because it involves multiple stops
simpler orders just give you items with
the destination so you accept the order
and get told that you need to deliver
the items quickly and furthermore that
the items that you're picking up are
classified as fragile which means that
you can't drop the packages often you
can't go in water etc basically you have
to be extra careful you select your gear
and load Sam up with any ladders pcc's
climbing anchors extra boots or weapons
that you may need then you set out and
you begin hiking in this case I'm not
going to use any vehicles because we're
going through a mountainous area and
they aren't particularly useful in this
rocky snowy area this is what would
usually be considered a more difficult
mission specifically because it's in the
snowy mountainous area not once in my
over 100 hours with Death Stranding did
I encounter a mission where I failed the
time limit
the only time I had any difficulty was
when the items were fragile or when I
was completing multiple orders all at
once loading up with four or five orders
at a given time and so the way that the
game dynamically alters the difficulty
is with the routes that they'll have you
do this is why long routes tend to
reward you with more likes and routes
that go into the mountains also do the
same now you can unlock certain items
that makes
traversal and mountain traversal easier
for instance lots of ladders climbing
anchors that you can level up power
gloves the all-terrain exoskeleton and
of course the zip lines which you can
use to set up routes
after you've initially explored them so
with all this in mind I continued hiking
eventually I reached a cliff top where I
could have just dropped a ladder or a
climbing anchor to descend and then
cross by foot but I happen to know that
this area is infested with BTS so I
decided to build a zipline which allowed
me to completely skip this area which
effectively skips five to ten minutes of
navigation don't worry we're gonna go
into a lot of detail with these zip
lines in just a bit I reach to the
bottom and continue hiking eventually I
pick up the items and then the entire
process repeats as you're return
now when you drop off the items you are
graded on the condition that the
packages are in this can be both the
quality of the outside container in
addition to the quality of the internal
item which can experience damage if you
aren't careful for instance if you fall
off of a ladder you'll fall take damage
and the packages will be worth less when
they're eventually delivered there are
however ways to deal with this for
instance with the time fall shelters if
you stay in them and especially once
they're upgraded they'll actually repair
your items as you stand underneath them
there of course also the cargo repair
sprays which you can carry on your back
but this is basically it there isn't
much more to the gameplay system other
than this I know it may come as a
surprise but Death Stranding is not a
third-person shooter it's also not a
monster fighting focused game which
means that all of the combat encounters
that you'll experience are pretty clunky
and now I know about you but every time
I went to one of these flashback
sequences with cliff I was really
excited because they're very visually
impressive you get to travel back to
World War one or World War two or
Vietnam it's very interesting visually
but once you actually engage with the
gameplay you realize that it's just a
shooting gallery and it's not a
particularly difficult one even on the
hardest possible difficulty it doesn't
change much really as long as you're
keeping cover and shooting the enemies
when they appear
which is all the time you're gonna be
fine now as you would expect with the
story the game heavily encourages you to
make sure that you're never using
actually lethal means of taking down
opponents that you're only using
non-lethal means for this reason they
include non-lethal assault rifles which
basically completely negates the
difficulty that would have been put in
place by having a non-lethal requirement
basically these are still guns they just
don't finish the opponent in a death
state instead they're in an
incapacitated state which allows you to
just continue on your merry way I don't
know why they did this because it seems
to undermine their own pursuit of making
sure that the player needs to take a
step above everybody else the player
needs to have non-lethal means of
interacting with enemies such as the
mules because they're better than the
mules but instead you just use assault
rifles that incapacitate them which
completely eliminates any gameplay
difficulty that would have been there as
a result of taking a stealth approach or
a peaceful approach but rest assured
this idea of the game undoing itself is
something we're going to talk about much
more in just a moment but while
discussing these deliveries it's also
important to discuss the map design now
in my mind this is probably the most
important game design element that is
here the mechanics of walking balancing
and using vehicles can all be
fantastically well-designed but if the
world itself is not worthy of being
explored nobody's gonna care now like I
said before there are very few inherent
reasons to explore the world of death
stranding there are no major secrets no
NPCs and only a very few select secret
locations and items to find that make
the player excited and wanting to
explore more for instance in Red Dead
Redemption 2 there are all sorts of
dynamic encounters that you can either
choose to interact with or not but the
world is littered with them which means
that every time you go out to explore
the world you're going to find something
new and interesting it's one of the
reasons the world of Red Dead Redemption
2 feels so alive my favourite example in
RDR too
would of course be the incestuous
siblings where I was just riding through
the map and I encountered this brother
and sister who were very close they try
to kill you and a bunch of really funny
and interesting stuff goes down I won't
spoil it but I highly recommend hunting
them down if you ever in that world or
another example would be the puzzles and
encampments that are hidden all over
breath of the wild they make the world
worth exploring for its own sake now
there are things in deaths training to
find I can already hear you saying it
things such as the memory chips and the
hot springs but I don't think these
actually qualify and I'll explain why in
just a moment the main thing to
understand is that the world of death
stranding isn't particularly well
crafted at least in my opinion and I
have a lot of math to back this up in
fact it seems to me that this map was
dynamically generated with very little
input on the part of the development
staff and they just went with it once
they found a random arrangement that
they liked once they had this they
decided to scatter all of the flat areas
with boulders and streams and I have to
ask why seriously you will be
hard-pressed to find any stretch of
grass that's more than a hundred yards
these rocks after all take a positive
action to create somebody has to put
them there so clearly there must be some
reason as to why that individual was
instructed to put them there and to me
it seems pretty clear they're just there
to break up the monotony and to make
traversing a conscious activity and they
also are there to make vehicles far more
difficult to use this is because if
vehicles become too useful the
deliveries cease being an engaging
experience where you're engaging with
the world looking around and interacting
with it and slowly begin to be a matter
of tedium after all if all you need to
do to make a delivery is hop in a car
and drive from one location to the other
why do you need to build and upgrade the
roads why do you need to build zip lines
there would be no reason to which is why
you have to drop boulders on the ground
to make cars and motorcycles just
annoying enough to
that it would be more useful to spend
the time upgrading roads and zip lines
now for those of you who followed this
channel for a while or have seen to my
older videos you will know that I do a
series where I break down the density of
a game world basically I will take a
selection of gameplay that's two or
three hours long and I will chart out
how much time is in between moments of
interest how I define moments of
interest is something that changes my
thought process so if I'm exploring the
world and I see an animal run across the
screen in Red Dead Redemption to
something that catches my attention and
changes my thought process that
qualifies but some things such as just
avoiding a tree while riding a horse
wouldn't qualify because that's
something I can do passively now granted
this is an incredibly subjective way of
measuring these types of things which is
why it's something that I do myself I
don't use data from other people or
other people's gameplay this is only
from me so it would seem in my
estimation that that alone would serve
as a fairly good control now all of this
started back with The Witcher 3 the
designer said that they were aiming for
anywhere between 30 and 40 seconds
between moments of interest if they hit
that number then they would know that
the world was dense enough to hold
players attention while feeling
expansive and in my testing The Witcher
3 does in fact adhere to that rule and
I've tested a lot of games in this way
zelda breath of the wild Skyrim Fallout
New Vegas all of them I even calculated
this for Red Dead Redemption 2 which had
the longest time between moments of
interaction but the quality of those
interactions were much higher for this
reason I decided to make these same
calculations for Death Stranding because
it seems to me that this world doesn't
feel anywhere near as alive or
interesting as the world of Red Dead
Redemption to Zelda breath of the wild
or even Fallout New Vegas so I broke the
map into three broad areas where a lot
of orders are going to be taking place
snowy areas greenery laced late game
areas and stream heavy areas where
vehicles are usually going to be you
but their batteries may drain quickly
for these are used roughly two hours of
gameplay footage timed out the moments
in between moments of interest and then
I paused the timer whenever I was
interacting or dealing with something
that engaged my interest so for instance
if I encountered a mule that started
attacking me I would pause the timer
while I dealt with that threat and once
I began exploring again with a clear
mind I started the timer and this is the
data I collected now do you notice
anything it looks completely randomized
there are a couple of exceptions here
and there such as when I was navigating
a very dense area and it required a lot
more of my attention but broadly this is
incredibly random in fact looking at the
standard deviations and the kurtosis of
the charts it seems to me it is
randomized this is something I haven't
seen in any of the after mentioned
open-world games all of those had very
intentionally placed items and dynamic
interactions they were placed and
designed in such a way that they would
intrigue the player and they would be
paced out in such a way that the player
would always have something tickling
their fancy however the world of death
stranding is completely randomized
everything here looks as though it was
dynamically placed with almost no effort
put on it from the developers there's no
careful crafting of routes there's no
trail building to give players a clear
way of going there's nothing like that
in this world it literally looks as
though it was just randomly generated
and left alone again I can't express how
insane this is for a $60 title in 2019
in my opinion it's straight-up
unacceptable now I can't help but also
feel as though the world of death
stranding is made in a much more
realistic way in other words it is
random it isn't carefully crafted by
developers to enhance the experience of
the player but the point is we're
playing video games here this is in the
real world
and if you're going to try to improve
the experience for the player you are
going to need to enact some positive
actions but even with this data staring
them in the face I guarantee you there
will be people who will defend this they
will say that this more realistic way of
designing the world was intentional and
it's good because the world itself is
more realistic and exploring it and
navigating it is more realistic which is
the point of Death Stranding blah Dee
Bloo de blah blah again Kojima syndrome
this is straight-up unacceptable in a
triple a game in 2019 when this released
it's not good this is laziness
personified and frankly this explains
why the world does feel so empty the
design wasn't carefully crafted or
arranged sure mules and BT zones are
permanently placed and those don't
change but rocks ledges routes and
everything else in the world that you
explore seems straight-up
randomly placed I also did some further
calculations on the placement of the
items that you can find throughout the
world such as other zip lines the
players have crafted generators and the
light and believe it or not these are
also pretty much random there are a
couple of constraints that seem to be
put in place such as a limitation on how
many of a single item can be in a given
area so for instance you can only have
one online generator within a certain
radius of another generator but in
general this is all randomly spawned in
with the limitation of chiral volume and
those distance limitations that I just
mentioned this is laziness and I don't
know how anybody could defend it again
the question is is this just a team that
was too small or was incapable
technologically of dealing with this
couldn't craft it more carefully or
maybe they just decided it wasn't worth
crafting it more carefully who can say
whatever the excuse in practice the
design of the world is random and it's
lazy
now speaking of chiral bandwidth I have
to ask why why is this a thing
chiral bandwidth is the system
by which the game determines how many of
a certain item or a collection of items
you can craft want to build a zipline
network that's massive and expansive and
spans the whole map too bad because you
have Kairo bandwidth to adhere to this
is basically their version of a carry
weight limit for items you need to craft
even though there also is a physical
carry weight limit but you get what I'm
saying it's stupid it's just a way of
controlling density and increasing
tedium if you want to build a bunch of
zip lines you have to go delete other
zip lines in order to build new ones the
question is whether this was a technical
limitation something where they couldn't
handle more of a certain item in the
world or if it was a design choice again
Kojima syndrome there were many times
when I was building a massive zipline
Network and I was limited because of
this bandwidth now sure as you upgrade
certain areas and new 5-star new
locations you will increase the
bandwidth that you're playing with but
it's never unlimited and you never have
the ability to build to your heart's
content there is always this arbitrary
limitation and it is very frustrating
now it seems to me that this was
probably put in place to make you
reliant on other players in other words
if you can't build an unlimited number
of zip lines then you're going to have
to rely on online generated zip lines as
well and other things in the game do
this as well they make you reliant on
other players and their work examples
being exoskeletons having batteries
motorcycles and trucks all needing
batteries as well in order to charge
these up you need generators and
dynamically in the world there are many
online generators placed in highly
trafficked areas this is something that
makes you feel as though you need other
people in order to continue exploring
even though you could have just charged
it up yourself with a generator you
built it makes you feel as though you're
all working together which is a cool
mechanic to have and it does work in
making you feel as though you're all
working together but there is a side
effect to this mechanism and that's
specifically that these batteries just
feel tedious especially when you
consider how small the charge on these
batteries actually are even in the long
version of the vehicles building
generators for these just feels like
busywork it's not actually fun let me
share with you the exact moment I was
completely fed up with batteries and
that system within this game I was
driving this truck with a huge amount of
cargo loaded in the back I dropped by
one location I loaded it up fully
charged it and then head out onto the
plains and this is a futuristic truck
with a fully charged battery but this
thing has an operating distance that is
so low it would make a first-generation
Tesla blush seriously this is where I
started and as I drive and drive and
drive and drive not even going very far
this is where the battery dies in the
middle of the stream the car immediately
starts freaking out it pushes me out and
then instantly the car disappears and
all of my cargo floats downstream and
this was so much cargo I couldn't
possibly load it up onto my back and it
all drifted out into the water and was
ruined this was well over a thousand
likes instantly lost and several
deliveries instantly failed due to a
stupid mechanism just designed to make
you engage in this tedious gameplay
cycle of building generators to charge
batteries to get to another generator to
charge your battery so you can move on
in no way is this realistic and that's
the other question if this world is
designed to be realistic and that's your
excuse as to why the world design is so
crappy
then why are batteries and things like
this so clearly gamified in order to
make you engage in the gameplay system
it's not consistent if you're going to
make the gameplay systems realistic and
lifelike do it don't do this half-assed
thing otherwise it just ends up being
frustrating and forcing the player to
wonder whether or not you had any idea
what you were doing now another feature
of the world are the memory chips there
are 56 of these and they're hidden in
very random places with almost no visual
cues now the first time you hear about
these is when you receive an email in
chapter
three from a character named Nick Easton
in it he describes a quote-unquote weird
glowing thing that he wants you to find
in capital not city's isolation ward and
these emails are actually the only thing
that pushed you towards finding these
chips it's not really a concern in the
main story now I ran around for hours
and hours collecting these even the one
in Higgs secret room that doesn't unlock
until after fragile deals with him on
the beach and the question is whether or
not these are busy work just designed to
pad out a platinum run or if these are
placed in the world as a reason for you
to explore it and to hike through trying
to find every single one of them now to
me it seems pretty clearly that it's the
former not the latter and to prove this
I'm going to show you some examples
these are some of the more commonly
collected ones so if you've yet to find
all of them don't worry you can still
hunt them down and have a good time for
what it's worth when you go to the
weather station there's one placed on a
concrete ledge okay you run past this
frequently enough I think I'm fine with
this one this one however is along the
red wall it's not an area you would ever
be running by there's no reason for you
to explore this area and even once you
get there it hides very very well it's
hidden in the truck bed of this area you
have no reason to go to this one I'm les
okay with and it doesn't seem as though
it's hidden in a way that encourages you
to explore the map it's hidden in a way
that encourages this busywork type of
gameplay this is another one that I'm
actually okay with it's hidden in an
underpass by Mama's base this is
something that I did stumble on too
while exploring I didn't have to read
any email cueing me to this area so
obviously I'm okay with this one this is
one I'm not okay with it's on the hood
of a semi Shore it's outside of an area
you're going to be trafficking fairly
frequently but you can't normally climb
onto vehicles you have no reason to ever
climb onto a vehicle so the only reason
you would hop up on this is if you
scanned it happen to spot it and jumped
up to grab it there's no reason for the
player to be looking up here or looking
for memory chips in this area this is
something that you would just stumble
onto or would find if you were cued on
to it there's this one in the back
corner of the loading zone room
it's just sitting on the floor now fair
enough if you go back here you're going
to spot it so it's fairly easy to find
however the player has no reason to ever
go back into one of these areas
it's just placed here and you're
expected to figure that out for reasons
even though there's never anything else
placed in these back corners in any of
the other loading zones there's this one
in the snow field just sitting on top of
a collapsed pillar this is one that you
would probably find during normal
gameplay especially because this is a BT
heavy area and this is zone where you're
going to be crouching and stealth in
your way through so I'm actually ok with
this one this one makes sense this one's
in a cave and this cave is actually
marked with a ton of signs as a time
fall shelter so it's also likely that
you would probably encounter this one
through regular gameplay even though I
didn't but the one I like by far the
most is the one hidden in hIG's his
secret room this is in the top right
corner of the central zone of the map
it's basically Higgs is center of
operations it's a really cool hidden
area that I like a lot this is really
cool that they included this here even
if some of the quotes scribbled on the
wall are kind of funny and weird I'll
just say it again I really like this and
I really wish there were more things
like this hidden and scattered
throughout the map if the map were
littered with things such as this the
player would have a reason and an excuse
to explore for the sake of exploring
without any deliveries strapped to their
back just going through the world for
the sake of interacting with it but alas
as far as I'm aware this is the only
thing like it in the game now it's
pretty clear to me that these are
supposed to be hunted down with emails
that you receive in the game which is
obviously true because many of these
chips won't actually spawn until you've
received a given email describing them
so clearly they want you to be
interacting with the emails and using
the emails to find them for example the
memory chip the walk doesn't actually
unlock until you've leveled up the first
prepper one of the most isolated
individuals in the entire game and
because you're supposed to rely on these
emails I think it's fair to say that
these are here to encourage you to read
through the emails not here to encourage
you to explore the world
last thing that I can think of that
would encourage you to explore the world
for the sake of exploring it would be
the hot springs these are something that
are briefly mentioned and they're kind
of cool basically there's six by my
count in the middle zone alone and they
allow you to hop in and there's
regenerative qualities to them and
though it is cute because you hop in and
you chill with your bb I never really
felt the need to use these or hunt them
down intentionally when I encountered
one I would hop in
but that was really the only time I ever
use them again I'm glad they're here but
this is by no means a reason to explore
the map it's just six things that sit on
the map that are kind of fun when you
find them but you'll forget about them
within 50 feet the point of all of this
is to say that the world design of death
stranding is so incomprehensibly bad I
don't really know how to explain it
other than pure laziness hell my degree
is in corporate finance I'm not a
specialist in game design but all of
this is pretty basic to me and the fact
that Kojima Productions can't manage to
follow any of the basic practices of
triple-a open-world game development
it's completely baffling to me if you
have an explanation for it I would love
to hear it down in the comment section
below
regardless one of the other common
accusations that's levied against deaths
training is the idea that the gameplay
is purely repetitive and there's no
reason to engage with it because of its
repetitious nature and on the macro
level I think that is fair enough which
is why I ran through the basic outline
of a quest earlier in this section
however on the micro level is where I
would slightly disagree because while
you are going to be repeating the same
basic macro process of delivering items
from one location to the other you are
going to be using a plethora of
different tools in order to achieve this
end whether you're walking using
motorcycles or trucks ladders climbing
anchors bridges or zip lines pretty much
across the board you're going to be
using a plethora of different tools all
told it is repetitive in the purest
sense of the word but what game isn't in
Red Dead Redemption you're going to be
engaging in gun firefights and riding
your horse that's pretty much it in The
Witcher 3 you're going to be talking
with people
and sword-fighting sure occasionally
you're also going to be crafting things
but that's also true of Death Stranding
and even with Red Dead Redemption too
every game has a set of gameplay
mechanics that they're going to repeat
rinse repeat rinse repeat over and over
and over again after all it's kind of
the definition of a video game to me the
problem isn't with the fact that the
gameplay system is repetitious the
problem is that the orders while being
repetitious require you to go over areas
that you've traversed time and time and
time again it ceases to be interesting
after the first few times especially
once you've built items that help you
get over this such as ladders climbing
anchors bridges or zip lines they
completely negate the need to engage
with the other elements of the gameplay
loop and end up just turning this whole
process into a tedious one instead of
one of exploration and adventure
this is especially an issue because you
are encouraged to craft a ton of items
and to load up way more than you likely
need for a given mission I found myself
many many times trying to use all of my
ladders and climbing anchors that I
brought with me just because I had
crafted too many and I didn't want to
have a back fully-loaded of things that
I wasn't using so I would make sure that
I would drop all the ladders all the
climbing anchors and everything that I
had carried to make sure that they were
getting used if anything I ever built
was interfering with the kairel density
or was making it so that the Kairo
bandwidth was overloaded I would just
delete them and many times the game
actually does this for you which is why
the time fall is kind of a cool gameplay
mechanic because it's a reason in game
four items to deteriorate and get
deleted effectively after a certain
amount of time which forces you to go
back over those areas rebuild the things
that you had previously put there but I
don't think time fall degrades these
items fast enough for you to feel as
though you need to constantly be up
keeping on all of the things that you've
put into the world furthermore I was
almost never limited by resources when I
was crafting these things after all
resources tend to be stored in the
locations at which you're crafting items
so there's rarely ever a time where you
find yourself short only when building
Road
and bridges did I notice a need for
extra materials but after a few quick
trips to a mule camp and back to the
home base to extract materials all of
this was fixed I experimented with some
higher difficulty options to see if this
would make item spawns or material
spawns much lower to make this much more
involved to make it so you couldn't
craft for ladders to anchors to boots to
gloves
five guns and three vehicles all at the
same time without ever feeling the
impact of it and I'm sorry to report the
difficulty really only affects the
combat and the damage that you receive
and deal out it doesn't actually change
much of anything as far as I can tell in
terms of item spawns or anything like
that furthermore you can also repair
items and packaging if a road is
degrading or if a bridge is breaking
down you can just repair it with some
extra items though I will be honest I
never felt the need to do this in all my
time with the game because the crafting
cost of a brand new one was so low but
now we get to the point where deaths
training starts to kind of undo itself
and unravel and this is my biggest
late-game problem with Death Stranding
in addition to the poor world design and
also the lack of any sort of emotional
tied to the world you're trying to save
you see the gameplay system is fairly
sparse to begin with which isn't
inherently bad after all anyone can boil
anything down to its simplest parts you
can say that disco Elysium is just a
walking simulator or that Grand Theft
Auto 5 is just a crime simulator in my
eyes you can turn anything into a game
as long as that thing is fun and
fulfilling hell you can even make a
farming game fun and relaxing so my
problem isn't with simplistic gameplay
systems it's with systems that undermine
themselves on a fundamental level and I
know that this is a big accusation to
levy against Death Stranding and I don't
make it lightly so allow me to argue my
point the zipline and the leveling
system you see the zipline in my opinion
is far too useful it makes all other
traversal techniques and mechanics
completely obsolete you see once you set
up a few zipline routes you have no need
to ever craft ladders to ever craft
climbing anchors all-terrain
exoskeletons it's all useless because
once you craft a couple of zip lines at
the highest peak and build your network
out from there you no longer have the
need to interact with the lazily
designed world all you do is dangle by
your cuff link as you fly through the
sky it bypasses all bt interactions all
mule interactions effectively negating
the entire gameplay system that they
just set up and I think Kojima
Productions was actually aware of this
and became aware of it at least later in
development which is why they added the
chiral bandwidth system in in the first
place because they realized if they
allowed players to just build zip lines
everywhere it would completely negate
the need for crafting roads building
ladders bridges everything now the
obvious defense of these zip lines as
they are is that they're going to force
players to appreciate the work of other
players that you're going to use online
zip lines in addition to the zip lines
your crafting paired with the chiral
bandwidth system this makes sure that
you're dependent on other people but I
would argue that this isn't the case
because roads which are introduced very
early in the game require so many
materials to construct they do this job
zip lines are simply too cheap and easy
to construct in order to make you feel
truly dependent on other players in fact
because the placement of these online
zip lines seems so randomized as I
discussed earlier I found myself
deleting online zip lines multiple times
because they were getting in the way of
my own zip line network if Kojima really
wanted zip lines to represent the
ultimate cooperation between players
they should have been far more expensive
to build instead of just a level 2 PCC
in my opinion the fix to this would be
to make roads far more important in the
late game and to have zip lines
completely cut or made far more
expensive on the same level of expense
as roads these things are so cool fast
and they bypass so much of the gameplay
system just like the roads do that they
shouldn't be so careless
added this is coming from somebody who
has a huge network of zip line set up in
his safe file of the game I love the zip
lines and I think they're far too useful
now I don't know when they added zip
lines to the game but it seems to me
they were probably added later in
development when they realized that the
late-game map was going to be too
vertical for roads this is likely one of
the reasons why roads are discussed
constantly in the first 10 to 15 hours
of the game and then it seems like
everybody forgets about them and they
start talking about zip lines my guess
is that this was because they realized
roads and mountains don't mix very well
whereas zip lines could be the ultimate
fix all for navigating over mountaintops
but to me this is no excuse all they had
to do was make zip lines more expensive
in terms of materials and to make it so
perhaps they require three players
chiral IDs or something to construct
point is there are ways they could have
done this to make sure that zip lines
weren't too useful so that players would
continue engaging with the core gameplay
loop that they had spent 30 to 35 hours
engaging with previous now I get it
you're giving players more options more
tools to use in order to engage with the
game I get that but if players are given
the chance to spam the gameplay loop
they will for better and worse and in
this case I think it's for worse and
again it really seems that Kojima
Productions were all aware of these
systems becoming too useful they were
scared that roads were too useful which
is why they made them incredibly
expensive to construct they were scared
that vehicles were going to be too
useful which is why they scattered
almost every square inch of the map with
rocks and boulders and rivers to make
sure that they were just tedious enough
to use that you wouldn't get reliant on
them this is also why batteries are
attached to every useful item in the
game whether their speed exoskeletons
power exoskeletons or the all-terrain
ones all because they want you reliant
on other players and to make sure that
you aren't bypassing all of the other
gameplay systems after all they could
have made a truck or a snowmobile that
made the mountain sections far easier
but they didn't because those were
supposed to be the difficult section
which is why it's so strange to me that
the zip lines completely negate all of
the mountain sections and make them
ridiculously easy now in addition to
these zip lines the leveling system I
think also undermines the gameplay
progression though I will be honest in a
much lesser degree you see every time
you level up you can carry more you keep
your balance better it increases your
stamina your health everything this is
pretty common but it often means that
the Kame becomes easier to play the
later you get into it this is actually
one of the major criticisms I made of
Assassin's Creed Odyssey that I made in
my ultimate critique of that game which
by the way is just under three hours if
you're enjoying this video I recommend
that you check that one out after this
as well the point is that as the player
becomes more powerful they become less
reliant on the gear and the items that
you have been given again undermining
those very items now I want to shift
gears a little bit and talk about the
broader implication of Death Stranding
as kojima described it he said the death
stranding was going to become and was
going to introduce a new type or genre
of game in my opinion he didn't do this
effectively the idea was that the world
was going to be shared at least in terms
of the items that players will put in
the world to share now don't get me
wrong the chiral network and shared
items are cool but it doesn't actually
feel like a revolution at least I think
in the way that Kojima intended sure
it's helpful to have a zip line already
built in an area but the developers
limited the number of items that can be
placed in a particular zone so that it
never feels particularly crowded and in
concept this is pretty simple and
straightforward it's a world that's
shared but you can't actually see or
find other players you only see traces
of them which makes you dependent on
them and the game actually tries to turn
this into some sort of profound
statement but I think it's just an
attempt at explaining why other players
are absent I don't know you let me know
in the comments
see the tracks you left behind they tell
a story if you were spy on a mission
you'd have failed
but you're not so be proud of those
tracks
there's proof that you exist let people
know you're out there give them the
courage to come together again as you
expand the network an angel fellow
Americans you strengthen the bonds
between us all and blazed the trail for
them to follow and honestly having this
in mind why not have other players
visible and present you could give them
other skins so that they don't look like
Sam to avoid griefing and even have
their movements recorded and then played
back in your world at a later time to
prevent griefing nauseam this would be
similar to what racing games do when you
race against your friends even when
they're offline you just play against a
ghost of theirs this could make it so as
you explore the world you're actually
seeing other Porter's delivering stuff
and yeah sure now there are NPCs that
you occasionally will see walking with
weapons and things but these are non
player controlled characters these are
computer controlled they are not other
players and while yes you can
occasionally see a ghost of a player or
signs that other players have left this
is not anywhere near on the level of
having truly interactable players at
least in my opinion the point is they
could have fully realized multiplayer
systems in Death Stranding and it
wouldn't have disrupted the story or the
gameplay so why didn't they well it
could have been technical it could have
been monetarily determined it could have
been that they didn't want to advertise
it as an online game it could have been
that they were avoiding the PlayStation
Plus requirement for online play and
that would have gone over the line or it
could have been simply that Kojima
wanted the world to be empty obviously
he stripped it of other life like the
birds and the deer that we see in the
opening so maybe he meant all this to be
empty and lifeless again Kojima syndrome
I think could have really added to the
game even just to have AI controlled
NPCs wandering the wastes and delivering
packages constantly you pass them on
trails you can speak with them you can
trade with them they might have a ladder
and you have a climbing anchor you need
the ladder more so you trade for it it
could have made the world feel
more alive again worth saving and this
is my primary point of the section if
this new genre of game is supposed to
bring people together it's ironic that
it's done the exact opposite but all of
this thoroughly convinces me that this
game was on a strict budget and even was
rushed out the door allow me to argue my
point to me it seems pretty clear
animals were cut from the game they went
through the trouble of modeling and
animating them for the opening sequence
they must have been in the game at some
point and they were completely cut later
in development when it became clear that
they were going to be too tedious to
place carefully in the world or perhaps
they were making the world feel too
alive and it didn't feel like an
apocalypse either way it looks as though
they were cut and PC interactions after
orders are almost all holographic and
look objectively terrible these are all
copy and pasted with different skins
effectively and new voice actors but
they're all the same bridges and fragile
housings buildings and environments are
all copy and pasted across the entire
game very few vehicles especially
considering the variability of locations
snowy areas rocky areas River covered
areas they're all highly variable and
the vehicles that are there to offer
transportation across these are nowhere
near as variable there are areas on the
outskirts of the map in the central area
which are all glitchy and frankly
terrible it shows that they put a lot of
effort in polishing the central areas in
the heavily trafficked areas which is
fair enough but it shows that there's a
real lack of polish all over this game
you just have to know where to look and
all of this is too bad because it does
really make you wonder what deaths
training would have looked like if
Kojima were given another year or so to
work on it and a lot more money but that
brings us to the question of Kojima's
strengths and weaknesses which no doubt
there are plenty I figured what better
way to end this critique of deaths
training than to discuss the man himself
you see Kojima does whatever he wants
whenever he wants to that's kind of the
whole point of him leaving Konami
is that now he is completely free
however after playing through death
stranding I can't help but feel as
though he desperately needs a dramaturg
or a co-director to keep him in check I
feel as though through the course of
this video I've outlined a lot of
reasons why Kojima needs to be
restrained and needs to have somebody to
deal with him in a much more mature way
because I honestly don't think he knows
when to stop or when he's being
ridiculous I could point to things such
as the fourth wall breaks all of the
product placement for AMC and monster
energy drinks there's a lot of really
bad plot twists and a lot of the writing
in here is so wordy it's hard to even
follow what Kojima is trying to
communicate now I took a playwriting
class a couple of years ago and it was
really interesting but one of the things
that the teacher said on the first day
of class was that new writers tend to
write a lot
whereas experienced writers tend to
write well and I couldn't help but feel
as though Kojima is a new writer he
seems to just throw all of the spaghetti
at the wall just hoping something sticks
so instead of writing a monologue that's
three sentences long he'll write one
that's 15 minutes long and hope that you
get something more significant from that
I think it shows a certain amount of
insecurity in his writing that he feels
as though he can't communicate in as
short a time as a lot of other writers
could such as Neil druckmann who wrote
The Last of Us uncharted 4 and is
currently writing and directing the Last
of Us part two now listen I loved PT and
that was all Kojima but it was a humble
and confident Kojima it wasn't Kojima
with something to prove having left to
Konami and to be honest I like humble
Kojima more than this new one now in
that survey I mentioned at the top of
this video where over 2400 of you
responded I asked you guys what you
thought of Hideo Kojima and many of you
had some pretty varied opinions of him
here's a selection of some of the ones I
thought were interesting and funny he's
an artistic genius who can't tell a
coherent story
I think he's innovative and incredibly
talented but he fails to see criticism
for what it is and his fans think he can
do no wrong
he needed others to rein in his vision
to make it more appealing he knows
exactly what he wants to make and he
doesn't waver he's an innovator but not
a hands-down genius he presents the most
unique ideas for world building and
characters despite falling on rather
generic writing tropes he's an excellent
designer with ideas he doesn't know how
to clearly express the very definition
of an auteur he's a great visionary and
original storyteller but a weak writer
and then 57 of you guys said he's kind
of insane now all of this seems to
coalesce into a consensus that he is a
talented artist with a lot of really
interesting original ideas but that he
doesn't know when to stop and to
delegate for instance he has an original
story idea but he insists on writing out
the macro and the micro story elements
himself despite being objectively bad at
writing dialogue and it's really too bad
because if death straining were more
lean it could have appealed to a lot
more people and it could have made a
much bigger splash so in closing death
stranding is an enigma it's a game that
I'm glad that I played the one that's
plagued with issues through and through
and while I'm glad that Kojima got to
pursue his passion project
I do hope that his next attempt is far
more coherent more polished and much
more fun but that's all from me thank
you so much for watching if you've made
it all the way to this point you are a
scholar and the Saint special thank you
again to the patrons that funded the
production of this video again it would
not have happened without the generosity
of these individuals and a very special
thank you to Zachary Johnson Mike
Holland
Christopher Scott and Paige Richardson
for their generosity let me know all of
your thoughts on Death Stranding below
and if you'd like to vote on and help
fund the next critique make sure you go
and check out my patreon page in
addition to getting all sorts of
behind-the-scenes peeks at the
development of these critiques helping
pick the thumbnails and much much more
you also get access to exclusive monthly
q A's free merchandise
early access to these critiques before
anybody else and exclusive videos just
for patrons but thank you all for
watching I love you all more than you
could possibly know and I'll see you in
the next video
[Music]