Now let's look at it from a top view
Tianhe core module
At the very front of it is the multi-docking hub
The multi-docking hub has two docking ports and two parking ports
and the most important is that the multi-docking hub
provides access for taikonauts entering and exiting the core module
Approaching slowly
the top of the multi-docking hub with the yellow handle
is the exit hatch for taikonauts
Next to him is a yellow device
and this is the extra tool kit
The tools for taikonauts' EVA
will be placed here in the tool kit
I can feel breeze at the place I stand
Mr. Sun who bring me up here
is from Shenzhou-1 to -11 … ?
from Shenzhou - 5
you're the person that the taikonauts
last saw on the ground? That's you right?
Yes
- So you closed those hatches?  - closing hatch
What did you say to them when you close the hatches?
And I said, "Well, our spaceship is very high reliable
It'll be like a tour, safely depart, happily return~
How about this view?
Exclusive on hole internet?
It's never been shot on this view
No excuse, this is exclusive!
During our taikonauts' first EVA operation
the first mission is to bring these two tools out
one of them is a portable feet fixing device
the other is this, external operating platform
The feet fixing device is to fix the spacesuit out in space
it's able to be mounted on the feet fixing device base on bulkhead
or the base on the mechanic arm
The taikonauts can fit their feet into these rings
and move outward to fit their ankle into these slots
to fix their feet
the ordinary shoe won't work right?
no, because this is designed for EVA suits' boot
On both sides there are "yaw" and "row"
yes, these are two control paddles of the device
pressing the left "yaw", you can rotate 360 at this direction
pressing the right "row", you can rotate 90 to both sides
to adjust to an appropriate position for operating
Is this portable feet fixing device mounted on the end of mechanic arm?
Yes, there's a same one on the end of mechanic arm
which is the base for portable feet fixing device
- That's the one we just saw…   - That's right
Oh it's very light
Yeah, the tool box's main structure is aluminium
it's mounted near the exiting hatch of multi-docking hub
they all use general standard port
you can see this tri-color sign on every base
it's for the convenience of taikonauts
aligning the angle when mounting them
When they finish the mission they will left it out on bulkhead?
That's right, just stored in external toolkit instead of bringing back in
And in the next mission
they can just take tools from here and go on using them
This is external operating platform
It's mounted to the port on the side of portable feet fixing device
It's mainly used for placing maintaining device or tools when EVA
There're 6 ports
2 loading pole on both sides
4 general ports on center panel
all can place or hang device
it's kinda shelf, storing things temporary
What's this port for?
This port is to mount an auxiliary pole for portable feet fixing device
It's here
It seems to be seen from the animation
Its both sides can be lockup
Up here, it can be pulled out
The handrail can fit the height of taikonauts
You see, the external operating platform can be rotated
It can rotate in front of taikonaut
oh, it can rotate
yes
180 degrees?
Exactly, both sides 90 degrees
Can I stand up here?
eh … you can have a try, I'll help you
Be careful
It's high
Yeah, and this is the handrail for taikonauts
It can fit to the height of them
This height … how about this?
It's a little bit scary on ground operating it right?
- Maybe better in space?   - Yeah
No no no, don't step on it
You'll flip over!
You can try this one
yeah, be careful
It's like step on a flying skateboard
This design is really humanization?
- Yeah  - It take every situation that taikonauts will face into consideration
Easy
There're a lot of instruction in Chinese, like "开""关" (open, close)
Yes
portable feet fixing device
It's product code "a"
It mean portable feet fixing device code "a"
On the bulkhead of core module there're lots of yellow
handrail for taikonauts' EVA operation
Despite its quantity and broadly range
there are still some unreachable places through handrail
since the module is very large
So what if taikonauts need to operate at these places?
Then they need this mighty tool
External transporting handrail
The yellow ones are all fixed
and this one is portable
When EVA, if taikonauts think some place is unreachable through handrail
but they need to operate here
and need a stabilized attitude
then they can use this tool
But where is it mounted?
It's also mounted to the handrail
It's also mounted to the yellow handrail?
Yeah, to the handrail
Is it retractable?
It has some functions, first it's retractable
then its angle can also be adjusted
You can see here, now it's locked
Open it up, then you can move this
and you press again, lock it up here
which means it can rotate to some specific angle
and then pull it out
This is it
That's really subtle, how did you make that?
That's according to taikonauts' EVA mission demand
You guys really made lots of efforts for taikonauts EVA mission
Great tools, all mechanical?
Yeah, except for electric tools, they are electronics
everything else are mechanical
Mechanical ones are highly reliable?
Highly reliable
But the design is …
It's difficult
Not only to implement functions
you also have to make it easy for taikonauts using out in space
When taikonauts wearing EVA suit
their action, moving angle, the power they can release
all different from that we do on the ground
So taikonauts must make sure this thing in accessible,
visible range is all operatable
Then we can get into next step of design
So every subtle mechanics and function we see here
they're not for good-looking
but all proved
firstly they should be functional
This is micro-work bench
It's fixed to the waist of taikonauts through this port
Then taikonauts can carry 3 maintaining tools with it when EVA
This is external general handrail
This is external wrench
It can also be detachable?
No need to screw, just pull it out
It's used to screw
Is there any difference that screwing a screw in space and on ground?
The gloves that taikonauts wearing
for one they are big
for the other it's hard to move after inflated
the operating wouldn't be as flexible as on ground
This rope is to prevent it float away
It's a generat port
There are lots of these kind of port
- Let's take a look   - That's right
It's like a bolt
Yeah
Lots of tools have this general port
That's convenient, you don't need to find everywhere
That's right
That's the third one?
The 3rd one is an electronic tool
- This …   - It's more than 10 pounds, isn't it?
5-ish (kilo)
This is the only electronic tool in space
It has a special charger, with battery inside
It has a function that starts slowly
It's not like …
No, it's not like tools on ground, we don't need that fast in space
Why is it so heavy?
Because the products in space have to overcome some situations
Every components are specially made, all aerospace level
So it has relatively larger size than the tools we use on ground
but we won't feel its weight in space
Oh there's also a general port here
Yeah, that's the same port
Just insert like this
It's a tool box
The regular three tools
Are there many chances to use it? This electronic one
Of course
It's an important tool for evert EVA mission
Will it be used for this EVA?
Yeah
It's so heavy
How about you take this?
I'll take this!
(Are you sure?)
That side is heavier
Taikonauts would be really tired if it's not zero-G
The space suit is heavy
plus these devices
They need to carry these at every EVA mission?
Yes
It's so heavy
I'll take it
I'll just put it down
Despite its tens-of-pound-weight
it would be easy to move in zere-G environment?
Yeah